(
"ai_sub_version": "3.5.2",
"generated_at": "2026-09-10T22:48:30.977574",
"lyrics_prompt_version": 9,
"subtitles_prompt_version": 18,
"complete": true,
"max_retries_exceeded": false,
"any_pending": false,
"settings": (
"ai": (
"model": null,
"model_subtitles": "google-gla:gemini-3.5-flash",
"model_lyrics": "google-gla:gemini-3.5-flash-lite",
"rpm": 4,
"tpm": 250000,
"google": (
"file_cache_ttl": 10,
"use_files_api": true,
"max_storage_gb": 18.0
),
"search": (
"qps": 0.3,
"max_length": 4096,
"web_search_tool": "langsearch",
"timeout": 60.0,
"retries": 3,
"min_wait_seconds": 1.0,
"max_wait_seconds": 10.0,
"multiplier": 2.0
),
"validation_buffer_ms": 2000,
"verification_gap_seconds": 60,
"gap_verification_retries": 1,
"gap_verification_ignore_start": true,
"gap_verification_ignore_end": true
),
"split": (
"max_seconds": 300,
"re_encode": (
"enabled": false,
"fps": 1.0,
"height": 360,
"bitrate_kb": 35,
"threshold_mb": 20,
"duration_tolerance_ms": 100,
"encoder": null
),
"start_offset_min": 0
"thread": (
"uploads": 4,
"re_encode": 2,
"lyrics": 4,
"subtitles": 4
),
"retry": (
"per_run": 5,
"max_runs": 3,
"multiplier": 2.0,
"min_wait_seconds": 30.0,
"max_wait_seconds": 300
),
"log": (
"level": "info",
"timestamps": true,
"scrub": false,
"progress_bars": true,
"progress_bar_width": 80,
"progress_bar_refresh_seconds": 1.0
)
おしゃべり、おしゃべり...
Let's talk, let's talk...
最終日やっていこう！
Let's do the final day!
なんか、謎のアイテムをデイリーから貰い
I got some mysterious item from the dailies.
あれ、私のさ...
Wait, my...
私のインベントリ、なんかね、肉とか入ってたはずなんだけど、空っぽになってんだけど
My inventory, I'm sure there was meat in it, but it's completely empty.
腐ってなくなったんじゃないかな、もしかすると
Maybe it rotted away?
腐ってなくなったんか？
It rotted away?
そうそうそう
Yeah, yeah.
なるほどな。よし、腐って消えた。
I see. Well, it rotted and disappeared.
そんな日もある、そんな日もある
There are days like that. There are days like that.
待って、さくら、一緒に行くわ！
Wait! Sakura, I'll go with you!
朝礼はさっきした通りなんですが、えー、こう、分かれて
The morning assembly went as planned, so let's split up.
パイレーツチーム、えー、フブ、ボタン、イナ先輩でお願いします
For the Pirate Team, Fubuki, Botan, and Ina-senpai, please.
はーい
Okay!
なんかカクカク... 集会場戻りますよ
It's a bit laggy... I'm heading back to the assembly area.
なんか、サーバー終わったか？え？
Did the server crash? Huh?
なんか... ただいま。帰ってきた
Something... I'm back. I returned.
空中歩行してる！すごい！空中歩行してる！
They're floating in the air! Amazing! They're flying!
うわ、リアルか
Whoa, is that for real?
あれ、何これ？どうなってんの、これ？
Huh, what's this? What's going on here?
あれ、私のやつ...
Wait, mine...
あ、でも大丈夫そうなの？あ、大丈夫、動いた、動いた
Ah, but does it look okay? Ah, it's fine, it moved.
人による感じです
It seems to depend on the person.
人による感じ？え、待って、拠点がいっさい見えない。怖い
Depends on the person? Wait, I can't see the base at all. Scary.
大丈夫ですか？多分ワープでなんかバグってるっぽいな、これ、画面が
Are you okay? It seems warping bugged out my screen.
はい、で、残りのメンバーは、えーっと
Okay, and the remaining members are...
こよ、ビビ、トワ先輩で
Koyo, Bibi, and Towa-senpai.
マル秘ミッションに必要なマンモスをテイムしにいって、そのままやりに行きます
We will go tame the mammoth needed for the secret mission, and do it directly.
で、今日は、我々こっち側はツェッペリン移動です。よろしくお願いします
And today, our side will be moving by Zeppelin. Please look after us.
おっけー
Okay.
では、VC、えーっと、マンモス隊の人、下に行ってもらって。さぁ、よろしくお願いします
Now, voice chat... Mammoth Team members, please go down. Alright, let's do this!
はーい。お願いいたすよー。頑張りましょう！
Okay! Good luck! Let's do our best!
ほな、またにゃんこや。にゃんこ行って、トード行って、終わったらツェッペリン合流
Well, it's Nyanko again. Go to Nyanko, then Toad, then merge with the Zeppelin.
そうだね
Right.
じゃ、私、ちょっと再ログするから、先に行っちゃってもオッケー
I'm going to re-log, so you guys can go ahead.
ただ、肉、肉が欲しいな、肉が。食べるやつ？
But I need some meat. For eating?
あと、鉄の装備が欲しくて。鉄の装備、鉄あれば作れるはず。ここに金属あります
Also, I want iron gear. You should be able to make it if there's metal. There's metal here.
作っちゃって全然オッケーやにん。金属の、あ、そっか、これ振らないとダメか
It's totally fine to make it. Metal... ah, right, I have to swing at this.
あの金属の... あ、なんでだ？なんか。てか私達金属、じゃないわ、毛皮装備もらえないのか？
That metal... huh, why? Also, do we not get fur armor? Trumped by...
なんか、随時っぽいんだよね。随時か
It seems to be as-needed. As-needed? Trumped by...
一旦は、毛皮はトード行くときだけだから大丈夫かな。おっけー
For now, we only need fur when going to Toad, so we should be fine. Okay.
あ、でもさ、パイロ乗ってたらさ、あれなんじゃないっけ？まあ、正直あってもなくてもいい
But if we're on a Pyromane, doesn't it...? Well, honestly, either way is fine.
えーっと、ちょっとこいつ入れて、こいつ。ホバテリは置いといて
Let's see, let me put this in, and this. I'll leave the hover teleporter.
サドルの鎧、皮がいるのか。皮
Saddle armor... needs hide. Hide.
ほい。よいしょ、オッケー。この、お手手マーク何これ？
Hop. Alright, okay. What's this hand mark?
お片付けなんとか
Cleaning up... something.
いーとー。ふー。さぁ、いつでも行けますよ
Let's see. Phew. Alright, I can go anytime.
作っている。そう、今ちょっと装備を
I'm making it. Yeah, I'm just...
作りたい
trying to make some gear.
装備作ったほうがいいですかね？まあ、やっぱ俺達いつまでも布でいるわけにはいかないからな。確かに
Should we make gear? Well, we can't wear cloth forever. True.
ギリースーツでも多分大丈夫。あ、じゃあギリーで行こうかな
Ghillie suits are probably fine, too. Ah, then maybe I'll go with Ghillie.
いつまでも布だったから
Since we've been in cloth armor this whole time.
あ、ちょっちょっちょっと、これ。
Ah, wait, wait, wait, this...
で、焼き肉、これ焼き肉ってどこ？食べ物どこある、これ？
So, cooked meat... where is this cooked meat? Is there food anywhere?
食べ物は外で焼いてるお肉ぐらいかな？
For food, maybe just the meat cooking outside?
オッケー。
Okay.
お肉が意外と焼けてないから、本当は工業用グリルとかが欲しいが。
The meat isn't really cooking that fast, so I'd love an industrial grill...
あ、ここいっぱいありますよ。
Ah, there's plenty over here.
あ、ばっちり！
Ah, perfect!
肉欲しい、肉が。
I want meat, meat.
あ、10枚、なんか。お肉ある？大丈夫？
Ah, ten... there's some... Do you have meat? Are you okay?
よいしょ、ここか。
Heigh-ho, here?
あるならよきや。よいしょ。
If you have some, that's good. Heigh-ho.
あ、じゃあ持っていくわ。
Oh, then I'll take it.
あいよ。
Alright.
おし、いつでも行けるぜ。
Alright, I can go anytime.
あいよ、じゃあ、行ってしまおう。
Alright, then let's head out.
えー、これを、こっち入れちゃう。
Um, let's put this... in here.
はい。はい。はい。えーっと。
Yes. Yes. Um...
おし、ういー。
Alright, wheee!
はいはいはいはい。
Yes, yes, yes, yes.
火山よね？ / そうだね、火山だね。で、また、えーっと、なんだっけ、ユウティラで...
The volcano, right? / That's right, the volcano. And then we'll use the Yutyrannus...
はい。 / うん、体力削ってもらってからかな？
Yes. / Yeah, after having it whittle down our health?
よいしょ。
Heigh-ho.
ほな、一旦海辺に。
Well, let's head to the beach first.
これペットの名前っていうか、恐竜の名前どうやって変えるんだっけ？
How do you change the pet names—I mean, the dinosaur names?
恐竜の名前は一回下りて「E」長押しとかかな？
For dinosaur names, maybe dismount first and hold down "E"?
あれ、全然別方向行ってた、全然...
Ah, I was going in a completely different direction, completely...
以前のやつだから、ちょっと名前... / 海、海行きたかった？
Since it's an old one, the name is... / You wanted to go to the beach?
逆、逆、逆でした。 / めっちゃ逆、めっちゃ逆、雪山行ってた。
Opposite, opposite, it was the opposite direction! / Completely opposite! You were heading to the snow mountain.
こっちだ、こっちだ。ういー。
This way, this way. Wheee!
どっちする、どっち？
Which way, which?
ういー。
Wheee!
こっちよな？
This way, right?
ういー、ういー。
Wheee, wheee.
よいしょ。
Heigh-ho.
交代用になってる、向こう。
It's set up for substitution over there.
ういー。
Wheee.
よいしょ、あ、下見な、下見な。おっきー、ういー。
Heigh-ho, ah, check below, check below. Okay, wheee!
えーっと、体力。
Um, stamina...
これ、みんなの巣って見えなかったっけ？
Wait, couldn't we see everyone's nests?
なんか見えると思うんだけど、なんか反映されてないんだよね、うまく。
I think we're supposed to, but it's not showing up properly.
よいしょ。まあ、もう海辺に着くよ。
Heigh-ho. Well, we're almost at the beach.
よし！
Alright!
いつもの場所？
The usual spot?
そう、いつもの、このベッドを設置した場所に行く。ういー。
Yeah, going to the usual spot where we placed the beds. Wheee!
ういー。よいしょ。
Wheee. Heigh-ho.
なんかヘビがいるわ。
There's a snake there.
よいしょ、よいしょ。
Heigh-ho, heigh-ho.
いつものキャンプ地...あ、ちょうどでもいますよ、あの、あれが。
The usual campsite... oh, but it's right there, you know, that thing.
よいしょ。
Heigh-ho.
グロウ、て...
Grow... wait...
あ、グロウテールが。なぜ？
Ah, a Glowtail? Why?
え？あれ？
Eh? Huh?
あ、あれ？もしかして...
Ah, wait, could it be...
もしかして？ / もしかして餓死か？
Could it be...? / Could it be starvation?
よいしょ。
Heigh-ho.
餌をやらなかったばかりに... / 餌をやらずに放置していたばかりに...
Just because I didn't feed it... / Just because we left it without feeding it...
すまんな。 / すまんな。
Sorry about that. / Sorry about that.
とりあえずいつもの場所来ました。
Anyway, I've arrived at the usual spot.
あいよ。
Alright.
ほなら、イナのユウティラを。よいしょ。
Well, let's get Ina's Yutyrannus. Heigh-ho.
はい。
Yes.
で、今回はししろんがテイムしてほしいから、イナがユウティラで。
So this time Shishiron wants to tame it, so Ina will be on the Yutyrannus.
はい。
Yes.
殴る感じかな？
We should hit it, right?
じゃあ、お、停止しといて、戻って。
Then... oh, stop and come back.
よし。
Alright.
ユウティラが...
The Yutyrannus...
おむ。
Oomph.
よし。
Alright.
ほい。
Hop.
じゃあ連れて来ようかな？ / あいよ。
Shall I go bring it over? / Sure.
えーっと、どこいるかな？
Um, where is it?
海沿いよ、ユウティ。
By the sea, Yuty.
うーーん、あ、いたいいたいいたい！
Hmm... Ah, found it, found it, found it!
誘える？ / よ、呼びますよ。
Can you lure it? / I-I'll call it over.
あい。
Okay.
お、来てる来てる来てる来てる！
Oh, it's coming, it's coming, it's coming!
なー
Huh?
ちょっとちょっと、こっち側かな？
Wait, maybe this way?
あ、いいよいいよ、その辺りで戦っちゃって
Ah, that's good. Fight it around there.
えーと、レベル、あ、135。
Let's see... level... oh, 135.
わぁ、結構高いね！めちゃめちゃ殴っちゃっていい、いいと思う。
Wow, that's pretty high! I think you can beat it up quite a bit.
でも、何か、と、止まった？
But it... stopped?
いや、まだまだ、多分。体力半分だからまだまだ。もうちょっとかな？
No, probably not yet. It's at half HP, so not yet. Just a bit more?
乗れる、乗った！
I can ride... I'm on!
あ、オッケーオッケーオッケー！
Ah, okay, okay, okay!
どいて、どいて！
Move, move!
えーと、どこ？この辺りにいないか？フンコロでもいい。
Let's see, where? Is it around here? A dung beetle is fine too.
いる？
Is there one?
フンコロでもいいんだが…
A dung beetle is fine, but...
あ、ここにはいません。
Ah, there isn't one here.
うわー、っぽいの。あ、いる、いる、いる。
Whoa, looks like one... Oh, there is, there is!
お、いる、いる、いる。
Oh, there it is, there it is!
お、オッケー。あと一回かな？もう一、もう一匹。
Oh, okay. Just one more time? Another one... one more.
もう一匹どこかに、どこかにいないか？
Is there another one somewhere? Somewhere around?
あ、あそこっぽいの。まっすぐ、フワワ先輩のところに。
Ah, something like that over there. Straight ahead, near Fuwawa-senpai.
いた？ / あ、いるいるいるいる！
Found it? / Ah, there is, there is!
オッケー、オッケー。あ、カマキリもいる。
Okay, okay. Ah, there's a Mantis too.
よいしょ。頼む！
There we go. Please!
ちょっと引っかかってる、引っかかって吸えない。
I'm stuck, I'm stuck and can't absorb.
ちょっと引いたらいいかも。あ、ここ、ここ！
Maybe back up a bit. Ah, here, here!
あか、マンティス。オッケー、あ、テイム、テイム！
Mantis is red. Okay, ah, tame, tame!
あ、できました？何でテイム？ちょっと待って、何、何でテイム？
Ah, did you get it? Tamed with what? Wait a sec, what did you tame it with?
コントロールとかで、あれ、あれではなく？ / コントロールじゃない。
With Control or something... wasn't it that? / It's not Control.
なんだ？テイムって画面に出てこない？
What is it? Doesn't "Tame" show up on the screen?
出なかったです。多分、名前…
It didn't show up. Probably because of the name...
名前つく画面が出てこない？ / はい。
The naming screen didn't pop up? / Yeah.
いや、何かボタンが、あれかも…
No, maybe the button is...
ん？左コントロール、右クリック？
Hm? Left Control, Right Click?
いや、もうそれテイム可能で、もうテイムしてる、テイムしてる、それ。
No, that one is already tameable, actually it's tamed, it's already tamed.
違う？あ、でも野生って書いてるな、あれ？
No? Ah, but it says wild. Huh?
あー。あ、白い四角になってる。 / ちょっと待って、ボタンが何かおかしいかも、私。
Ah, it's a white square. / Wait a sec, maybe my buttons are a bit weird.
吸収できてなかったかも。もう一回、こいつ、もう一回。
Maybe it wasn't absorbed. Let's do it again, this guy, one more time.
私ね、あ、ごめん。あれかも。
For me, ah, sorry, maybe that's it.
引き寄せ、もう一回海に、海に。
Pull it, let's go back to the sea, to the sea.
海に、海に。
To the sea, to the sea.
私さ、あの、あれしてるんだよね。あの、何だったっけ？ボタン、キーコントロール変えてるから。
You see, I... changed that. What was it? The button, because I changed the key binds.
あー、それの影響かも。
Ah, that might be why.
それの影響あるかも。ちょっと待って。 / じゃ、もう一回、自分で乗るわ。
That might have an effect. Wait a sec. / Okay, then I'll ride it myself this time.
お！
Oh!
熱い！
Hot!
クールタイム多分、5分ですからね。
The cooldown is probably 5 minutes.
クールタイムあるから無理かな。
Since there's a cooldown, maybe it's impossible.
すまね、ちょっとボタン見るわ。
Sorry, let me check the buttons.
最後なんか吠えなきゃいけないのかな？
Do we have to roar at the end or something?
あ、それができたら行けた、から、大丈夫。多分ね、ボタンなんだよね。
Ah, if we could do that, it would work, so it's fine. It's probably the buttons.
クールタイムが、えーと、4分。
The cooldown is... let's see, 4 minutes.
あと4分、オッケー。
4 minutes left, okay.
表示バグ？90%で足りなかった？足りなかったのかな？まだだったのかな？
Display bug? 90% wasn't enough? Maybe it wasn't enough? Or was it not ready?
いや、でも、しかも100%っぽいけどな。
No, but it looks like 100%.
四角プラス、マウスクリックってなってたから。テイムは勝手になるから。え、イナ、テイム昨日、勝手になった？炎の獅子。
Since it said Square + Mouse Click. Because taming happens automatically. Hey Ina, did the taming happen automatically yesterday? The fire lion?
はい。 / あ、じゃあ足りなかったのかな？
Yes. / Ah, then maybe it wasn't enough?
足りなかったのか、ちょっと。わかった。でも100%って出てるけどな、もう一回分だったのかな？
Maybe it was slightly short. Got it. But it says 100% though... maybe it needed one more go?
オッケー、ですかも。
Okay, maybe so.
咆哮せず時間切れになっちゃったのかな？もうちょっと引き連れて…
Did it time out without roaring? Let's lure it a bit more...
絶対ボタン表示出てたから、絶対ボタンだと思うんだけどな、私あれ。壁に引っかかってバグってたからかもね。
The button prompt was definitely there, so I really think it was the button. Maybe it glitched because it got stuck on the wall.
うーん。私ね、左コントロールしゃがみにしちゃってんだけど、ここはあんま関係ないもんな。
Yeah. I set Left Control to crouch, but that shouldn't really matter here.
あと何分だ？まだ3分ぐらいあるか。
How many minutes left? Still got about 3 minutes.
え、でも、なんかもう火がなくなってる？
Wait, but is the fire already gone?
乗ってみようか？ / あ、またありました。えーと。
Should I try riding it? / Ah, there it is again. Let's see...
何分。オッケー。
How many minutes... okay.
2分40秒。 / オッケー。
2 minutes 40 seconds. / Okay.
あれかな？する、マウント、オーバーライド、この辺かな？恐竜。
Could it be that? The "Mount Override" bind? Dinosaur...
この辺りに…あ、ローカルチャット。
Around here... Ah, local chat.
水遊びしてるわ。
It's playing in the water.
もう一回やってみるか。 / うん、もう一回。
Should we try one more time? / Yeah, one more time.
100になるまで殴るか。
Should we hit it until it hits 100?
あと何分かな？君は。
How many minutes left do you have?
あ、やばい。助けて！ / あいよ。
Oh, no. Help me! / Coming!
助けて。
Help.
あ、危ない！ / あ、危ない！
Oh, that was close! / Watch out!
あぶない！
Watch out!
まぁ死んでもベッドあるから。
Well, even if we die, we have beds.
いや、こっち、こっちだよ！
No, this way, this way!
殴って。
Hit it.
え？
Eh?
オッケー、オッケー。
Okay, okay.
死なない？オッケー、オッケー、オッケー。
Will it die? Okay, okay, okay.
オッケー、オッケー。
Okay, okay.
あぶい。
Dangerous.
あぶい。あう！
Dangerous. Ow!
初期値26秒です。
The initial value is 26 seconds.
なんでだったかな。
Why was that again...
左コントロール？
Left control?
うん。
Yeah.
左コントロール多分なんかに、あの、左クリックと右クリックがどうとかっていうのなかったっけ？
Left control, wasn't it like left-clicking and right-clicking or something?
特に...
Particularly...
あぶい！
Dangerous!
え？どこ行くの？
Eh? Where are you going?
え、しっちゃん！しっちゃん、こっち、こっち、こっち、こっち！
Eh, Shicchan! Shicchan, this way, this way, this way!
あぶない！もっと！
Watch out! More!
おら！
Take that!
あう。
Ow.
あと45...
45 seconds left...
お、もうちょっと。
Oh, a bit more.
もうちょっとです。
A bit more.
やばい、ししろんに虫がたかってるかも。
Oh no, Shishiron might have bugs on her.
そこ、この虫置いときたいんだけどな。
I want to leave these bugs there, though.
あ、いける、いける、いける。あの、飛びました、僕。
Ah, you can do it, you can do it. I jumped.
よし、あぶねえ。ししろん、多分もう行ける。
Okay, watch out. Shishiron, I think you can go now.
なんか動く、動く、動けない。
I can't move, can't move.
そろそろ乗れるぞ！
We should be able to ride soon!
行くぞ！あ、虫が。
Let's go! Ah, the bugs.
動け。あ、いた。
Move. Ah, there it is.
あー、あと10秒ぐらい。
Ah, about 10 seconds left.
10秒、10秒、10秒。
10 seconds, 10 seconds, 10 seconds.
じゃ、ここに虫置いときたいな。あ、痛い、痛い、痛い、死んだ。
Then, I want to leave the bugs here. Ah, it hurts, hurts, hurts, I died.
ああ、誰？
Ah, who's that?
あ、待って、じゃ、乗ろう、乗ろう、じゃ。
Ah, wait, then let's ride, let's ride.
乗ります。
I'll ride.
わ、分ける、分ける。あ、大丈夫？
I- I'll split them, split them. Ah, are you okay?
あ、確かに、分けるなら。
Ah, indeed, if we're splitting...
ちょっと...
Wait...
いや！
No!
殺したくないから。
Because I don't want to kill it.
そう。
Right.
うわっ！来ました。
Whoa! Here it comes.
どこ？
Where?
いや、ユーティ、カバー。
No, Yuty, cover!
殴ってもいいかな。
Is it okay if I hit it?
助け！だきすん、だきすん、もうやめてくれ！
Help! Dakisun, Dakisun, stop this!
殴るな、だきすん！
Don't hit, Dakisun!
いや、殺したくないよね。あ、痛い、痛い、痛い。
No, you don't want to kill it. Ah, ow, ow, ow.
テイム、テイム、テイム。
Tame, tame, tame!
動いて、動いて、ここ。
Move, move, here.
きゃー！あ、来ました。
Kyaa! Ah, it's here.
降りちゃった。
I fell off.
乗れるかな。
Can I ride?
乗れるか？
Can you ride?
行くぞ！
Let's go!
ちょっと、ちょっと危ないんですけど。
Wait, this is a bit dangerous.
あ、ユーティがやばい。
Ah, Yuty is in trouble.
乗れない。
I can't ride.
ちょっと。
Wait.
今乗れないっすね。
I can't ride right now.
どうですか？今、今はどうですか？
How is it? Now, how about now?
乗れなかったよ。
I couldn't ride.
今固まってた。
It was frozen just now.
あ！もう一回やります。
Ah! I'll try again.
はい。
Okay.
どうですか？
How about now?
乗れないね。
I can't ride.
まだ？もう一回。
Not yet? Once more.
まだ。
Not yet.
乗れた！
I rode it!
オッケー。
Okay.
来た。
It's here.
ここはめっちゃ合いますからね。
This matches perfectly.
どこ？
Where?
ここ。
Here.
あ。でもなんか、上に来ました。
Ah. But it went up somehow.
あ、消えちゃった。あ、ここに、ここに。
Ah, it disappeared. Ah, here, here.
あ、オッケー。
Ah, okay.
ここ。
Here.
ここももう一匹いる。
There's another one here too.
もうちょっと行くかな。
Should we go a bit further?
うん。
Yeah.
はい、もう一匹。
Yes, another one.
あ、私のところ。
Ah, at my place.
オッケー。
Okay.
後ろ、後ろ、後ろ、後ろ。
Behind, behind, behind, behind.
これで方向が...
With this, the direction...
で、今100%？
So, is it 100% now?
うん。で、吸収してもダメ。それ吸収できてないかも。
Yeah. And absorbing doesn't work. It might not be absorbing.
吸収がないんだよね。どのボタンだっけ？
There's no absorb. Which button was it again?
コントロール右クリック。
Control right-click.
コントロール右、左クリックか右クリックだって、初期は。
Left-click or right-click with Control, initially.
コントロール右クリック。
Control right-click.
ボタンがね、やっぱりね、ないんだよね。
The button, indeed, isn't there.
あ、じゃ、多分あれだ。リセットしなきゃいけないかも。
Ah, then maybe that's it. We might need to reset.
設定リセット、全設定をデフォルトでこれいけんのかな。
Reset settings, can I restore all settings to default?
キーボード全リセットで。
Reset all keyboard settings.
コントロール左クリック。
Control left-click.
コントロール押して、左クリック。
Hold Control and left-click.
オッケー。
Okay.
なったかな？
Did it work?
どうだ？
How is it?
あれ？なんかバグった？
Huh? Is it bugged?
全然動いてない。
It's not moving at all.
なんか歩行モードになった。ちょっと、ちょっと、ちょっと。
It went into walk mode somehow. Wait, wait, wait.
あー！
Ahhh!
いや、でも、そろそろ。コントロール左にしましたけど。
No, but soon... I set left control, though.
時間切れ！
Time's up!
ユーティのHPも、これなんか、あげれるんですかね？
Can we increase Yuty's HP too, like this?
ご飯をあげたら、ちょっと回復するかな。
If we give it food, will it recover a bit?
ベッドが今使えません。やっぱりあれだね。
We can't use the bed right now. As I thought, it's that.
あ、クールタイムだね。うん、やっぱりない。
Ah, cooldown, right? Yeah, indeed there isn't.
キーコンフィグであれしてたわ。
I was doing something with my key config.
違うのになってた？
Was it set to something else?
違うのになってるね。
Yeah, it was different.
あ、じゃあちょっともう1回5分待ちかな？
Ah, then maybe we have to wait another five minutes?
オッケー。さっきフブちゃんやっていいよ。
Okay. Fubu-chan, you can go ahead first.
あ、でも5分待つくらいなら、新しいやつの方がいいかもね、連れてった方が。
But if we have to wait five minutes, maybe it's better to bring a new one.
そうですね。
Yeah, that's true.
うん、こいつ1回やっちゃおう。
Yeah, let's just finish this one off first.
おらー！
Take this!
あ、これ、家が違うわ。
Ah, this one belongs to a different house.
やっちゃいますよ。
I'll take care of it.
うん。
Yeah.
どうぞ。
Go ahead.
えっと。
Let's see.
え、ってことはちょっと待って、これ。グラフィック設定変わってる？もしかして。
Wait, does that mean my graphic setting changed?
グラフィックは変わってないか。
No, maybe the graphics didn't change.
キーが変わったので、ええと。
Since the keys changed, let's see...
いけるか？
Can I do this?
熱い！
It's hot!
熱いね。
It is hot.
でも、これで...今引っかかってくれてるか？
But is it stuck right now?
変わったから。
Because it changed.
え、いってないかな？
Wait, is it not going through?
かな。でもこいつ130なんだっけ？
I wonder. But is this one level 130?
あ、135くらいでした。
Ah, it was around 135.
135はでも欲しいよな。でもちょっと耐えるの大変だよね。
We definitely want a 135. But keeping it alive is a bit tough, huh.
いや、でも3分だったら、待つかも、いけるかも。
Well, if it's three minutes, we might be able to wait.
いける？じゃあ、ちょっとこっち側に引き付けよう、引き付けよう、こっち。
Really? Then let's lure it over to this side.
はい。
Okay.
ちょっと待ってよ、プテラで、取りたい。プテラで、取らせて...
Wait, I want to get it with the Ptera. Let me get it with...
ああ！また落ちちゃった、自分。
Ah! I fell off again.
大丈夫です、多分。なんとなくしたら大丈夫かな。
It'll be fine, probably. It should be okay somehow.
大丈夫、大丈夫。
It's okay, it's okay.
こっちだぞ。
Over here!
来ない？
Not coming?
ユウティに、あれあげようか。あの、また生きる、今日貰ったアイテム。
Shall I give Yuty that item? The revive item we got today.
ユウティ多分使えるかも。
Yuty can probably use it.
使えるなら、使っちゃった方がいいかも。
If we can use it, we might as well.
そうですね、ユウティにあげます。
Right, I'll give it to Yuty.
うん。
Yeah.
オッケー、ユウティ全然離れてもらってていいよ。
Okay, Yuty can stay far away.
はい。
Okay.
うん、ここ引き付けとこ、ここで。
Yeah, let's lure it here.
あんまり引っかかんないか。
It's not getting stuck much.
うん。
Yeah.
いいよ、ここでしばらく待ってようね、ねこちゃんね。
Alright, let's wait here for a bit, Neko-chan.
ふう。
*sigh*
Yeah, I didn't bring enough food.
えっと。
Let's see.
あ、「デイリーミッションの付与が完了しました」って来た。できたね。
Ah, it says "Daily missions have been assigned." It's done.
おお、できた？
Oh, it did?
ってことは毛皮装備が来たのかな？
Does that mean the fur gear is here?
毛皮装備？
Fur gear?
えっと。
Let's see.
よし、プテラもう1匹いるから行くわ。
Alright, I have one more Ptera, so I'll go.
おお、ファイト。
Oh, good luck.
オッケー。
Okay.
あ、多分そろそろベッド復活してるのでは？
Ah, the bed should be active again soon, right?
あ、マジ？
Oh, really?
うん。
Yeah.
じゃあ、湧けるか。
Then I can spawn there.
よいしょ。
There we go.
ふう。
*sigh*
うーん。
Hmm...
おい、ねこちゃんどこ行くねん。
Hey, where are you going, Neko-chan?
Now, Yuty needs raw meat.
生肉ありますか？
Do you have any raw meat?
あ、そのあたりの虫狩ったら大丈夫だよ、多分。
Ah, if you hunt the bugs around there, you should be fine, probably.
あ、オッケーです。
Ah, okay.
虫とか食べちゃったら。
Just eat the bugs.
近接武器で攻撃とマウス左クリックか。
Melee weapon attack and left mouse click.
どっかくるくるしてる。よいしょ。
Something is spinning somewhere. There.
虫退治よ。
Bug extermination time.
テレポートってさ。
You know, teleporting...
うん。
Yeah.
ベッド、ベッドって何分湧きなの？あれ。
Beds... how many minutes is the cooldown for spawning on them?
5分とか10分とかだったかな。
I think it was around five or ten minutes.
まだ出てないな。
It's still not showing up.
ああ、だったら迎えに行った方がいいかい？
Ah, then should I go pick you up?
マップで湧いたっけ？
Did you spawn on the map?
マップで多分...
Probably on the map...
まだ出てないね。
It's still not showing up.
いや、あれがあるから大丈夫だよ、プテラもう1匹いるから。
No, it's fine because we have that. I have another Ptera anyway.
本当？
Really?
あ、うん、ちょっと待って。湧けるかな？
Ah, yeah. Wait a second. Can I spawn?
寝袋使い切りなの？
Are sleeping bags single-use?
ああ、使い切りか！そっか、ベッドじゃないからか。
Oh, single-use! Right, because it's not a bed.
あ、なるほどね。
Ah, I see.
ああ。
Oh.
じゃ、行くわ。
Then I'll go.
オッケー。
Okay.
よいしょ。
There we go.
あと何分だろう？よいしょ。
How many more minutes? There.
ベッドどっかにあった気がするんだよな。
I feel like there was a bed somewhere.
まああと何分だ？お前。
Well, how many more minutes do you have?
皮ないか。
No hide?
う...
Oh...
そろそろ時間かな？
Is it about time?
はい。
Yes.
ただ、ちょっと寝袋持ってくわ。ちょっと待っててほしい。
But I'll bring a sleeping bag. Please wait a bit.
あいよー。
Alright.
じゃ、先に自分やっちゃっていい？今いけるかい？
Then, is it okay if I do mine first? Can you go now?
ええっと...
Let's see...
今連れてくる。
I'll bring it over now.
あ、はい。
Ah, okay.
あいよ。
Sure thing.
もうちょっと、もうちょっとこっち側、陸側の方がいいな。
A bit more... a bit more this way, closer to the shore is better.
陸の方が嬉しいな。
I'd prefer land.
あ、あれ出していいし。よいしょ。
Ah, you can pull that out. Heave-ho.
この辺ですかね？
Around here?
おこたいよー。
It's angry!
よいしょ。
Heave-ho.
あ、乗れた！
Ah, I mounted it!
あ、オッケーオッケー。オッケー。
Ah, okay okay. Okay.
ええっと、どこだどこだ？
Let's see, where is it, where is it?
あ、いたいた。これ死んでる？
Ah, there it is. Is this dead?
死んでる！
It's dead!
あ、来た来た来た。いけた。
Ah, here it is, here it is. I did it.
あ、え？
Oh, really?
テイムも100％だからいけた、いけた！
The tame is at 100%, so we got it, we got it!
あーー！よかったーー！
Aah! Thank goodness!
わら、木材。
Thatch, wood.
オッケー。
Okay.
来た！
It's here!
ナイス！
Nice!
ふう。
Phew.
あれ、わらないの？
Huh, is there no thatch?
あると思うけどな、どっかのチェストか何か。
I think there is some, in some chest or something.
全然わらがねえぞ、わらが。
There's no thatch at all, none.
にゃう。
Meow.
猫また「おこたい」って名前にしてあった。あっし。
I named the Nekomata "Angry" again. Yep.
ベッド。
Bed.
ユーティは戻って。
Yuti, go back.
すいませんねえ。
Sorry about that.
よいしょ。
Heave-ho.
いえいえ、でも早く行けました。
No problem, but it went fast.
にゃ。
Meow.
はいよ。ちょっとここに。
Okay. Just a bit here.
めちゃくちゃ慣れてるわ。さすがすぎる。
You're so used to this. As expected.
え、こうか。
Ah, like this?
お、ファイヤーうんこ。
Oh, fire poop.
ファイヤーうんこ。
Fire poop.
キーコンフィグ直したんで安心してください。
I fixed the key config, so please don't worry.
オッケー。
Okay.
どこ行くんお前。
Where are you going?
間違えた。
Made a mistake.
あいつどこ行くねん。
Where is that guy going?
あれ？お前、おこよ！おこよ！
Huh? You, you're angry! Angry!
来た来た来た。
It's here, it's here.
おこよ！
Angry!
やべ、めっちゃ貯まってる、ここ。
Crap, there's so much piled up here.
お布団じゃなくって...
Not a futon...
すいませんけど火山行かせて...
Sorry, but let me go to the volcano...
火山だ！
It's the volcano!
あ、火山、火山だ。火山だ！
Ah, volcano, volcano. It's the volcano!
火山だ！
Volcano!
火山？火山、火山だ。
Volcano? Volcano, volcano.
よいしょ。
Heave-ho.
火山に連れてかれます。
I'm being taken to the volcano.
今行きます。
I'm going now.
あいよー。
Alright.
オッケー。
Okay.
にゃう。
Meow.
あ、ボイチャの設定も戻っちゃってるわ。
Ah, my voice chat settings went back to default.
直さないと。
I have to fix them.
おっしゃ。
Alright.
みゃう。
Meow.
みゃう、みゃう。可愛いみゃう。
Meow, meow. Cute meow.
これ何でしたっけ？キーが。あの、ちっちゃくやる...
What was this key again? To make it small...
ちっちゃくなるのはね、えーっとEを長押しして「Eキー」
To make it small, let's see, long press E and then "E key."
で、多分、なんだろ、変身っていうのがあるのかな。
And then, probably, what is it, there's something like "Transform."
あ、変身！
Ah, transform!
あ、そうそうそう。そうそう。
Ah, yes yes yes. Yes.
で、乗りながらも一応できて、コントロールCを押すと、
And you can also do it while riding, if you press Ctrl+C,
ああ、なるほど。変身、そうそう。
Ah, I see. Transform, yes yes.
コントロールCでいけないかな？無理か。
Can we do it with Ctrl+C? No?
やべ、キーコンフィグ全部直ってるからこれちょっと、あとで、あれしなきゃ。
Crap, all my key configs are reset, so I have to do that later.
あ、これベッドだと土台いるんだ。
Ah, for a bed you need a foundation.
あ、そうそうそう。
Ah, yes yes yes.
やべ、ベッド持ってきちゃった。
Crap, I brought a bed.
あ、でも一応寝袋置いてるから。
Ah, but I placed a sleeping bag anyway.
あ、これって分けるんだっけ？
Ah, do we share this?
多分トライブだったら分けられるのでは、という...
Maybe if we're in a tribe we can share it...
えーっと、待ってよ。
Let's see, wait.
これ私の死体どこだっけ？あ、あった。
Where was my corpse again? Ah, there it is.
俺のカバンどこかにございませんか？
Is my bag anywhere around here?
えーっと、あ、この、うしろのカバンが、この辺だとどこ、これ、これかな？これかな？
Let's see, ah, this... the bag in the back, around here, where is it, this, is it this? Is it this?
あ、これかな？
Ah, maybe this?
助かります。
That helps a lot.
よし、じゃあ連れてくるか。
Alright, then shall I bring it over?
よろしくお願いします。
Thank you in advance.
おーい。もう一匹、もう一匹。
Oi. One more, one more.
近くにいないかな？
Is there none nearby?
あ、もう一匹？
Ah, one more?
あ、寝袋同じトライブ共有できませんだって。
Ah, it says we can't share sleeping bags in the same tribe.
あ、そうんだ。
Ah, is that so?
寝袋、皮と繊維だっけ？
Sleeping bags, is it hide and fiber?
皮と繊維。うん、ある？
Hide and fiber. Yeah, do you have any?
皮はある。
I have hide.
あ、ほしいかも
Ah, I might want that.
拠点戻るに...
To go back to base...
あー、ユウティ出して
Ah, let's summon Yuty.
おし、ユウティ
Alright, Yuty...
よし、ユウティール
Okay, Yutyrannus.
繊維はここから
Fiber is from here.
ユウティじゃない
That's not Yuty!
はい、サンキュー
Okay, thank you.
ユウティこっち
Yuty, over here.
ユウティいるかい？
Is Yuty here?
あ、ボス出ます
Ah, summoning the boss.
はいよー。出ました
Alright. It's out.
生肉めっちゃ必要でしたね
We really needed a lot of raw meat, didn't we?
そうだね、やっぱりね、いっぱい食べるからな
That's true. After all, they eat a lot.
いっぱい食べるね
They sure eat a lot.
えっと、近くに、もしかすると、虫たちが...
Um, nearby, maybe, the bugs...
いないか？
Are they not around?
あれ、なんか、全然...
Huh, there's none at all...
ファイヤーキャット、どこ？
Where is the Pyromane?
いて
Ow.
あ、ユウティ、足にいる。It's okay.
Ah, Yuty is under my feet. It's okay.
モンボしまって
Put the cryopod away.
Yuty will rise from the dead if need be.
よいしょ
Heave-ho.
おねむちゃん
Sleepy head.
みゃおみゃおどこ？
Where's Meow-Meow?
みゃおみゃお、おーいみゃおみゃお
Meow-Meow, hey Meow-Meow.
おーい、みゃおみゃお
Hey, Meow-Meow.
おるか？
Are you there?
おる、あ、しっしっしっ
There you are! Ah, ts-ts-ts...
いたいたいたいた！なんどうせなら違う色とか思ったけど、こいつにしとくか
There it is! I wanted a different color if possible, but I'll go with this one.
さ、みゃおみゃお、おいで
Come on, Meow-Meow, come here.
こちらや
Over here.
で、虫たちが...
So, the bugs...
あんまりないっすね、今日
There aren't many today.
雑魚？うん
Trash mobs? Yeah.
ちょっと走り、走らなきゃいけないかもね
We might have to run around a bit.
すいませんな
Sorry about that.
はーい、今連れてきてますよー
Okay, I'm bringing them over now~
おーい
Ooh~
わー！
Wah~!
何がいた今？
What was that just now?
うおー！
Whoa~!
うおー！行くぞ！
Whoa! Here we go!
心臓を捧げよう！
Dedicate your heart!
捧げよ！捧げよ！
Dedicate! Dedicate!
殴れ、イナ！
Hit it, Ina!
うわー！おら！
Whoa! Take that!
あ、ミスっちゃ
Ah, I missed.
いって
Ouch.
おっけ
Okay.
今ここで、はい、待っときます
I'll wait right here.
ちょっといいポジションに...
In a slightly better position...
はい。55％です
Yes. It's at 55%.
体力弱い、すぐ乗れそう
Its health is low, looks like you can ride it soon.
あ、今行ける？ちょっと止まったんですけど
Ah, can we go now? It stopped for a moment.
もう一回
One more time.
まだ
Not yet.
どうですか？乗れた、乗れた
How is it? I mounted it, mounted it!
おけおけおけ
Okay, okay, okay.
虫！
Bugs!
虫どこかいる？
Are there bugs anywhere?
虫が全然...
There are no bugs at all...
あ、いる、正面、正面いる、正面いるね
Ah, there they are! In front! In front of us!
正面ね
In front, indeed.
もう一匹、もう一匹多分いる、いるよな
There's probably one more, right? There is.
あ、いけた、いけた、いけた
Ah, I did it, did it, did it!
はやい！やったー！
So fast! Yay!
じゃ、犬、犬、犬神ころねにしとくか
Then, let's name it Inugami Korone.
お肩凝っちゃった
My shoulders got stiff.
おけ、これで。で、あとは、そうだね、ちょっとレベリングはしたいから
Okay, that's done. And then, well, we want to do some leveling.
そうだね
Yeah.
で、肩のせペットにする
So, make it a shoulder pet.
一旦拠点にじゃあ帰ろうかな
Shall we head back to base for now?
はい。重量過多...
Okay. Overburdened...
お疲れ、ユウティ。よくできました
Good job, Yuty. Well done.
さすがや
As expected.
肩に載せる
Put it on your shoulder.
そう、肩に載せると、ちっちゃくなる
Yes, if you put it on your shoulder, it gets small.
おけ。お騒がせしました、本当に
Okay. Sorry for all the fuss, really.
いや、よかったよかった。ほんじゃあ一旦帰ろうか。あっちに
No, glad it worked out. Well then, let's head back for now. Over there.
てか、やべえ、キーコンフィグ全部変わってるからすげえやりづらい
By the way, oh man, all my key configs are changed, so it's super hard to play!
ちょっと拠点戻って直すわ。あぶねえあぶねえ
I'll go back to base and fix it. That was close, that was close.
私、インベントリ「Tab」で開くとかやってたから
I used to open inventory with 'Tab' and stuff.
あ、そう。自分も「Tab」でやってるわ。そうそうそうそう。今ね、「I」ボタン押さないと開かなくて。あれ？何で開かねえんだみたいになってる
Oh, really? I also use 'Tab'. Right, right. Now, I have to press 'I' to open it. I was like, 'Huh? Why won't it open?'
はい
Yes.
よし、帰るぞ
Alright, let's head back.
よいしょ。お肉も戻っとくか
Heave-ho. Should we put the meat back?
いやー
Yeah~
あ、そういうこと？ペット重量過多ね
Oh, is that it? The pet is overburdened.
はい、よいしょ
Yes, heave-ho.
モンボどうしようかな。モンボないんだよね
What should I do about the cryopods? I don't have any cryopods.
あ、モンボなかった？何でやろうとしてた？
Ah, you didn't have cryopods? What were you trying to use?
あのね、ペット持っていったまま、肩乗り...
You see, I took the pet with me, shoulder-mounted...
にゃんこで乗ると重いんだよね。
It's heavy when I ride with the cat.
あ、何？
Oh, what?
今重量いくらなんだろう、526。なんか重いって出るな。
I wonder how much weight I'm carrying. 526? It says it's heavy.
ただ、あ、こいつの重量自体が... プテラ自体が？
But wait, this guy's weight limit... The Ptera's limit?
プテラ自体がでしたね。
It was the Ptera's limit.
あげたら何とか...
If I level it up, maybe...
お、いけるか？
Oh, will that work?
えー、捨てるか。
Well, let's discard some items.
鉄装備捨てるのちょっと嫌だな。あ、この辺捨てるか。
I don't really want to discard iron gear. Oh, let's discard these.
よいしょ。
There we go.
マンモス組がマンモスいけたのかな？まだかな？
Did the mammoth team manage to get a mammoth? Not yet?
そうだね。
I wonder.
帰ってきてないね、まだ。
They haven't returned yet.
あれ？マンモスいる、マンモスいる。赤ちゃん？
Huh? There's a mammoth! A baby?
幼少期のマンモス赤ちゃんいる。
There is a baby mammoth!
お、マジ？
Oh, really?
ベイビーやん。
It's a baby!
ベイビー！
Baby!
ベイビー赤ちゃん、ベイビー赤ちゃんはどっちも同じ意味や、ベイビーマンモスや。
A baby baby? That's redundant. It's a baby mammoth!
ただ、私も肩乗りのやつ、ちょっとレベルあげたいんだよね。
But I also want to level up my shoulder pet a bit.
そうだね。近くのあれだ、ブロントサウルスとかなんか倒しに行っちゃっても。
Yeah. Maybe we can go hunt down a nearby Brontosaurus or something.
一旦、ちょっとボイチャに行くか。ちょっと報告してこよう。
First, let's head over to voice chat and report it.
どの辺だったかな。
I wonder where they were.
あった。ちょっと一旦、拠点行くわ。
There they are. I'll head back to base for a moment.
はい。
Okay.
一旦拠点に集会所戻って...
I'll head back to the meeting point at base...
やばい、離れよう。
Whoops, better get away.
銃使ってやろう。ブロントさん。
Let's use a gun on him. Mr. Brontosaurus.
ブロントさん。
Mr. Bronto.
で、ええとね、キーコンフィグを直したいんですよね。
And, well, I want to fix my key config.
おっきい、ウンコ。
A big poop.
ここもなんかあれになっちゃってるわ。
This is messed up too.
ただいま。
I'm back.
50分からアイスワーム？
Iceworms starting from 50 minutes?
はい。
Yes.
行こうって話になって、それまでちょっとレベリング？
We decided to go, so should we level up until then?
オッケー。
Okay.
で、この3人プラス、トワの4人で行こうってことになって、で、イナのユーティを、トワに貸してあげてほしいのね。
So, the three of us plus Towa, four in total, are going. And we'd like you to lend Ina's Yuty to Towa.
はい。
Sure.
で、我々3人パイイルで、殴りに行く感じで。
And the three of us will go on Pyles to attack.
オッケー。
Okay.
よし。じゃあ、ちょっとレベリング行こうか。
Alright. Let's go do some leveling.
うん、ちょっと私、キーコンフィグ直します。
Yeah, I'm going to fix my key config first.
はーい。
Okay.
ほな、じゃあイナ行くか。
Well then, let's go, Ina.
レッツレベリング。
Let's level up!
あ、イナ帰ってきてるかな？
Oh, is Ina back yet?
あ、はい。
Ah, yes.
あ、いたいたいた。じゃあ。
Ah, there you are. Well then,
空飛べるの、プテラ乗って、猫連れて行こう。
let's ride on a flying Ptera and take the cat along.
はい。
Okay.
よいしょ。
Here we go.
たぶんね、こっちにでっかいのが...
Probably, there's a big one over here...
ええと、いるかな。
Let's see, is there one?
ブロントサウルスがいると、めちゃめちゃ美味しいんだけどな。
If there's a Brontosaurus, it would yield a ton of EXP.
よいしょ。わ、ティラノはさすがに無理かな。
Alright. Whoa, a T-Rex is probably too much.
ティラノは無理だね。
Yeah, a T-Rex is impossible.
さ、さすがに。
Indeed.
ええと、でっかいでっかい恐竜、でっかい首の長い恐竜はいませんか。
Let's see. A big, big dinosaur... is there a big dinosaur with a long neck?
あれ？あ、いたいたいたいた。
Huh? Ah, there it is, there it is!
よし。
Alright.
と、ここにいてもらう、いや、いてもらうか、ここに。
And we'll have it stay... well, let's keep it here.
ね。
Right?
トワのユーティってさ、誰か持ってる？
By the way, does anyone have Towa's Yuty?
あ、私が持ってます。
Oh, I have it.
あ、オッケーオッケー、わかった。はい。
Ah, okay okay, got it. Yes.
近接攻撃も上げとく。えい。
I'll also increase its melee damage. There.
あ、キー。
Ah, key.
これ、これどうやるの？ええと。
How do we do this? Um...
F。F。
F. F.
Fダブルクリック、二回かな？あ、オッケーオッケー。
Double-click F, maybe twice? Ah, okay, okay.
で、E長押しの...あ、よし、オッケー。
And then hold E... Ah, alright. Okay.
レッツゴー！
Let's go!
あ、こいつ、こいつ...こいつ、ブロントさん...
Ah, this one, this one... This is a Bronto...
あ、ちょっと、ふふふ、間違えた。こいつ、デ、ディプロだった、全然違った。
Ah, wait, haha, my bad. This was a Diplo. Completely different.
ちょっと私重すぎて、ええと。
I'm a bit too heavy, so um...
あ、アイテム！アイテムが...
Ah, my items! My items are...
アイテム一旦プテラの中に入れちゃいな、全部。
Just put all your items inside the Pteranodon for now.
あ、そうですね。うん。
Ah, right. Yeah.
ええと、トライブの管理。
Um, tribe management...
つかむ。
Grab.
スルーをする。
I'll skip this.
何でこんなに持ってるんだろ。
Why am I carrying so much?
よいしょ。これ大丈夫か。
There we go. Is this alright?
オッケー。
Okay.
うん。うん。よいしょ。おらぁ！
Yep. Yep. Here we go. Take this!
あいあいあい、殴ってこう、殴ってこう、殴ってこう。
Alright, alright, let's keep hitting it, keep hitting it.
あれ、どこだったっけ？ボイチャの。常時みたいなやつ。
Where was it again? The voice chat setting... The "always on" option.
ボイチャ？ボイチャ、キー切り替えをオフにみたいな、オンを...
Voice chat? Like turning off push-to-talk to make it always on...
あ、他のお肉も。ナイス！
Ah, and the other meat too... Nice!
はーい。
Okay.
これレベル上がってるかな？
Did its level go up?
そう、今行動不能になってるから。
Yeah, because it's immobilized right now...
あ、これでお肉齧れるからね。
Ah, now we can harvest the meat.
トントンって。
Tap, tap...
オッケー、オッケー。でもめちゃめちゃレベル。上がる。
Okay, okay. But the level... is going way up.
おおー。
Wow!
体力とかかな？体力とか攻撃力？そうですね。
Maybe health? Health or melee damage? Yes, indeed.
体力...うおー！
Health... Whoa!
よし、他にも探すか。
Alright, let's search for others too.
じゃあ、一旦。一旦にゃんこホームで。
Then, for now... let's head back to Nyanko Home for now.
よいしょ。オッケー。
There we go. Okay.
またでっかいの探しに行こう。あれ、どこだったかな？
Let's go look for a big one again. Wait, where was it?
ボイチャ設定って何かDiscordの中の設定のやつなかったっけ？そう、それ今探してるんだけど...
Wasn't there some voice chat setting inside Discord? Yeah, I'm looking for that right now...
あ、あった、あった、あった、あった！詳細、会話の切り替えか。
Ah, found it, found it, found it! Advanced, toggle communication...
詳細、会話の切り替え...よいしょ。
Advanced, toggle communication... There we go.
石、石、石、石、石もいらないな。あ、これだ！あった、あった、あった！
Stones, stones... I don't need stones either. Ah, this is it! Found it, found it!
これ、もらっとこ。ありがとうございます。
I'll take this. Thank you very much.
あ、ありがとうございます。オッケー、レッツゴー！
Ah, thank you very much! Okay, let's go!
え、重そうなんだけど。さあ、でっかいのいるかな？でっかいの。
Huh? It looks heavy. Now, will we find a big one? A big one...
お留守じゃないかな？
Maybe they're not home?
怖いなんか。木、めちゃめちゃ倒してる音聞こえない？あれ？
I feel scared somehow. Don't you hear the sound of trees getting knocked down?
何これ？見えない敵がいる！何？
What is this? There's an invisible enemy! What?
あ、草の中にいるの？お？何？
Ah, is it inside the grass? Oh? What is it?
なんか、でっ...なんか、いた。
There's something b... There was something.
なんか、いましたね。ね、何だったんだろ、あれ？
There was something indeed. Right, what was that?
あ、あれは、ティラノさんなのかギガノトなのかわからないのがいる。
Ah, there's one over there, I can't tell if it's a Rex or a Giganoto.
ちょっと怖い...多分、いける、いける。
A bit scary... Probably we can do it, we can do it.
あ！多分いけるので行きます。
Ah! I think I can manage, so I'll go.
あいよー！このあたりにいないかな？でっかいの。
Alright! Are there any big ones around here?
あ、昨日はなんか。この上にありましたけどね。
Ah, yesterday there was something up here, though.
ね、いたよね。
Yeah, there was one.
え、何？肉食に食べられちゃったかな？
Eh, what? Maybe a carnivore ate it?
よし、レベリング！二人、どこいる？
Alright, leveling! Where are you two?
ええと...仮拠点のところ。オッケー！
Um... At the temporary base. Okay!
なんか、すごいでっかいのいる！
There's an incredibly big one!
これ、やばいかな？このクマみたいなの、アリクイみたいなのいる、なんか。
Is this bad? There's this bear-like, anteater-like thing.
何だ、こいつ？テリ、テリジノだっけ？
What is this guy? A Theri, Therizino, was it?
クマ...クマもやるか...
A bear... Shall we take on the bear too?
パイロに...パイロにお肉入れてあげたいよね。
To Pyro... We want to put some meat inside Pyro, right?
そうだね。
Yeah.
え、これどうやって戻すの？
Eh, how do we turn it back?
ええと、E。パイロはE長押しでチェンジってのが、変身かな？
Um, E. For Pyro, hold E and there should be "change", maybe "transform"?
あれ？何か...E長押し？
Huh? Something... Hold E?
うん、で、画面出して...あれ？
Yeah, and then open the menu... Huh?
あれ？でないな
Huh? It's not working.
あれ？なんか、パイロのフォーム皆さんどうやって…
Huh? How do you guys change the Pyromane's form...
あれ、なんか「E」開けない
Huh, I can't open it with "E."
あ、こうか？
Ah, is it like this?
ありがと。Rの長押しだった。
Thanks! It was holding down "R."
あ、いけた、いけた、いけた。おっけ、おっけ。
Ah, there we go, got it. Okay, okay.
ほんで？
And then?
じゃあ、この辺りの奴らを
Then, the ones around here...
はい。
Okay.
よいしょ。こいつかな？
All right. This one?
パイロって肉？
Do Pyromanes eat meat?
パイロ肉。
Pyromanes eat meat.
おっけー。
Okay.
お、メガテリ…
Oh, Megathe...
うわぁ！
Whoa!
いー、いー！
Take that, take that!
で、な…ラブドプラス？あれか。
And then... Labdu-plus? That one?
おっけー。
Okay.
りゃー！
Hyaa!
あ、よしよしよし。美味い。
Ah, good, good, good. Tasty.
おら！
Take that!
よし！
Nice!
おっけー、さっきみんなが言ってくれたから
Okay, since everyone told me earlier...
長押しだって。
...it was "holding it down."
くっ！
Ugh!
ヒットポイントが低いんだ、あいつ結構。
His HP is pretty low.
強い、こいつ。
This guy's strong!
もっとより強い、55なのに。
He's stronger than expected, even though he's level 55!
ええー？！
What?!
なんかバフついてるのか？
Is he buffed or something?
虫バフで強化されてる、ほわぁー！
He's strengthened by a bug buff! Whoa!
うわぁ！
Aaaah!
うっ、やっぱ体力がまずいな、ちょっと。こっちの体力がやばい。
Ugh, my HP is getting bad. My HP is in trouble.
ヒットポイント2000ちょっと低いな、なんか。
2000 HP is a bit low...
一緒に殴れるかな？
Can we fight it together?
あ、やばいやばいやばい！
Ah, this is bad, bad, bad!
当たらなければ
If I don't get hit...
あ、この子、こういう奴のがいいの？
Ah, is this kind of creature better?
ビビッ！
Ah!
いや、虫バフめんどくさいね。
Man, the bug buff is so annoying.
虫バフ、早く切れてほしい。
I wish the bug buff would wear off.
切れないか。
It's not wearing off?
なんか、HPとか上がる…
Does it increase HP or something...
こ、アルマジロとか？
An armadillo?
ん？
Huh?
こことか、アルマジロとかいいの？
Like here, is an armadillo good?
アルマジロとかもやっちゃっていい！
You can take on armadillos too!
この辺の子
These ones around here...
こいつを言ったんだけど、こいつは今
I said that one, but that one is now...
強い！
Strong!
あ、やばいやばい、ダックスン、ダックスン、ダックスンが！
Ah, wait, wait, Dachs, Dachs, Dachs!
ダックスン！
Dachs!
やばい、ダックスンが死ぬ！
Oh no, Dachs is gonna die!
あ！
Ah!
ちょっと待って。
Hold on a second.
いくよ。
I'm going.
乗る乗る乗る！
I'm mounting, mounting!
おっけー、おっけー！
Okay, okay!
おっけー、おっけー、ちょっとあいつをほっと、ほっとこう、ほっとこう、おいとこう。
Okay, okay. Let's just leave that guy alone, leave him, let's leave him.
うわぁー！
Whoa!
あ、飛んでない、飛んでない。
Ah, I'm not flying, I'm not flying.
危ない、危ない。
Close one, close one.
てら、どこ？どこ？
Ptera, where? Where?
おっけー。
Okay.
ちこ置いてくるか。
I'll go drop off Chiko.
つええ！
So strong!
うわぁ！
Whoa!
走り回っててても、レベルって上がる？
Does your level go up even if you're just running around?
上がったりする。
It does sometimes.
なるほど。
I see.
あの鳥もやろうか。
Shall we do that bird too?
もんぶ置いてこうか。
Should I go leave Monbu?
よいしょ。
All right.
合流した！
We met up!
はーい！
Okay!
おっけー、じゃあこいつ倒したら行こう。
Okay, let's go after defeating this one.
あ、どこですか？
Ah, where are you?
簡易拠点にいてくれたら。
If you could stay at the temporary base.
あ、おっけーおっけー。
Ah, okay, okay.
で、あれだ、周回から、あの、毛皮の、納品中？
And also, the fur delivery from gathering?
鳥、取りに行かないといけないかも。
We might need to go get the birds.
あ、鳥、私も持ってる。
Ah, birds, I have some too.
あ、鳥？
Ah, birds?
じゃあじゃあ、我々も取りに行く。
Then we'll go get them too.
いやー、なんか
Geez, there are...
ウサギがいっぱい！
...so many rabbits!
ウサギから逃げるのだ！
Escape from the rabbits!
逃げるのだ！
Escape!
ちょちょっと、上げて。
Let me level up a bit.
このフレイム吸収が、シフト…
This flame absorb is shift...
なんか難しいよね、それ。
That seems kind of difficult.
そう、炎吸収シフト、シフトコントロール。
Yeah, flame absorb is shift, shift-control.
あ、なんか吸収してるわ。
Ah, it is absorbing.
帰ろう、えーっと。
Let's head back, let's see...
炎吸収、殴りながらできるか。
Can I absorb flames while attacking?
よいしょ。
All right.
あれ？どこ…あ、いたいたいた。
Oh? Where... ah, there it is.
きれいよね〜。
It's so pretty~
よいしょ。
Heigh-ho.
えーと、これでじゃあ帰って毛皮装備取りに行って…
Um, with this, let's head back and go grab the fur armor...
行くか、トードー。
Shall we go, Todou?
あ、空から…
Ah, from the sky...
じゃ、イナ達も取りに行く、毛皮。
Then let's go get some fur too.
行きますぜい。
Here we go.
よいしょ。
Alright.
ちょっと待ってね。
Wait a sec.
またなんか、ロードバグみたいになってる。
It's like a loading bug again.
うわ、可愛い。うさぎちゃんの赤ちゃんじゃん。
Wow, cute! It's a baby rabbit.
集会所が…集会所が見えないバグだ。
It's a bug where the gathering place is invisible.
建物見えないバグ。
A bug where buildings are invisible.
今日多いね。
There are a lot of them today.
なんかね、読み込みラグがすごい。
Yeah, the loading lag is crazy.
ふぅ。
Whew.
よいしょ。
Okay.
お、毛皮デイリー報酬。
Oh, fur daily reward.
え、パイロのエサって何入れとけばいいの？肉でいいの？
Eh, what should I put in for the Pyromane's food? Is meat fine?
焼き肉になるんだ、こいつ。 / そうですね。
It turns into cooked meat, this guy. / That's right.
焼き肉になるんだよね。可愛いけど。
It really cooks it, though it's cute.
よいしょ。
Up we go.
毛皮…ちょっと待ってね。
Fur... wait a sec.
さ、ユーティ。
Now, Yuti.
ユーティHP低いんだよね。
Yuti's HP is low.
低いので、いま絶対して、肉あげました。 / オッケー。
Since it's low, I just fed it some meat. / Okay.
毛皮装備。
Fur armor.
毛皮装備重たいから気をつけてね。 / マジ？
Fur armor is heavy, so be careful. / Really?
よいしょ。
Alright.
え、トードーってどこだっけ、場所？
Wait, where is Todou again?
トードーのダンジョンの場所が、どこだ？
Where is Todou's dungeon?
えっとね、わかるよ。 / 本当？
Um, I know where it is. / Really?
デモ洞窟の中はなんか探索できなかったから、ちょっとわからないかもしれないけど、入り口はわかる。
But we couldn't explore inside the cave, so I might not know the way, but I know the entrance.
オッケー、入り口さえわかれば。 / オッケー。
Okay, as long as we know the entrance. / Okay.
じゃあ、準備できてる？
Then, are you ready?
ユーティはもう現場まで行けばいいか。
Yuti can just go straight to the site.
うん。トードーは今毛皮取りに行ってるかな、毛皮。 / オッケー。
Yeah. Todou is probably going to get fur right now. / Okay.
私パイロ乗ってたら、まあ、行けるっちゃ行ける。
If I'm riding the Pyromane, well, I can make it.
何番…ちょっと待ってね。
Which number... wait a sec.
とね、じゃあ先移動してるから、そっち行ってもらったらわかりやすいかも。ワープ。
Well, we'll go ahead first, so it might be easier if you teleport there. Warp.
オッケー。
Okay.
え、どこワープだ？ / えっとね、10番かな。10番。
Uh, where is the warp? / Um, number 10, maybe. 10.
あ、10番！10番の洞窟。 / オッケー。
Ah, 10! Cave 10. / Okay.
洞窟、了解。 / トードーの洞窟。
The cave, got it. / Todou's cave.
大丈夫かこれ、死んだ？死んだ？あ、生きてる。
Is this okay? Did it die? Did it die? Ah, it's alive.
よいしょ。
Alright.
ちょっと仮拠点いっこ行ってからだ。 / うん。
Let me go to the temporary base first. / Yeah.
ほんならじゃあ、トードーの洞窟にテレポートしとこうかな。
Then I guess I'll teleport to Todou's cave.
もう入り口入って、中入ったけど、もう迷子になったし、迷子になったし、めちゃくちゃ酔ったし、もういいやって。
I already went in the entrance and got inside, but I got lost, got lost, got super motion sick, and thought, "whatever."
出てきてしまいました。
And I just came back out.
惨段や。 / 惨段や。
Terrible. / Terrible.
で、トードーの洞窟？ / うん。もう多分、方向音痴なんや。
And, Todou's cave? / Yeah. Probably because I have no sense of direction.
はにゃ。
Oh my.
え、革のベッド持ってったほうがええか？
Uh, should we bring sleeping bags?
ああ、まあ、一発でクリアできなさそうだったら、って感じかな。 / どちらでも。
Ah, well, if we think we can't clear it in one go, I guess. / Either way is fine.
せーい。
Hup.
4人分持って行こうか。 / よいしょ。
Let's bring enough for four. / Okay.
もはや、他人の寝袋でもいいか。
At this point, even someone else's sleeping bag is fine.
いや、4つ持ってくよ。
No, I'll bring four.
うい。
Got it.
いいな、トワがユーティ乗ってるからな、このユーティね。 / ユーティ？
Nice, since Towa is riding the Yuti, this Yuti, right? / Yuti?
いや、トワ様が名前つけたんでしょ？ / ユーティ。
Didn't Towa-sama name it? / Yuti.
トワがつけたの？ / 違う違う、なんかトワが…
Towa named it? / No no, Towa...
イナに「これなんかいい名前ある？」って言ったら「ユーティ」って言ったから。
Asked Ina, "Do you have any good names for this?" and since you said "Yuti"...
結構、結構うまくはまったよな。 / ユーティ。
It fit pretty well, didn't it? / Yuti.
この遊びで一番いい名前になった気がする。 / ユーティ？
I feel like it's the best name we've had in this playthrough. / Yuti?
ほんまか？
Really?
イナ、ご飯トワがあげとくから、持ってきちゃっていいよ。
Ina, Towa will feed it, so you can just bring it over.
あ、いいですか？
Oh, is it okay?
アイテム名常に表示するみたいなやつどこだっけ？
Where was the setting to always display item names?
オッケーです。
Got it.
なんか設定にあった気がする。それも。
I feel like that was in the settings too.
どこだっけ？
Where was it?
えーっと...
Let's see...
詳細か？
Under "Toggle Tooltips"?
詳細とかかな。
Maybe under "Toggle Tooltips"?
あ、詳細の左。一番左。
Ah, to the left of "Details." The far left.
左の、上から4番目。
The fourth one from the top on the left.
左の上から4番目？ 詳細の。
Fourth from the top on the left? In the details?
あ、ここか。ありがとう。
Ah, here? Thanks.
これだ。
This is it.
おっけ。
Okay.
ねこ... ねこ掴めない。なんでお前...
Cat... I can't grab the cat. Why are you...
追従、団体、これ。
Follow, group, this one.
まだ... まだかかるんだったら、鳥入れてくるわ。
If it's going to take a bit longer, I'll put my bird away.
あ、はい。
Ah, okay.
あれ？なんか、なってないな。ちょっと待って。
Huh? It's not working. Wait a second.
いけるかな？
Will it work?
アイテム名、常に表示...
Always display item names...
あ、なんかHボタン押してずっと出るやつってどれだったっけな？ あ、Qか？
Ah, what was the button to keep it toggled on instead of holding H? Ah, is it Q?
トグルになっちゃってんだよね、これ。
This is toggling it on and off.
結構カスタマイズしてたんだね。
You customized it quite a lot.
そう、めっちゃカスタマイズしてたの。これ常に出すやつ、ちょっと誰か教えて。
Yeah, I customized it a ton. Someone please tell me how to keep this displayed always.
「常に出す」を何を出すんだ？それ知らないやつかも。
Always display what? I might not know that one.
え、マジ？この数値。
Really? These numbers.
数値？
Numbers?
あの、数値見えるじゃん。H押すとさ。
You know, you can see the stats when you press H.
うん。
Yeah.
ずっと出していたんだよね、私。
I used to have them displayed constantly.
あ、そうんだ。
Ah, really?
詳細だったかな？
Was it "Toggle Tooltips"?
HUDかな？HUDの表示ってやつかな？
Maybe HUD? The setting for HUD display?
あ、それだ。
Ah, that's it.
あ、これだ。ありがとう。
Ah, this is it. Thanks.
これめっちゃ不便なんだよな。
This is so inconvenient without it.
お帰り。
Welcome back.
はい、ありがとう。出た。
Yes, thank you. It appeared.
オッケー。いけるか？
Okay. Ready to go?
はい、そっち行きます。
Yes, heading over there.
あいよ。
Alright.
ユーティだけもらうわ。
I'll just take the Yuty.
あ、はい！えーっと...
Ah, yes! Let's see...
これ入り口どここれ？
Where is the entrance to this?
どっこ？テレポート。
Where? Teleport.
そうね。テレポートでね、10番のテレポート。
That's right. Teleport to number 10.
ナンバー10にいますわ。
We are at number 10.
ナンバー10。
Number 10.
ナンバー10にみんなおいで。
Everyone come to number 10.
ダーキスンさんに乗りたいのに、あいつ壁の向こうに行っているから。
I want to ride Dark-san, but he's gone over to the other side of the wall.
こっち来てくんない？
Can you come over here?
なんか落としてんな、アイツ。
He's dropping something.
ゴミ落としてる。ゴミ落としてる。
Dropping trash. Dropping trash.
ポロポロポロポロ。
Plop plop plop plop.
これでも閉めなきゃいけないんだよね。
We still have to close this, right?
よいしょ。
Heave-ho.
おかゆ先輩ずっといるなぁと思った。
I thought Okayu-senpai was always here.
そう。ボクいるよー。ボクいるよー。
That's right. I'm here! I'm here!
はっ！
Ah!
先輩！？
Senpai!?
あら。ボクこんなに、こんなにちっちゃくなっちゃった。
Oh, dear. I've become so, so tiny.
ちっちゃい！
Tiny!
かわいい。
Cute.
こんなになっちゃったんだ。
I've shrunk so much.
えーっと、ユーティ。はい。
Let's see, Yuty. Here.
おお、ありがとう。
Oh, thank you.
じゃ, これ使いますね。
Then, I'll use this.
あっちのユーティよろしくおねがいします。
Please take care of that Yuty over there.
大丈夫よ。
It'll be fine.
生肉が大好きです。
He loves raw meat.
あ、降りない。
Ah, she won't get off.
降りたくないの？
Don't want to get off?
降りないの？
You're not getting off?
あ, この下だ。ここかな？
Ah, it's down here. Is it here?
あ、そうそうそうそう。
Ah, yes yes yes yes.
なんかここら辺だった。
It was somewhere around here.
怖い。ホワイト。
Scary. White.
え、これ下、下、下。ここ、ここ。
Eh, down here, down, down. Here, here.
白上見えない？飛んでます、今。
Can't you see Shirakami? I'm flying right now.
あの、テレポートの目の前やで。
Right in front of the teleporter.
え、目の前？
Eh, in front?
うん、目の前やで。
Yeah, right in front.
あ、こっちだ。お、白い。
Ah, this way. Oh, it's white.
ここだ。
It's here.
あ、じゃあやっぱり入り口違ったんだ。
Ah, so the entrance really was different.
トワ様は、ドッコンに行った？ですかね？
Did Towa-sama go to Doccon?
ここじゃないか。あ、だめだわ。
Is it not here? Ah, it's no good.
え、おじゃ、テレポート戻っといで。
Eh, well then, head back to the teleporter.
はい、テレポート。
Yes, teleporter.
はい、こっち。こっち、こっち。
Yep, over here. This way, this way.
こっち、こっち。ここの割れ目の下。
This way, this way. Under this crevice.
下。
Down.
え、寒そう。
Ugh, looks freezing.
はい、じゃ、ここから、多分、もうプテラ使えないんじゃないっけ？
Alright, from here on, we probably can't use Pteranodons anymore, right?
いける、いける。
We can, we can.
途中までいける。
You can go partway.
よし、そしたら、ほなじゃあ行ってみるか。
Alright, then shall we try going in?
俺、マップ一応貼ったぞ。
I posted the map just in case.
あ、そうして。マップ。
Ah, do that. The map.
おじゃ、右？左？
Well then, right? Left?
左じゃね？
Isn't it left?
いや、どうだ？
Or is it?
左行くか、じゃあ。
Let's go left then.
ボス前までは飛べるらしい。
Apparently we can fly up until the boss.
オッケーオッケー。
Okay, okay.
へえ。
I see.
こっちでしょ？
This way, right?
こっちかな？
Is it this way?
こっちかな。お、なんかでもぽい。続いてる続いてる、一本道。
Is it this way? Oh, but this looks like it. It keeps going, a single path.
お、いや、ここじゃないでした。なんかこれ違う出口...これトワが入ったとこか？もしや。
Oh, wait, it wasn't here. This is a different exit... Is this where Towa entered, maybe?
あ、オッケー。あ、なるほどね、出口。
Ah, okay. Ah, I see, the exit.
二個あるんだ。 / うん。 / 出口でした。
There are two. / Yeah. / It was an exit.
戻りやしょう。
Let's head back.
うぃー。
Okay.
湖通り抜けてなんか右からぐるっと回る感じっぽいぞ。
It looks like we go through the lake and loop around from the right.
おっきー。
Okay.
とりあえず一旦プテラのスタミナを回復します。
For now, I'll recover my Pteranodon's stamina.
お荷物持とうか？大丈夫？
Should I carry your things? Are you okay?
なんか... あ、そっか。ギリースーツも入れてるからかな？
Like... Ah, right. Maybe it's because I have the ghillie suit in there?
あ、ちなみに、寝袋置きますか？持ってきたけど。
Ah, by the way, should we place a sleeping bag? I brought one.
あ、確かに。置いとく？
Ah, true. Should we place it?
置いててもいいかもよ。 / ここに一回ぽぽって置いて。
It might be good to leave one. / Let's just plop one down here.
使わないかもしれないしね。 / じゃあ、私が置けばいいのか、これ。
We might not use it though. / Okay, so I should just place it here?
じゃあ、トワのアルゲンのガジェットとギリースーツ入れちゃう。
Then I'll put Towa's Argent's saddle and ghillie suit in.
うん、いいよいいよ。 / いいよ。
Yeah, sure, go ahead. / Okay.
前に熊いるから気をつけてね。 / あ、本当だ。
There's a bear up ahead, so be careful. / Ah, true.
はい、置きました。 / はい。
Okay, I placed it. / Okay.
よし。 / もうマジわからねえ。 / よし、じゃあ、こっち行こう、真っ直ぐ。
Alright. / I seriously have no idea anymore. / Okay, let's go this way, straight ahead.
熊に気をつけて。
Watch out for the bear.
これが右、左、どっち？左行ってみるか？一旦。
Is this right or left? Shall we try left for now?
水、水ある方？
The water, the side with water?
あ、水あるの、ここだ、こっちだ。
Ah, the water is here, this way.
ここを、右からぐるっと？ / 右からぐるーかな？
Loop around from the right here? / Loop around from the right, maybe?
一旦、右行ってみる？ / ここ、行き止まりっぽくないけど。どうなんだろう？
Should we try right for now? / This doesn't look like a dead end, but who knows?
あら、出ちゃったかも。じゃあ左か。
Oh, we might have gone outside. Left it is, then.
ちなみに、ワンちゃんが熊に襲われておりますが、大丈夫でしょうか？
By the way, the dog is being attacked by a bear, will it be okay?
ワンちゃん？ / トワの犬だ！
Dog? / It's Towa's dog!
あれ？トワの犬って... / ワンちゃんってさ、勝手になんかどうにこうにワープしてくれるんじゃないの？
Wait, Towa's dog... / Don't dogs usually warp to you somehow?
いや、敵対しちゃったら、無理やで。 / あ。
No, if they get targeted, they can't. / Ah.
ワンちゃん！ / あ、でも熊弱いから大丈夫。
Doggy! / Ah, but the bear is weak, so it's fine.
犬、大丈夫？
Is the dog okay?
あれ、犬は？ / 犬どっか行った。
Wait, where is the dog? / The dog went somewhere.
ま、大丈夫でしょう。 / 大丈夫でしょう？
Well, it'll probably be fine. / It'll be fine?
大丈夫か？ / なんか、ついてくるらしい。
Is it really okay? / Apparently it'll follow.
ほな大丈夫。 / ほな、大丈夫。 / 帰るって。
Then it's fine. / Then it's fine. / It's heading back.
これ、ラビリンスとかじゃないの、これ？違うか。
Isn't this like a labyrinth? No?
え、でも、一応道繋がってるよ、左。 / じゃあ、こっち行こう。
Well, the path does connect on the left. / Then let's go this way.
なに、あのムカデのとこ。怖。
What is that centipede place? Scary.
うわ、うわ、うわ。ひんやりする。
Whoa, whoa, whoa. It's chilly.
え、外に出ちゃったかも、ここも。 / お？
Eh, we might have ended up outside here too. / Oh?
なんか、トワが見つけたトコ、一回行ってもらってもいい？ / あ、オッケーオッケー。じゃあ、トワ先行して。
Can we go to the place Towa found once? / Ah, okay, okay. Then Towa, lead the way.
一回、ちょっと外出して、外に出てもらっていい？ / あ、じゃあ寝袋回収してこないと。
Could you go outside for a bit? / Ah, then I need to go retrieve the sleeping bag.
でも、多分洞窟には変わりないから、大丈夫や。 / あ、そっか、オッケーオッケー。
But it's still a cave anyway, so it's fine. / Ah, I see. Okay, okay.
えっとね、こっち側の...
Let's see... On this side...
多分...
Probably...
マンモス。 / マンモス。 / マンモス。
Mammoth. / Mammoths. / Mammoths.
こっちの... あ、ここが原油の場所です。
This way... Ah, this is the oil location.
おお、本当だ、原油。
Oh, you're right, oil.
なんかね、なんかロード画面、ロード入るんだよね、やっぱり。
Like, you know, the loading screen... it really does trigger a load.
洞窟、ちゃんと。
For the cave, properly.
でもなんか、場所が結構むずくて。
But the location is quite tricky.
ただの洞穴だったのか、あそこじゃ。ね？寝床だった、熊の。 / 熊の。でも、そこと繋がるんだよね。
Was that place just a simple hollow? Right? A bear's den. / A bear's. But it connects to there.
ほうほうほう。
I see, I see.
なんかここら辺だった気がする。ピンさして。 / この辺の、洞窟か。
I feel like it was around here. Let me place a pin. / A cave around here?
うん、ここら辺の洞窟どこかに...
Yeah, somewhere around here there's a cave...
おお？
Oh?
なんか木の間にあったんだよな。
It was between some trees.
これか？あ、違うか。
Is it this? Ah, no, maybe not.
下の方か？
Is it further down?
入り口二つあって、さっきの空洞からと正式な入り口があるらしい。 / へえ。
Apparently there are two entrances: the hollow from earlier, and an official entrance. / Oh really?
なるほど。 / うん。
I see. / Yeah.
じゃ、戻るか。 / そうね。さっきの空洞から行けるんだったら、行こうか。
Then shall we head back? / Right. If we can go through that hollow from earlier, let's go.
さっきの空洞から行けるんだったら。
If we can go from that hollow...
戻ろう。 / 確かここら辺にあった気がするんだよな。
Let's head back. / I'm pretty sure it was around here.
あった、これだ、これだ。ここ、ここ。 / あ、これだ。これこれ。 / オッケー。
There it is! This is it! Right here. / Ah, this is it. This one. / Okay.
ここ、これだ、これだ。これか？ / おお、すごい。洞窟だ。
Here, this is it. This one? / Oh, awesome. It's a cave.
この下？ / おお。 / おお、ガチ洞窟。
Under here? / Oh. / Oh, a real cave.
お？ / ああ、トワの、トワの犬がいた。トワの犬だ、これ。
Oh? / Ah, Towa's... Towa's dog was here. This is Towa's dog.
あ、トワ。 / 本当にどこかでぴょんぴょんしてますね。
Ah, Towa. / It's really jumping around somewhere.
あ、じゃあ、こっから行くか。 / うん。
Ah, then should we go from here? / Yeah.
はい。 / ういー。
Okay. / Whew.
おお、ひんやり。ひんやり。おお。 / こっからだったら、右に沿えばいいのかな？
Oh, it's chilly. Chilly. Oh... / If we go from here, should we just hug the right?
クレート、取らなければ
We have to get the crates.
取らなければ、もう多分右ずっと行って、ぐるっと。
If we do, we should probably keep going right and loop around.
あ、そう。
Ah, I see.
まだまっすぐか？
Is it still straight ahead?
うん。
Yeah.
オッケー。
Okay.
ちょっと羽休め。
Resting my wings for a bit.
ふぅ。あ、クレートある。
Phew. Oh, there's a crate.
クレートある？
Is there?
やった。黄色いクレート。
Nice, a yellow crate.
革のなんか、ちょっと革装備のいいやつと...
Some decent hide armor, and...
あ、テラバードのサドルね。
Ah, a Terror Bird saddle.
クマいます。
There's a bear.
クマちゃん？あ、オッケー。
A bear? Ah, okay.
いけます。
We can go.
はい、どうぞ。
Go ahead.
このまま右にまっすぐかな？
Do we keep going straight to the right?
うん。
Yeah.
右に沿う感じではあるね。
It feels like we follow the right wall.
オッケー。
Okay.
なんかむずいから一旦遠回りでもいい。
It's tricky, so looping around is fine too.
あ、なんか狭いとこがある。
Oh, there's a narrow path here.
ココの先かい？もしかして。
Is it past here, maybe?
ああ。
Ah.
すごい狭い、ここ。
It's really narrow here.
狭いね。
It is narrow.
でもこの先っぽいよね。
But it seems like it's past here, right?
ね。
Yeah.
ここで一旦下ろすか。
Should we land here for a bit?
オッケー。
Okay.
遠くない？ここから徒歩かな？
Isn't it far? Do we walk from here?
ここじゃない？あ、ここじゃないらしい。
Isn't it here? Oh, apparently not here.
ここじゃないの？
It's not here?
ここじゃない、左だって左。
Not here, they said to the left.
ここじゃないらしい。
Apparently not here.
左だった気がするって。
I feel like they said left.
ほんまか？
Really?
あー、引っかかっちゃったね。
Ah, I got stuck, I got stuck.
左奥にアーティファクトじゃなくて、なんか、素材がある、素材っていうか...
In the back left, not the artifact, but some materials...
クレートがあればいい、と。
...or rather, as long as there's a crate.
あ、あった、ここにクレートが。ということは、左上だから...
Ah, there was a crate here. Which means, since it's top left...
フブちゃんに付いていくか。
Should I follow Fubu-chan?
うん。
Yeah.
あ、じゃ、クレートがある。
Ah, then there is a crate.
へえ。
Oh.
じゃあ、こっちか。
Then, this way?
メガテリウムのサドルだ。
Megatherium saddle.
あれ？なんか特に...
Huh? There's nothing really...
あれ？
Huh?
なんか、ここ、ここ、なんか動画で見たことがあるかも。
I might have seen this place in a video.
この先？じゃあ、そっち。
Past here? Okay, that way.
飛べないの？
Can we not fly?
こっちか。この先に、多分飛べないと思う。
This way? Past here, I don't think we can fly.
あ、アイスクイーン。あ、バイバブル。
Ah, Ice Queen... Ah, bye-bye bubble.
あ、本当だ。
Ah, indeed.
あ、バイバブル。
Ah, bye-bye bubble.
じゃあ、この先なんだな。
So it's past here.
まあ、飛べるとこまで飛んでみるか。じゃあ。
Well, let's fly as far as we can then.
うん。
Yeah.
ここまで。ここ、ここ、ここまでだ。ここまで。
Up to here. This is the limit.
オッケー。
Okay.
じゃあ...
Then...
本当だ。
It really is.
じゃあ、しまって。
Then let's put it away.
しまって、行こうかな。
Put it away and let's go.
しまって。
Put it away...
トワいないからあれだよね。
Towa isn't here, so we do that, right?
うん、ユティラ乗っちゃおう。
Yeah, let's ride the Yuty.
うん。
Yeah.
よいしょ。ユティ。
Okay. Yuty.
なんかインフォメーション来てるけど、どうなんでしょう？
We got some information, but what is it?
なんか、別のチームが...
It says another team is...
戦ってたら、待ってくださいって。
...if they're fighting, please wait.
はい。まあ、行かないと分かんないよね。
Yes. Well, we won't know until we go.
そうだね。よし、行ってみよう。
Right. Alright, let's go check.
行ってみよう。
Let's go.
ええと...
Let's see...
急にBGM。
Sudden background music.
どうした？
What happened?
重い！すいません、ちょっと待ってください。
Heavy! Sorry, please wait a moment.
ちょっと待ってね。
Hold on a second.
預かっといてほしい。
I need you to hold onto this.
あ、待って。ここも通れないや。
Ah, wait. We can't pass here either.
あ、じゃあ、乗らなくていっか、まだ。
Ah, then we don't need to ride yet, right?
うん、まだ乗らなくていいや。
Yeah, we don't need to ride yet.
オッケー。
Okay.
ニャン。しまっていい気がする。
Meow. I think we can put it away.
ティラノの卵？
Rex egg?
なんでこんなに重いんだ、私。
Why am I so heavy?
石とか持ってるんじゃない？
Aren't you carrying stones or something?
そうかもですね。お肉。
Maybe. Meat.
これ、すき間じゃない？これ。
Isn't this a gap?
ね。一人、一人通るくらいの。しゃがんで行くしかないかも。
Yeah, about wide enough for one person. We might have to crouch.
え、これしゃがんで行けてる？
Wait, am I crouching through this?
しゃがむんだ。
You have to crouch.
うん。一人称視点にしたら行けるかも。
Yeah. It might work if you switch to first-person view.
あ、行けた、行けた、行けた。
Ah, I made it, made it.
あ、ちょっと待ってね、レフトコントロール。
Ah, wait a second, left control.
え、どう行くんですか？
Wait, how do we go?
コントロール。あ、コントロール。オッケー、オッケー。
Control. Ah, control. Okay, okay.
狭い。
It's narrow.
今行きます。
Coming now.
よいしょ。
Phew.
戦う時スタックに気をつけよう、かい？
Be careful not to get stuck during fights, okay?
怖い。
Scary.
トワ様の、え、ここ、ここだよね、入れるの？
Towa-sama's... wait, we can enter here, right?
そうだよ、しゃがんで。
Yeah, just crouch.
トワ様のに引っかかってるかもしれん。
I might be getting stuck on Towa-sama's.
トワの、なんか、勝手にね、ぷよんて。
Towa's character just bounces around on its own.
大丈夫、オッケー。
It's fine, okay.
あ、今のも行った方がいいんですかね？
Ah, should we go now?
あ、間違えた、間違えた、間違えた。何でなっちゃったんだ？
Ah, my mistake, my mistake. Why did that happen?
きれいよ。
Beautiful.
よいしょ、きれいよね。オッケー。
Phew, it is beautiful. Okay.
で、まだまだ先だね。
And we still have a long way to go.
おう。
Yeah.
えー、怖い。
Oh, scary.
あ、怖いよ。
Ah, it's scary.
お前先行けや。
You go first.
いや、行けや。え、これどっち？
No, you go first. Wait, which way?
どっち？どっち？
Which way? Which way?
これ多分
This is probably...
右じゃね？
Isn't it right?
右か
Right?
右か左か
Right or left?
右か、左か？
右か？
Right?
あ、なんか、あ、な、なんだよ！
Ah, wh- what is that?!
え？
Eh?
あららら
Oh my, oh my.
穴ある、これ
There's a hole here.
え、これ大丈夫なの？
Eh, is this okay?
何これ？
What is this?
え、怖っ！
Eh, scary!
これ何これ？
What is this, what is this?
怖いんだけど、これ
This is scary.
左にクレートがあるらしいからちょっと見てくる
There's supposedly a crate on the left, so I'll check.
はーい
Okay.
でも正解は右ってことでしょ、これ多分
But the correct way is right, probably.
これ、どうやって降りるの？
How do we get down this?
穴に落ちるんじゃないかな？
Don't we fall down the hole?
シュウって
Like, sliding down.
落ちるよね、これ
We fall, right?
ここ、ここ行ったら死ぬって
They say if we go here, we'll die.
え、なんか、うんこ降ってきたんだけど、上から
Eh, some poop fell from above.
は？
Huh?
うんこ降ってきた
Poop fell.
トワのうんこじゃない、だってうんこって上から降ってきたんだけど
It's not Towa's poop, because it fell from above.
デスワームのうんこが次々と...
Deathworm's poop is falling one after another...
お前かよ！
It was you!
お前らうんこ...
You guys, poop...
どんな、どんな僻地だよ！
What kind of remote place is this!
ちょっと広すぎるわ、帰ろう
It's a bit too wide, let's go back.
落としたよね、落としたんだけど。やめて、トワの頭の上に。
You dropped it, right? Stop doing that on Towa's head.
3個くらい落としてくんだけど
You dropped like three of them.
これいいよな
This is good.
びっくりしたわ、うんこ
That startled me, the poop.
ゲームマスターのうんこ落ちすぎだ
The Game Master's poop is falling too much.
本当だよ
Seriously.
あれ穴、あいてるんじゃないですか？
Isn't there a hole open there?
どんだけ快便なんだ
Talk about healthy bowel movements.
近くになんかなかったから帰ってきた、行こう
There was nothing nearby, so I came back. Let's go.
はーい
Okay.
おっけー
本当に降りるんですか？あそこ
Are we really going down there?
本当にその穴なのかな？
Is it really that hole?
みんな良いの？降りて良い？
Is everyone ready? Can we go down?
良いですよ
It's fine.
ボディーから行くよ
Going body first.
行くよ
Going.
はい
Yes.
え、でもさ、ここ引っかかるの嫌だしさ、ちょっと行くわ、私
Eh, but I don't want to get stuck here, so I'll go first.
お、マジか
Oh, really?
様子見てきて
Go check it out.
お、すげえ
Oh, amazing.
良いよ、良いよ
Good, good.
ここまで、ここまで行ける、ここまで
You can go up to here, up to here.
滑っていかないといけない感じなんだ、なるほど
So you have to slide down, I see.
ちょっと、ちょっとずつね
Little by little.
あ、多分この先にはあるね。この先にまたあります、あります、あります
Ah, probably up ahead. There's more up ahead.
待って、でも正解は左って言ってる人もいるんだけど、え？
Wait, but some people are saying the correct way is left. Eh?
まあ、一回進んでみようよ、じゃあ
Well, let's move forward once then.
え？
Eh?
もう登れないから
We can't climb back up anyway.
私登れないから、もう、どっちみち
I can't climb back up anyway, either way.
もう行こうよ、もう
Let's just go.
え？
Eh?
え、ですか？
Really?
いいよ、いいよ、ワサップ、ワサップ。絶対ワサップだよ、それ
It's fine. What's up? That's definitely what's up.
ワサップか？
What's up?
ワサップだよ
What's up.
えー？
Eh?
もう行くしかないよな、もう戻れないから
We have no choice but to go forward, we can't go back.
戻れないよな
We can't go back.
もう戻れない
No going back.
出しとく？出しとかない？大丈夫？出しとく？
Should we bring them out? Or not? Is it okay? Should we bring them out?
ここら辺じゃね？
Isn't it around here?
え、ここら辺なんじゃん？
Eh, it is around here, right?
これどうやって出てくるの？怖いんだけど。急にもるもるもるって出てくるの？
How does it come out? This is scary. Does it suddenly pop out?
あの、え？いない
Um, eh? It's not here.
多分こっちにまだ道がある
There's probably still a path this way.
え？
Eh?
え、怖い
Eh, scary.
みんな乗ら、乗らなくて大丈夫？乗れるけど、一応
Is everyone okay not riding? We can ride, just in case.
回ってきたかも
Yeah, wait? We might have just come back to the left path.
本当？
Really?
ん？
Hm?
あ、クレートがそっちだったのかな？本当は
Ah, maybe the crate was actually that way?
なんかここあるかな？
Is there something here?
怖いよ
Scary.
あ、こっちじゃないな
Ah, it's not this way.
だめだ、もう方向転換無理だ、あ、あ、あった
No use, I can't turn around anymore. Ah, there it is.
あ、左行きます？じゃあ左行こう、左行こう
Ah, going left? Let's go left then.
左か
Left?
おっけー
Okay.
もうフブちゃんについていく、もう本当に
I'll just follow Fubu-chan, honestly.
多分こっち
Probably this way.
よいしょ
Heave-ho.
あー
Ah.
うわ、ちょうど！
Whoa, perfect timing!
あ、ちょうどね
Ah, perfect.
あ、でも3分待てば良い
Ah, but we just have to wait 3 minutes.
ちょうどなんか場所が
Just the right place.
そうだね、場所探してるぐらいで
Yeah, just enough to look for a place.
そうだね、もう一回さっきの
Right, let's go back to that place from earlier.
トワちゃんどこ行った？
Towa-chan, where did you go?
あのー、左ですか？みんな
Um, are you all on the left?
あ、ここか
Ah, here?
左かな、あ、いたいたいた
Left maybe? Ah, found you, found you.
こっち、こっち
This way, this way.
よいしょ、よいしょ
Yoisho, yoisho.
あれが終わって
Once that ends,
3分待ったら沸くから
and we wait 3 minutes, it'll spawn.
あ、ここアーティファクトだ。ここアーティファクトだね
Ah, the artifact is here. The artifact is here.
アーティファクト、おっけー
Artifact, okay.
よく覚えてるな、すげえな
You remember that well, amazing.
いいよ
You're welcome.
あ、あ、でも
Ah, ah, but
逆に雑魚倒してくれてたのかな？これ道中
Did they defeat the small enemies for us on the way?
あ、そういうこと？
Ah, is that so?
全然敵がだっていないもん
Since there are no enemies at all.
美味しい
Nice.
ザルすぎるだろ、だって普通に
That's way too loose, normally.
アロサウルスの...
Allosaurus's...
こっち左だっけ？
Was it left here?
うん
Yeah.
あ
Ah.
ぽい？こっち左か？
Is it? Left here?
さっきこっち右
Earlier it was right here.
やばい、水がない、水が
Oh no, there's no water, no water.
わかる
I feel you.
わかる、水ないんだよな
I know, there's no water.
水ないんだな
No water, huh.
敵掃除してくれてるっぽいな
Seems like they cleared out the enemies for us.
私、持ってますよ、水
I have some water.
水が欲しい
I want some water.
1個だけ？
Just one?
えっと、2つ
Um, two.
いいの？大丈夫？
Is it okay? Are you sure?
あ、水入れにいってくる
Ah, I'll go fill it with water.
あ、私のもどうぞ
Ah, please take mine too.
あ、ここあれだ多分
Ah, this is probably it.
シオンが、日の裏にあるんじゃね？って言ってたとこだ、繋がる
The place where Shion said, "Isn't it behind the sun?" It connects.
え、ありがとう、いなちゃん
Eh, thank you, Ina-chan.
はい
Yes.
いなちゃん
Ina-chan.
いなちゃん、神、いなちゃん、神
Ina-chan is a god! Ina-chan is a god!
滝壺から登ったところって何だ？
What is "the place climbed from the waterfall basin"?
よいしょ
Heave-ho.
え？
Eh?
カルノにやられてる
Killed by a Carnotaurus.
本当だ
Indeed.
カルノ
Carnotaurus.
フブちゃんどこ行った？
Fubu-chan, where did you go?
右？
Right?
滝あった、滝
There's a waterfall, waterfall.
あ、滝あった？
Ah, there's a waterfall?
うん
Yeah.
滝発見した、水飲みたいならそこ行ける
Found a waterfall, if you want water you can go there.
あ、１回水筒ぐびぐびしよう。
Ah, let's chug some water first.
あ、なんか、こっち先？
Oh, is it this way first?
まっすぐ行ったら、滝がある。
If we keep going straight, there's a waterfall.
この先が、ここがたぶんボス前なのかな？
Ahead... is this probably in front of the boss room?
インフォが、インフォ消えちゃう。
The info... the info is disappearing.
Waterfall... What's waterfall in Japanese?
え、滝あるこれ？
Wait, is there a waterfall?
正面もっと行ったら、ここにね、滝があるんだよね。
If you go further straight, there's a waterfall here.
あ、結構進むのか。
Ah, we have to go pretty far.
滝、あ、滝。水。
Waterfall... Ah, waterfall. Water.
あ、人間しか、なんか行けない。
Ah, only humans can pass...
行けない、行けない！ちょっと待って！
We can't pass! Wait, wait, wait!
じゃあ、ここ？
So, is it here?
はい、ここ。ここで待ちます。
Yes, here. We wait here for 3 minutes.
お、じゃあ、ここで待っとくか。
Oh, then we'll wait here.
ちょうどいい、ちょうどいい。
Perfect timing.
うんこ。これ、誰の？
Poop. Whose is this?
アミちゃんじゃない？神様？
Isn't it Ami-chan's? Or God's?
神様じゃない？
Isn't it God's?
うんこ人狼始まる。
The poop werewolf game begins.
ねえ、人狼って英語でなんて言うの？
Hey, what do you call "Werewolf" in English?
人狼？
Werewolf?
人狼、なんかアモングアスみたいな、なんて言うんだろう？
Yeah, like Among Us... how do you say it?
Werewolf!
ウェアウルフ？
Werewolf?
ウェアウルフってこと？
As in werewolf?
あーー！なるほどね！
Ah! I see!
よいしょ。プープー。プープー。
Up we go. Poop-poop, poop-poop.
ウェアウルフ？
Werewolf?
ウェアウルフのうんちってこと？
Does that mean werewolf poop?
いや、これ、誰かのうんこ。
No. This is someone's... someone's poop.
そう、誰のうんこか。３人の中。
Yes, whose poop... whose poop is it, out of the three of us?
プープーや。
It's poop-poop.
よいしょ。あ、倒したってことは？
Up we go. Ah. Oh, since they defeated it, that means?
え、早いな。じゃあ、こっから3分だ。
Eh, that was fast. So, 3 minutes from now.
出る場所で待っててもいいのかな？
But is it okay to wait where it spawns?
3分後に再生成。はい。
Respawns in 3 minutes. Okay.
え、この先にもう出るの？
Eh, does it spawn just ahead of here?
あ、そうなんだ。じゃあ、ここで、あれか、3分待てばいいのか。
Ah, I see. Then, we can just wait 3 minutes here.
たぶん。おっけー。
Probably. Okay.
ゲーム的にはあいやウェアウルフらしい。
Game-wise, it's apparently... actually, werewolf.
うーん、あいやウェアウルフ。
Hmm, actually werewolf.
で、これ終わったら、一旦、みんなで集合して、あれする？丸秘？
And once this is done, should we all gather together and do that? The secret thing?
はい。かな。おっけー。
Yes, I think so. Okay.
3分分かんないよ。
I don't know when the 3 minutes is up.
19分、21分...
19 minutes, 21 minutes...
になる。8時21分に湧くかな。
It will spawn at 8:21, then.
本当、ショットガンの設計図手に入るのもいい。ね。
It's really great that we can get shotgun blueprints here too. Yeah.
ダイオドンも助かる。
Daeodons are a big help too.
ブロントサウルスを倒すが、あと2匹なんだよね。
We only need to defeat two more Brontosauruses.
トライブテイムは、あと10匹。
Ah, for tribe tames, we have 10 left.
10匹か。いけそうな気もするな。ね。
Ten? That feels doable. Yeah.
ニードルズパック。
Needles pack.
はい。上で、アイスワームクイーンを倒しました。
Yes. Up there, we defeated the Iceworm Queen.
これ、トワ様の犬、しまえないの？
Wait, Towa-sama, can't you put away your dog?
多分、ワープしてくるから、大丈夫。
It'll probably warp, so it should be fine.
コンパニオンだったら大丈夫。あ、コンパニオンか。おっけー。
If it's a companion, it's fine. Ah, companion. Okay.
一応、情報だけ共有しといたよ。
For now, I shared the info.
助かる。
Thank you.
ヒットポイント足りるかな、私のやつ。
Will my HP be enough?
最悪だめだったら、あれ出すわ、テリジノ。
Worst case scenario, I'll bring out the Therizinosaurus.
あ、誰かさ、ロケラン作ってくれてたじゃん。
Oh, what was it... someone crafted rocket launchers for us, right?
ロケラン3本にして、あとロケランの弾もちょっと作っといたから。
I made three rocket launchers and crafted some ammo too.
助かる。ラヴァさんをやるためにね。
That helps! To deal with the Lava Golem.
まぁ、3人ぐらいだったら、いけんのかな？
Well, can we do it with just three people?
道中で死ななければ、って感じかな。
As long as we don't die on the way, I think.
あの、フックショット使ってもらわなきゃいけないから。
Because we'll have to use grappling hooks.
そうそうそう。
Right, right, right.
なんか湖ビリビリになってるけど、これ。
The lake seems to be buzzing with electricity, though.
あ、もう湧いた？
Ah, did it spawn already?
湧いてる？
Is it spawning?
3分経った？
Has it been 3 minutes?
ユーティの体力増やしとこうかな。でかい！
Maybe I'll increase Yuty's health. Woah, it's huge!
でかい、でかい。そろそろいけそう。
It's huge, it's huge. We should be able to go soon.
およ。ほんだら、くぐるかい？
Oh. Shall we go through then?
くぐる？
Go through?
おっけー。びちゃ、溺れる、溺れる！
Okay. Splash... Ah, I'm drowning, I'm drowning!
陸に上がればいいのかな？
Should we just get on land?
ちょっと遅れてます。
I'm lagging a bit behind.
はい
Yes.
はい、向かいます
Okay, I'm heading over.
うわ、どっちだ？
Whoa, which way is it?
あ？
Ah?
こっち？
This way?
あ、え？
Ah, wait...
やってるね、今。
They're doing it right now.
まじか。1個前の人がいたのかな？
Seriously? Maybe there was someone right before us?
あ、アーティファクト発見！
Ah, found an artifact!
あいよ。
Got it.
いや、クレートだった。
No, it was a loot crate.
あいよ。えっと...
Got it. Let's see...
お、革のブーツと、お、至高の毛皮。
Oh, leather boots and... oh, Ascendant fur.
おおー。
Ooh.
ないすー。
Nice.
えっと、職人...
Let's see, Journeyman...
え、これじゃあもう終わりか？
Wait, is this the end of it?
ここの先とか？
Maybe further ahead?
そうだね。
Yeah.
右側かな？右側。
Maybe to the right? The right side.
おけー。
Okay.
うん。
Yeah.
まだもうちょい奥っぽい。
Seems like it's a bit further inside.
よいしょ。
Up we go.
この先かな？あ、これだ！これだ！
Is it ahead? Ah, this is it! This is it!
あー、なんか。
Ah, looks like...
なんか結界張られてるわ。
They have some kind of barrier set up.
あ、じゃあここか。
Ah, so it's here.
ここだ！
It's here!
じゃあ待っとくか。
Let's wait here then.
おおー。
Ooh.
お？おおー。
Oh? Ooh.
あ、これ？これね。
Ah, this? This one, right?
ここで待ってたらいいかも。
Maybe we should wait here.
はーい。
Okay.
おけ。ちょっと水の上...
Okay. I'll get out of the water...
唐突に湧き出したら怖いからここいとこ。
I'll stay here because it'd be scary if they suddenly spawned.
同感、同感。気持ち的にちょっと嫌だよね。
Agreed, agreed. Psychologically, it feels a bit bad.
陸にいたい。
I want to stay on land.
陸にいたい。あはは。
I want to stay on land. Haha.
本当に何回もごめんね。本当にすぐ一緒に...
I'm so sorry for leaving so many times. I'll be right back...
どうぞ。いってらっしゃい。
Go ahead. See you!
はい。
Yes.
よいしょ。
Up we go.
これなんだ？あ、メガテリウムね。
What's this? Ah, a Megatherium.
じゃあ、この人たちが倒そうが死のうが、次うちらってこと？
So, whether they beat it or die, we are next?
多分、うん。
Probably, yeah.
おけー。
Okay.
よいしょ。
Up we go.
ここからもう乗れるのかな？
Can we ride from here already?
よいしょ。
Up we go.
お腹よ。
My stomach...
お腹、胃がめっちゃ下がってるけど。
My hunger is dropping quite a lot, though.
大丈夫かい？
Are you okay?
お腹いっぱいだし...
I'm full, and...
あ、討伐、再挑戦可能、あ、まだか、でも。
Ah, defeat... "can be challenged again in..." Ah, not yet, though.
3分後。
In 3 minutes.
あ、寒くて...
Ah, because it's cold...
寒くて？
Because it's cold?
あ、毛皮装備着てる？
Ah, are you wearing fur gear?
毛皮装備着てねえ。
I'm not wearing fur gear.
着てない！
You're not?!
着てないんかい！
You're not wearing it?!
ちょっとギリー、ギリー...
Just a ghillie, ghillie...
ギリースーツ。ギリースーツ。
Ghillie suit. Ghillie suit.
ギリースーツは寒いね。
A ghillie suit is cold, yeah.
あ、ベール消えたね。
Ah, the barrier disappeared.
ベール消えたから行っていいのか？
The barrier disappeared, so is it okay to go?
どうなんだろう？
I wonder.
行けるのかな？なんかちょっと分かんないんだけど、行けますか？
Can we go? I don't really know, but can we go?
なんか、飲み物飲みすぎて、もういっぱいお手洗いにいっちゃって。
I drank too much, so I've been going to the restroom a lot.
ごめんなさい、何度も何度も離席、離席して。
I'm sorry for leaving my seat over and over again.馆
どんだけやねん。
How many times already?!
いや、でも多分膀胱ちっちゃいんだと思う。
No, but I think my bladder is just small.
そっか。
I see.
許容量がね。
The capacity, right?
そう、そう、そう。器がちっちゃいからしゃあない。
Yes, yes, yes. My vessel is small, so it can't be helped.
あ、器がちっちゃい、なんかちょっと違うやん。
Wait, "vessel is small" has a slightly different meaning!
耐えられない。
I can't hold it.
入ってくる水に。どんだけ笑うねんお前！
With the water coming in. How much are you going to laugh?!
人の膀胱笑うな！
Don't laugh at someone's bladder! Anti-gravity.
助けて。
Help.
膀胱が小さい。
My bladder is small.
膀胱が小さい言わないでね。
Don't say "bladder is small"!
健康だから。健康。
Because it's healthy. Healthy.
あ、健康体は素晴らしい。
Ah, a healthy body is wonderful.
うん。
Yeah.
それは素晴らしい。
That indeed is wonderful.
あ、あ、違うな、あ。
Ah, ah, no... ah.
いいね、ラオラ、エントリやってるね。
Nice, Raora is doing the entry.
えー、やってるね、すごいな。
Eh, they're doing it, amazing.
よし。いや、行きたいな。アンプリンク...
Alright. Man, I want to go. Amplink...
あれで、あれなんだよな。これ、水の中に松明入れたら、あれする？ジュッってなる？
Yeah, that's the thing. If I put the torch in water, does it go "psst"?
うん、あ、ちょっとジュッてなる。
Yeah, ah, it goes "psst" a bit.
ジュッてなるんだっけ？これどうなんだ？行けるかな？
Does it go "psst"? How is this? Can we go?
アイスワームって行けます...
Can we do Ice Worm...
行っていいやつ？
Are we allowed to go?
アイスワームって行けますか？
Can we do Ice Worm?
それ、あれになってない？あの、全体チャットになって...
Isn't that in the global chat...
あ、全体チャットになってる。これいけ、行っていいのかな？
Ah, it is in global chat. Can we go... is it okay to go?
なんか死んでる。恐竜死んでる。
Something died. A dino died.
どれくらいで沸くのか分かんないよね、3分って。
We don't really know how long 3 minutes takes to spawn.
ね。
Yeah.
はーい。でも、これが...
Okay. But if this...
これが今開いてるってことは...
If this is open now, then...
うん。
Yeah.
行けるのかな？この黄、アキロゼがボイチャにいねえんだよな。
Can we go? AkiRose isn't in voice chat, though.
アキロゼに行きたいんだけど、アキロゼあいつ...
I want to go to Akirose's, but Akirose is...
待機...ボイチャにいない。常駐にいないんだよな。
on standby... not in voice chat. She's not usually there, is she?
まあ、空いてるなら行ってみるか。
Well, if it's open, should we go see?
行こうか。トワ様が行ける？
Let's go. Can Towa-sama go?
トワ、乗れないよね、これ。
Towa can't ride this, right?
一回下行ってからだね、多分。
Probably after going down first.
かな？
Maybe?
どうやって行けばいい、これ？ これ滝降りるんでしょ？
How should we go? We go down the waterfall, right?
じゃ、行こうか。 あいよ。 ほい。 うおー！
Then, shall we go? Alright. Here we go. Whoa!
え、ボタン死んだ？ え、いる、生きてるよ。
Wait, did Botan die? No, she's here, she's alive.
下、水だよ。下、水だよ。 うん。 おけおけ。
It's water below! It's water below! Yeah. Okay okay.
うおーー！ うわー！ 何か... 生きてる。
Whoaaa! Whoa! Something... Alive.
これ、あれ... あわわ。陸に上がれない。
This is, like, whoa... I can't get onto land.
今やってる？ 陸に上がれない。あれ？上がれない。
Are they doing it now? Can't get onto land. Huh? I can't get up.
あれ？ あや？ 誰かいる。ヤッホー。 これから？
Huh? Oh? Someone is here. Yahoo. Is it from now?
あ、じゃあ、先どうぞ。あらら。え？
Ah, then please go ahead. Oh dear. Huh?
どうぞどうぞ、お先にどうぞ。
Please go ahead, after you.
これボイチャって自分聞こえてるのかな？フブキちゃんの声聞こえてないわ。
Can they hear my voice chat? I can't hear Fubuki-chan's voice.
ボイチャ壊れてるな、自分。 これ今、これ今あれか？
My voice chat is broken. Is this... is this that right now?
アイスワームって... Dチームがやってるみたいな感じか。
The Ice Worm... Looks like Team D is doing it.
アイスワームって今どういう状況？
What's the situation with the Ice Worm right now?
どういう状況？
What situation?
今、あの... バグでまつり先輩が死んでしまって...
Right now, due to a bug, Matsuri-senpai died...
で、今生き返らせてもらってて、それ待ちですね。
And they are reviving her now, so we are waiting for that.
なるほど。で、まつりちゃん来たらこれからアイスワーム。
I see. And once Matsuri-chan gets here, we start the Ice Worm.
はい、おけ。うちらはじゃそれを待ってたらいいのね？ だと思う。
Okay. So we just need to wait for that, right? I think so.
かな？ あいよ。 そりー。そりー。おけ。
Maybe? Alright. Sorry. Sorry. Okay.
かがり火あったかいんじゃ。これまつりかがり火。 あったかい。
The bonfire is so warm. This is Matsuri's bonfire. Warm.
あったかい。 これでいい。 全然聞こえね。やだ、ボイチャ壊れてる。
Warm. This is fine. I can't hear at all. Oh no, voice chat is broken.
ボイチャ壊れてたら一回ね、再起動しないとあれか？
If the voice chat is broken, do we need to restart once?
Steamで... Steamがあれなのかも。 あ、なんか変わっちゃったのかな？
Steam... Steam might be acting up. Ah, did something change?
うん、変わっちゃったかもしれないから、一回Steam見てみたら？ おけ。
Yeah, maybe it changed, so why not check Steam once? Okay.
Steamの設定... まつりのてし、てしなのがいないかも。
Steam settings... Maybe Matsuri's... is not there.
えーっと... あ、あ、あ。
Let's see... Ah, ah, ah.
よ。 おけ。ちょっとこのプテラだけなんかスタックしちゃった。
Yo. Okay. Just this Ptera got stuck.
まいっか。 チームなんか変わってなかった？その設定した...
Oh well. Did the team change? The setting...
変わってない。 でもこれうちらも降りちゃってるけどいいのかな？
Didn't change. But is it okay that we've come down too?
トワ様の上から降りたら... もう一個降りるんじゃない？
If you get down from Towa-sama... Don't we go down one more?
もう一個下か。 あ、なのかな。 なるほどなるほど。
One more down? Ah, maybe. I see, I see.
これでもここから出していいか？あれ。 うん、大丈夫だと思う。
But can we release them from here? That. Yeah, I think it's fine.
よし、ならお待ち...待ちながら... これはボスが始まったら...
Alright, then while waiting... When the boss starts...
うん。 表示されるのかな？ そうだね。
Yeah. Will it be displayed? That's right.
これだと終わったか...終わってるのかと思っちゃうよね。 ね。
If it's like this, you'd think it's already over, right? Yeah.
おいしょ。はは。
Heave-ho. Haha.
いや、ほかの恐竜意外とテイムできたんじゃないかと思ってしまう。やばい、効率厨は。
Man, I end up thinking we could've tamed other dinosaurs instead. Oh no, the efficiency-obsessive in me is coming out.
わかる、わかる、すごくわかるぞ。この時間もったいないよな。
I understand, I totally get it. This time is such a waste, right?
時間めちゃくちゃもったいないよね。
This time is totally a waste, isn't it?
まあまあしょうがないんだ。しょうがない、バグっぽいからしょうがない。どうやらバグってたらしい。 うん。
Well, it can't be helped. It seems like a bug so it can't be helped. Apparently, it was bugged. Yeah.
洞窟に入った瞬間に何々チーム洞窟入ってますみたいな。 アナウンスあったらよかったね。 うん。
The moment we enter the cave, like 'Team X has entered'... It would've been good if there was an announcement. Yeah.
おいしょ。はは。
Heave-ho. Haha.
まだまだ... あ、出てるよ。 うえー！ うあー！
Not yet... Oh, it's out. Whoa! Whoa!
怖いんだけど、それいけるの？ 頑張れ！
That's scary, can you handle that? Good luck!
え、なんか誰かの... 誰か... おーい、誰か！ え、誰かのプテラが！
Eh, someone's... someone... Hey, someone! Eh, someone's Ptera!
おーい、誰かのプテラ！ プテラ！ 多分向こうのチームじゃないか、これ？
Hey, someone's Ptera! Ptera! Isn't this probably the other team?
うん。 ちょちょちょちょ！ ちょちょちょ、どうしよう？
Yeah. Wait, wait, wait! Wait, wait, wait, what should we do?
ちょちょちょちょ、あのあのあの... あのあの！
Wait wait wait, um, um, um... Um, um!
うおいさー！ 別チーム！ プテラ！
Uoisaa! Different team! Ptera!
誰かのプテラが！ 戦っ... あ、自分のボイチャ聞こえないんだ。
Someone's Ptera! Fighting... Ah, my voice chat can't be heard.
誰かのプテラが... 終わったっぽい？もう終わったっぽい？ 終わった？
Someone's Ptera... Looks like it's over? Already over? Over?
やば、もうこれ上にも上がれないしな。 じゃあちょっとラグ...
Oh no, we can't even go back up now. Then, maybe the lag...
あ、っとっと、置いてかな...置いてかないで！置いてかないで！ プテラ！ おーい、誰かのプテラ！
Ah, wait, don't leave me... don't leave me behind! Don't leave me! Ptera! Hey, someone's Ptera!
訴えたい！
I want to report this!
おい、助けて！
Hey, help me!
助けて！
Help!
おい、誰かのプテラ！
Hey, whose Ptera is this?!
これ下がるか？
Should we back off?
おい！誰かのプテラが！
Hey! Someone's Ptera is...!
すいません、アキロゼです。こちら対応してもらえるよう至急運営さんにお願いしております。
Excuse me, this is Akirose. I'm currently asking management to deal with this immediately.
少々お待ちください。すいません。
Please wait a moment. Sorry about this.
誰か！
Someone!
死んじゃうよ！
I'm gonna die!
死んじゃうよ～！
助けて！
Help!
誰のよ？
Whose is it?
怒った？怒った？忘れて
Is it mad? Did you forget?
おい、ダメージ追ってます！
Hey, we're taking damage!
でもこれ、もうしょうがない、これ
But we have no choice now.
しょうがないよ、これ、もう
Yeah, there's nothing we can do.
俺が死ぬか、お前が死ぬか
Either I die, or you die.
そうですよ。俺が生きるか、お前が生きるか
Exactly. Either I live, or you live.
しかもいなくなっちゃったし
And besides, it went away.
本当だよ、置いてったんだ。置いてかれたぞ、かわいそうやな
Indeed, it left you behind. You were abandoned, how sad.
かわいそう～
How sad!
お前、285
You, level 285.
あ、でもなんかおとなしくなった？
Ah, but did it calm down?
確かに。多分消えたから
True. Probably because it vanished.
消えたか？あ、置いてかれてる
Did it vanish? Ah, it was left behind!
悲しい
So sad...
そうか、置いてかれたって。悲しい
I see, it got left behind. How sad.
捨てられたんだ
It was abandoned.
ふうちゃん、HP大丈夫？
Fu-chan, is your HP okay?
ここで見とけよ。うん、とりあえず大丈夫
Keep watch here. Yeah, I'm okay for now.
やば、スタック消えそう
Oh no, the stack is about to disappear.
プテラノドン、お忘れですよ
You forgot your Pteranodon.
どういう状況？多分「おい」って繋がってると思われてるわ
What's the situation? They probably think "Oi" is connected.
なるほど
I see.
スタックしてるからいいらしいみたい
Apparently, it's fine since it's stuck.
は？え？してなかった？
Huh? What? Wasn't it?
攻撃されてて
It was being attacked...
え、なんか動く
Eh, it's moving.
運営さん、助けて...らしい
Management, please help... apparently.
お前、俺のチームに来るか？お前
Hey, do you want to join my team?
俺のチームに来る...え、なんか。赤ちゃん生まれたと思ったらスタッフさんだった
Join my team... Wait, what? I thought a baby was born, but it was a staff member.
あ、よかった、よかった
Oh, thank goodness.
早っ！どこ行った？どこ行った？一瞬見えた
So fast! Where did they go? I saw them for a second.
おかえり。あ、よかった
Welcome back. Ah, thank goodness.
トーチあった。あ、助かる
We have the torch. Ah, that helps.
スタックしちゃってたんだ、あいつ。かわいそうに
It got stuck, that poor thing.
スタックしてたのか、かわいそうに
It was stuck? Poor thing.
敵対したことにより、自由の身になったんだ
By turning hostile, it became free.
なるほど、そういうことね。うん
I see, so that's what happened. Yeah.
主催申します、アキロゼです
I'm the host, Akirose.
はい、色々ダメージ負ってしまったところもあるかもなので、回復アイテムをお渡しします
Yes, um, since you might have taken some damage, I will give you some recovery items.
助かる。少々お待ちください。ありがとうございます
That helps. Please wait a moment. Thank you.
あ、でも、なんだかんだすぐ回復はできてるから大丈夫っちゃ大丈夫かな、HP
Ah, but we recovered pretty quickly, so our HP is mostly fine.
大丈夫ですか？
Are you okay?
うん、大丈夫大丈夫
Yeah, we're totally fine.
了解しました。では、このまま時間次第、チャレンジしていただくということで大丈夫でしょうか？
Understood. Then, once the time comes, are you ready to take on the challenge?
はい、分かりました
Yes, we understand.
一応メディカルブリューお渡しできるんですが、どうします？
I can give you Medical Brew, what would you like to do?
あ、もらっとこうぜ
Ah, let's take it.
タダですよね？タダですよね？
It's free, right? It's free, right?
タダです。タダならもらいます
It is free. If it's free, we'll take it.
もらい得か、一旦。もらい得
Might as well take it for now. Might as well.
一旦もらい得か、一旦もらい得
Might as well for now.
少々お待ちくださいね。ありがとう
Please wait a moment. Thank you.
あ、捧げもの、いただきやす。おし
Ah, thanks for the offering. Alright.
あ、すごい、8個もあるよ、8個も
Ah, amazing, there are 8 of them!
渡まりましたでしょうか、無事に？
Did you receive them safely?
はい、来ました！
Yes, we got them!
はい、そちらご活用いただきまして、攻略続けてください
Yes, please use them and continue your conquest.
それでは健闘を祈っております。頑張ってください
Then, I wish you good luck. Do your best!
はーい！行ってきます！すいません
Okay! We're off! Thank you!
はい、ちょっと別件で質問があるので、一瞬下に来てもらうの、順番待ちしてます今
Yes, actually, I have a question about another matter, so I'm currently waiting to have you come down.
あ、いい、大丈夫です。ちょっと下にお願いします。すいません。下チーム、2の方ですか、VC？
Oh, no, it's fine. Please head down. Sorry. Is the lower team VC 2?
はい、ビビさんがいるところにお願いします。あ、分かりました。移動します
Yes, please join where Vivi is. Ah, understood. Moving now.
あ、メディカルブリュー、これ。ありがとう
Ah, here is the Medical Brew. Thank you.
何捨てたのだ？何捨てたの？
What did you throw away?
これ乗ったまま飲むとどうなるの？ペット回復する？
What happens if you drink this while riding? Does the pet heal?
自分かな、どうなんだろう。自分か？うん
Maybe yourself? I wonder. Is it yourself? Yeah.
メディカルブリュリュリュ。ブリュリュ
Medical Brew-ryu-ryu. Brew-ryu.
ブリュリュリュリュリュ、ありがとうございます
Brew-ryu-ryu-ryu, thank you very much!
はい、行けます。これもう降りとく？じゃあ
Okay, we can go. Should we get off now then?
いや、時間になったらって言ってるから、まだなのかな、どうなんだろう。もういいかな？
No, she said "once the time comes," so maybe not yet? What do you think? Is it okay now?
あ、重くなった。動けるか、動けるか
Ah, it got laggy. Can we move?
動ける？おけ
Can you move? Okay.
あ、なんかモヤモヤしてる、あそこ。モヤモヤしてるよ
Ah, there's some misty effect over there. It's foggy.
来るっぽいね。行こう、行こう！おけ、おけ！行く？
Looks like it's coming. Let's go! Okay! Ready?
行けー！
Go!
行け！あれじゃない？なんかモヤモヤしてるとこ入る
Go! Isn't that it? Let's enter the foggy area.
あ、来た来た来た来た！
Ah, here it comes!
おおー！来た！
Whoa! It's here!
うわー！
Whoa!
あれ？どこ行った？
Huh? Where did it go?
どこ行った？
Where did it go?
こっち、こっち、こっち！
This way, this way, this way!
やめて！ユウティが...
Stop! Yuty is...
ユウティ！
Yuty!
おりゃりゃりゃ！
Oryaryarya!
ユウティ逃げる！ユウティ逃げる！ユウティ逃げて！
Yuty, run! Yuty, run! Yuty, run away!
逃げて、ユウティ！
Run away, Yuty!
おいで！みんな頑張って！
Come on! Everyone do your best!
よいしょ！
Oof!
ほ、どこだ？ユウティはやめて！
Huh, where is it? Stop it with Yuty!
ユウティだめ！
No, Yuty!
行け！行け！
Go! Go!
今度吸い込めるのかな、これ。頑張って！
Can we suck it in this time? Do your best!
よいしょ！わおーん！わおーん！
Oof! Awoo! Awoo!
どこだ？ヘイト買ってる、ヘイト買ってるけど。
Where is it? It's drawing aggro, drawing aggro.
ユウティが一番ヘイト高いからな。
Yuty has the highest aggro, you know.
やばいやばいやばい。ユウティ持っていかれる。
Oh no, oh no, oh no. Yuty is gonna get carried away.
やばい？だめ！
Is it bad? No!
削りたい、削りたい！
I want to chip it down, chip it down!
デリジウム出そうか？
Should I bring out the Dilo?
出してほしいかも、早めに。
I might want you to bring it out, quickly.
ちょっと結構きついわ、これ。助けて！
This is pretty tough. Help!
よいしょ！
Oof!
デリジウム出すよ、これ。
I'll bring out the Dilo.
おら、おら、おら！
Take that, take that, take that!
よいしょ！かわせ、かわせ。
Oof! Dodge, dodge.
やばい、ユウティはだめだ。
Oh no, Yuty is no good.
あ、おけおけおけ。ええっ！
Ah, okay okay okay. Eh?!
ナイス！
Nice!
ケラチンめっちゃ手に入る。
We get so much Keratin.
おお、よかった、よかった。ナイス！
Oh, thank goodness. Nice!
おけ。
Okay.
うわ、重たすぎ。おもっ。
Whoa, it's way too heavy. Heavy.
重っ、ちょっと捨てよう、捨てよう、捨てよう。
Heavy, let's discard, discard, discard them.
捨てよう、捨てよう、捨てよう。
Discard, discard, discard.
めっちゃある、やばいやばい。めっちゃある。
We have so much, oh no, oh no. So much.
アルゲンって出せる？今。
Can we bring out the Argent now?
アルゲンここで出せんのかな？かな？
Can we bring out the Argent here, I wonder?
あ、こんなに別にいらん。
Ah, we don't really need this much.
出せるわ、どうぞどうぞ。
We can, go ahead.
えっと、ほい。
Um, there.
どこにアイテムどこに入ったんだ？ふぶちゃんとかに入ったのか？
Where did the items go? Did they go into Fubu-chan or something?
ん？あ、これ、アイテム？
Hm? Ah, this, the items?
なんか倒したらなんか出るとかじゃないんだ、これ。
Isn't it like something drops when we defeat it?
あ、ではない。このクレー、クレーとかかな？うん、4つ、4つぐらいあるやつか。
Ah, no. Maybe this crate, crate? Yeah, there are about four of them.
うん、回収しよう。あ、至高のライフルに。
Yeah, let's collect them. Ah, and an Ascendant Rifle.
ここ、あっちか。ちょっとアルゲンの中に入れさせてもらうわ。
Is it here? Over there. I'll put it inside the Argent.
ポンプショットガンとかいっぱいあるわ。
We have a lot of Pump-Action Shotguns.
うん。
Yeah.
あれ、アルゲンどこいる？
Wait, where is the Argent?
ここにいるよ。
It's right here.
あ、あそこか。
Ah, over there.
よいしょ、ちょっと、こっち行くか。ちょっと走って行きます。
Oof, let's go this way. I'll run over.
サドル、こんがり肉、セミオート式、なんかいっぱい、全部持って帰ればいいっか。
Saddle, cooked meat, semi-automatic, there's a lot, I guess we should just take everything back.
クレートある。あ、至高のライフル激うま過ぎるな、これ。
There's a crate. Ah, the Ascendant Rifle is way too good.
いいね。
Nice.
待って、入れてます。入れてます。
Wait, I'm putting it in. I'm putting it in.
クレートはもうない？
Are there no more crates?
よっ、ね、なさそう。うん。
Yep, doesn't look like it. Yeah.
ナイス！ナイス！ナイス！
Nice! Nice! Nice!
ちょっと湧くの怖いから出ちゃうよ、一回。ポイポイして。
I'm afraid of spawns, so let's get out of here. Throw them away.
うん、出よう。
Yeah, let's get out.
重くない？大丈夫？大丈夫。
Isn't it heavy? Are you okay? I'm okay.
大丈夫？おけ。
Okay? Okay.
こっちでいいのかな？出口。あ、ちょっと重かった。
Is this the right way? The exit. Ah, it was a bit heavy.
これ何が重たいんだ？
What is making it so heavy?
にゃんこ、にゃんこが重たいか。にゃんこがまだ重たかったっぽいな。
Is the kitty, kitty heavy? Seems like the kitty was still heavy.
はいよ。
Here.
あと、道どこ？
Also, where is the path?
回収しようか？
Shall we collect it?
いや、多分捨てるやつだから大丈夫だと思う。終わり。
No, it's probably stuff to discard, so I think it's fine. That's all.
おけ。
Okay.
よいしょ、あ、まあ一旦お肉だけど。
Oof, ah, well, for now it's just meat.
うわ、すげえ、卵。
Whoa, awesome, an egg.
取って、この辺は全部ぽいぽい。
Take it, discard all of this.
おっき。えーで、みんな待ち。
Okay. And then, waiting for everyone.
おっけーです。出ます。
I'm ready. Let's go out.
はーい。
Okay.
あれ、どこ？どっちからだ？右、左、どっちからだ？
Wait, where? Which way is it? Right, left, which way?
右だね、これ。上なんか突き抜けられるそうにないけどな。
It's right. It doesn't look like we can break through the top, though.
気持ちわる。気持ちすぎる。
Feeling sick. So sick.
さーさんもそれ行けなくね？
Can't Sa-san go that way either?
アーティファクト回収、アーティファクト、アーティファクトどこにあるんだ？
Artifact collection... Artifact, where is the Artifact?
アーティファクトあります？
Is there an Artifact?
ここ。
Here.
これだ、これだと思う。これだけど、今湧いてないから。
This, I think it's this. It's this, but it hasn't spawned yet.
写真撮ったらいいみたいに言ってなかったっけ？
Didn't they say we should take a picture?
あ、確かに。なんか言ってた気がする。アーティファクト。
Ah, indeed. I feel like they said something like that. Artifact.
とりあえず写真撮っとくわ。
I'll take a picture for now.
おけ。はい。撮った。
Okay. Okay. Took it.
ふむふむ。
Hmm, hmm.
じゃあ右。ここですかね。
Then right. Is it here?
ここかな？
Is it here, I wonder?
よし、スクショ助かる。
Okay, the screenshot helps.
右？
Right?
こっちかな？このまま行ったら出れるのかな？
This way? If we keep going, can we get out?
あれ？もう、どうやって右行った？あれ？
Huh? Wait, how did you go right? Huh?
あ、出れなくなった？
Oh, you can't get out?
あ、あ、なんか引っかかってる
Ah, ah, it's like, stuck.
穴から出て？
Oh, did you come out of the hole?
これちょっと回収しなきゃいけないかも
I might have to retrieve this.
それ上突き抜けられないもんね？
You can't phase through the top of that, right?
うん
Yeah.
閉じ込められたか？ん？
Are you trapped? Hm?
もしや回収できない
I might not be able to retrieve it.
なんかあれかも
It might be...
ワンチャン運営案件
...possibly an admin issue.
あのボス部屋通れなくなっちゃってるから
Since we can't go through that boss room anymore...
閉じ込められたわ
...I'm trapped.
あ、閉じ込められ案件もしや？
Oh, maybe a "trapped" issue?
あ、待って、降りちゃった
Ah, wait, I got off.
この、こっちじゃないのかじゃ？
So, is it not this way?
いや、フブちゃんたちの方で合ってる多分
No, Fubu-chan and the others are probably going the right way.
あ、そうなの？
Oh, really?
そう、そう、そう
Yeah, yeah, yeah.
あー、なるほど。じゃ、こっちで
Oh, I see. Then, this way.
え、何このチタノ生きてんじゃない？戻っていこう
Wait, what is this? Is the Titan still alive? Let's head back.
マジ？倒しとく？
Really? Should we kill it?
収納のして、出るのかな？
Put it away and head out?
これ、アキちゃんに言って、出してもらうとかも
We might have to ask Aki-chan to get us out.
あ、すご、重い。よいしょ
Ah, wow, it's laggy. Oof.
アキちゃん
Aki-chan.
自分たぶん出れたかな？
I think I made it out?
運営連絡でいいか。あれ？
Should I just contact the admins? Huh?
うん
Yeah.
戻ってきた？あれ？
You came back? Huh?
いない、いない
She's not here.
demo, jīpan modocchatta
But I ended up going back.
戻ってしまえばよかった
You should've just gone back.
あらら、さっきのところでよかったんだよ
Oh dear, that spot earlier was fine.
I guess I thought I saw it.
およ、およぎ、およぎたともうたけど
I thought I could swim, but...
戻ってしまいました。えへへへ
I ended up going back. Ehehehe.
はいよ
Alrighty.
お、重い、ここ重い
Oh, it's so laggy here.
登れない、そして
And I can't climb.
あれ？写真、写真はどこに行けばいい？
Wait, where should I take the photo?
あね、プテラ閉まっちゃって
Wait, my Pteranodon is put away.
くっ、くっ、登れない、登れない。なんでこんな登れないの？ここ
Ugh, I can't climb up, I can't climb up. Why is it so hard to climb up here?
あ、あ、ここですよ、ここ。やばい
Ah, it's here, over here. Oh no.
で、このまままっすぐ水渡って行こう
And then, let's cross the water straight ahead.
お、よいしょ
Oof, there we go.
あ、そっか。ここか
Oh, I see. It's here.
よいしょ
Up we go.
外だ！外だー！
Outside! It's the outside!
ナイス。オッケー。うわ
Nice. Okay. Whoa.
あ、ここから滝に落ちるしかない？もしや
Oh, do we have to drop down the waterfall from here?
うー。あ、ジャンプできた。あははは保存する
Ooh. Oh, I jumped. Ahahaha.
アーティファクト部屋から抜け出せないらしい。うわああああ！
Apparently, they can't get out of the artifact room. Whoaaaaaaa!
イナ！
Ina!
イナ大丈夫か？
Ina, are you okay?
大丈夫。いけた。ぷぷぷぷぷ
I'm okay. I made it. *spluttering*
いけた。は、は、は
I made it. *panting*
あ、いたいたいた
Oh, there you are!
よかったー！
Thank goodness!
これ、帰る？帰る？
Should we head back? Go home?
え、何？何？
Eh, what? What?
痛い！痛い！
Ow! Ow!
なんか、落とされて、ここ動かん。あー
I got knocked down and I can't move. Ah...
伊藤さんにも連絡してみた。メンションして
I tried contacting Ito-san too. I mentioned them.
オッケー
Okay.
あ、出れた。イェイ
Ah, I'm out. Yay.
やったー。帰りましょう
Hooray. Let's head back.
よいしょ
Up we go.
え、でもこれ歩いて行ける場所ないよね？多分。そもそも通り抜けできないから。うーん
But wait, there's no way to walk out of here, right? We can't even get through to begin with. Yeah...
アーティファクト部屋監禁されてる？
Are you locked in the artifact room?
そう、アーティファクト部屋監禁だと思う。これ
Yeah, I think we're locked in the artifact room. This.
ちょっと待ってね、だって
She said, "Hold on a second."
はい。はいよー
Yes. Okay.
この後はじゃあ、何になるのかな？えっと...
So after this, what's next? Let's see...
ボス部屋に戻れないんだよね、そもそも
We can't get back to the boss room in the first place.
なんか、見えない壁が見えるよね、多分ね。そうそうそう。オーロラの壁が
It's like, you can see an invisible wall, probably. Yeah, yeah, yeah. An aurora wall.
見えない壁が見える
You can "see" an invisible wall.
見えない壁は、見えない。あははは
You can't see an invisible wall! Ahahaha.
アナウンスします。アキロゼです
This is an announcement. This is Akirose.
はい！アキロゼちゃん
Yes! Akirose-chan.
閉じ込められてる、えっとボタンちゃんとトワは、えっとテレポートして洞窟の外に出します
For Botan-chan and Towa who are trapped, I'm going to teleport you outside the cave.
あ、ありがとうございます！
Ah, thank you so much!
はい、そちらでよろしくお願いいたします。少々お待ちください
Yes, please take care of that. Please wait a moment.
はい。はい、ちゅちゅば
Okay. Yes, understood.
どこだろうね？稲、帰り道、これ
Where is the way back, Ina? Is this it?
帰り道どこだろう？トワ様、これ
Where is the way back, Towa-sama? This?
迷子。ちょっと嬉しい。あははは。迷子になってちょっと嬉しいやつ
We're lost. I'm a bit happy. Ahahaha. Getting lost is kind of fun.
これ秘密の話だけど、めっちゃちょっと嬉しい
This is a secret, but I'm actually a little happy.
誰にも言えないけどね
Can't tell anyone, though.
ししろが、出てきてくれたら、あれで分かるかな？
If Shishiro comes out, maybe we can find our way?
そうだね、待っとくわ。よいしょ
True, let's wait here. Alright.
これ、そしたら、あれだね。このアーティファクト、アーティファクトじゃなくて...
If that's the case... this artifact... wait, not the artifact...
で、うん。この、トロフィー、飾りにいかないとね。
And, yeah. We have to go display this trophy, right?
確かに。なんか納品するって。そう。そう。
Indeed. They said we need to deliver it. Right, right.
こっちか？
Is it this way?
そしたらそのあとが、チームミッションがなんだ？
Then, after that, what's the team mission?
あとあれだよ。ツェッペリン。
Also, there's that. The Zeppelin.
乗って、みんなでわちゃわちゃやろうだぜ。
We should get on it and have some fun together.
いえい。
Yay.
大型恐竜テイムするだ。大型恐竜テイムする。
Taming a large dinosaur. Tame a large dinosaur.
確かにティラノとかいたから、あの、仮拠点の所ね。
Right, there was a Tyranno or something near the temporary base, right?
うん、うん。その間に…やってました。
Yeah, yeah. In the meantime... I did it.
あ、戻ってきた？え、これどこだ？
Oh, you're back? Wait, where is this?
なんか、地図バグってんだよな。
The map is kind of bugged.
あとあれだよ。アキちゃんにさ、1時間に1回の申請やっとかないと。
Also, we need to make sure Aki-chan does that once-an-hour request.
一応、チャレンジ申請中。
For now, the challenge request is pending.
あ、そうだ。チャレンジ申請だから、もうすぐやっちゃう？じゃあ。
Oh, right. Since it's a challenge request, should we do it right away then?
いいんじゃない？トワ様見えますよ。
Why not? Towa-sama, I can see you.
あ、本当？あっち。あ、あっちだ。あっちだ。
Oh, really? Over there. Ah, that way. That way.
おいで。
Come here.
トワ様の事見える？
Can you see Towa-sama?
地図で、地図で見える。
On the map. I can see on the map.
遠い。あ、みんなもう合流してるのか。ごめんごめん。今行きます。
Far. Oh, is everyone already grouped up? Sorry, sorry. I'm on my way.
うち、テレポート場所が分からなくて迷子なんです、こっち。
I don't know where the teleport spot is, I'm lost over here.
テレポート場所は、もっと、もっと雪山の方。
The teleport spot is further, further towards the snowy mountain.
え、どこだ？
Wait, where is it?
こっちか？山の方よね。
This way? Towards the mountain, right?
あの、雪山を近くにして回ったら。
If you keep the snowy mountain close and head around...
行くのかな？
Maybe that will work?
先輩達、すいません、ちょっと共有していいですか？はい、はい。
Seniors, sorry, could I share something? Yes, yes.
なんか、ムキロゼのやつ。
It's about Mukiroze's thing.
ムキロゼミッション、ちょっと事前申請しとかないといけなくて。そうそうそう。
We have to pre-apply for the Mukiroze mission. Right, right, right.
申請締切が21時だから、一旦申請しといたんですけど。オッケー。
The deadline is 9 PM, so I went ahead and applied. Okay.
ありがたい。今帰ってます。
Thank you! I'm on my way back now.
ユウティラか、ギガノト見つけられた奴で始められるので、
We can start with whichever we find, either a Yutyrannus or Giganotosaurus,
どっちかを今、頑張ってみんな、血眼になって探して貰っていいですか？
so could everyone desperately search for either of them?
今、下で、開会式の所のマンモス太鼓やってます、こっち。
Right now, down here, we're doing the mammoth drums at the opening ceremony.
あ、了解。
Ah, got it.
オッケー、ありがとう。戻ったら探しに行こう。
Okay, thank you. Let's search once we get back.
マンモスが大人になりました。
The mammoth has grown up.
ユウティラ、どんな奴だろう？
What does a Yuty look like?
ユウティラ…
Yuty...
なんか、雪山にいるとか言ってなかった？気のせい？
Didn't they say it was in the snowy mountain? Or am I imagining it?
ユウティラは、ユウティラはトワがさっき乗ってた奴だよ。
A Yuty is... A Yuty is the one Towa was riding earlier.
あ、そうんだ。あの、毛むくじゃらの奴。あ、そうそうそう。
Oh, really? That fluffy one. Ah, yes, yes, yes.
到着。ここだね。
Arrived. It's here.
うわあ、スタミナが。
Whoa, my stamina...
ほい。
Whew.
うん。
Yeah.
じゃ、探すか。
Well, shall we search?
そうだね。ユウティラ、ギガノト。
Yeah. Yuty or Giganoto.
ユウティラかギガノト。
Yuty or Giganoto.
回収オッケー、ほなじゃあ、テレポートします。
Retrieval OK. Well then, teleporting.
はーい。はーい。
Okay. Okay.
よいしょ。
Here we go.
戻ってきた。これ、集会所行かなきゃじゃない？
We're back. Don't we need to go to the assembly hall?
あ、集会所もか。
Ah, the assembly hall too?
トロフィーが、ええと、待って。もしかするとアルゲンに入ってるかも。
The trophy... Wait, it might be in the Argentavis.
あ、オッケー、オッケー。
Oh, okay, okay.
ちょっと見たい所あるから、お願いしていいですか？オッケー、オッケー。
There's somewhere I want to check, can I leave this to you? Okay, okay.
ええと、どれだどれだどれだ？
Let's see, which one is it?
あ、これか。アイスワームクイーンのトロフィー。オッケー、取った。
Ah, this one? Iceworm Queen trophy. Okay, got it.
おお、きた。
Oh, nice.
ドレッドノートスってなんだ？
What's a Dreadnoughtus?
あれかな、銃乗っけられるカメかな？違うかな。
Maybe that turtle with a gun mounted on it? No?
へえ。
Oh.
よいしょ。
There we go.
オッケー、ありがとう。
Okay, thank you.
あ、ごめん。集会所来ちゃった。あ、いいよ。オッケー。
Oh, sorry. I came to the assembly hall. Oh, that's fine. Okay.
ええと。
Let's see.
なんか、ライフルとか、革靴とかは、
Like rifles or leather shoes...
あ、一旦これ、借りちゃおうかな。
Oh, maybe I'll borrow this for now.
ええと、トロフィー、どこだっけ？なんかどっかの樽の中だっけ？
Let's see, where was the trophy again? Was it in one of the barrels?
あ、こっちやね。
Oh, this way.
あの、中央の。あ、ここで合ってた。
The one in the center... Ah, this was the right place.
中央…
Center...
なんか、トロフィーはどこどこ、みたいなのなかったっけ？
Wasn't there something about where the trophies go?
ええと、集会所近くの樽。あ、樽にアーティファクトを納品して、樽、樽。
Let's see, barrels near the assembly hall. Oh, deliver artifacts to the barrels, barrels.
集会所近くの樽？あ、これか。
Barrels near the assembly hall? Oh, this one?
あ、これだ。
Ah, this is it.
あ、ユーティね。ユーティ探そう。
Oh, Yuty, right. Let's look for a Yuty.
ユーティね。
A Yuty, right.
ユーティは、あの、
The Yuty is... well,
ユーティ…冷蔵庫の中。あ、はいはい、お願いします。
Yuty... inside the fridge. Ah, yes, yes, please.
オッケー、オッケー。冷蔵庫ね。はい。
Okay, okay. In the fridge? Yes.
おお。ユーティ、ボロボロね。
Wow, the Yuty is in bad shape.
頑張りましたね。でも、ユーティ、あの、死んでも戻れる、
It did its best. But the Yuty has that thing where it returns even if it dies,
あ、確かに確かに。
Ah, true, true.
入れましたので。
because I put that on.
よいしょ。一旦戻るか。
Alright. Shall we head back for now?
ええと。
Let's see.
と。
Okay.
よいしょ。
There we go.
トロフィーとアーティファクト、もしかして違うか？
Are trophies and artifacts different?
びびさん？
Bibi-san?
1個1個別だね、それ。
They're separate items.
あ、えーっと、じゃあ待って、トロフィーはどこだ？
Ah, wait, then where is the trophy?
あ、ビビ飛ばしてもらおう。
Ah, let's have Bibi teleport me.
トロ、トロフィーの納品所は違うか？
Is the trophy turn-in spot different?
I dropped all...
えーっと...
Let's see...
あ！
Ah!
ポータル1回使っても？
Can I use the portal once?
ちょっと待ってくださいね。すいません、なんかバグってマモスが出ちゃった。失礼。どうぞ、お気...
Wait a moment. Sorry, a bug spawned a Mammoth. My bad. Go ahead...
ナイスマモスクエスト！
Nice Mammoth Quest!
終わりました。で、報酬ももらってきました。
It's finished. And I got the reward.
あれ？なんかいつの間にか自分、ダキスに乗ってたわ。
Huh? Somehow I ended up riding Dakis without realizing it.
あ、いいよ。
Ah, it's fine.
戻った、戻った。
It's back, it's back.
あと約10分くらいで、もう見つけなきゃいけなくて、ユーティラヌス、えーっと何だっけ？
We have about 10 minutes left to find a Yutyrannus, um, what was it?
ユーティラヌスがたぶん一番見つかりやすいかな。
Yutyrannus is probably the easiest to find.
見つけようと思ったら、たぶん。
If we want to find one, probably.
なるほど。
I see.
で、このなんだ、ツェッペリンがちょっと今からテレポートができるのか、ちょっと試します。
And, let's see if we can teleport with this Zeppelin. I'll test it out now.
はい。
Yes.
え、これってモンボに入れられるのか？この...
Wait, can this be put into a Cryopod? This...
あ、来た来た来た！
Ah, they're here!
え？入れられないんじゃない？
Huh? I don't think you can.
どうなんやろう？
I wonder.
ちょっとやってみます。
Let me try.
物は試し。
It's worth a shot.
お前は恐竜なのか？どっちなんだい？
Are you a dinosaur? Which one are you?
でもテレポート、テレポート場所に乗せれば、一緒に行くんじゃない？
But if you put it on the teleporter, won't it go with us?
おっ。
Oh.
果たして。
We'll see.
これ、推薦枠って何？9時から10時までってこと？
What is this recommendation slot? Meaning 9 to 10?
そうなんですよ。その1時間枠で、みたいな。
Yes, in that one-hour window.
だから、まあユーティラやるんだったら9時45分までにやんなきゃいけないし、ギガノトやるんだったら...
So if we're doing Yutyrannus, we have to do it by 9:45, and if we do Giganoto...
たぶん、湧いた時点で、なんかスタートらしくて。
Apparently, it starts once they spawn.
なるほど。
I see.
だから9時になった瞬間、もう始まっちゃうから、今すぐ見つけておかなきゃいけない。
So the moment it hits 9:00, it starts, so we need to find one right away.
あ、そうなの？
Oh, really?
たぶん、そうです。で、次の枠が10時らしく。
Probably. And the next slot is at 10:00.
ちょっと、雪山にユーティラいると思うから、雪山ぐるっと回ってたら。
I think Yutyrannus is in the snow mountain, so if we circle around there...
だよね。
Right.
今、ちょっとこれ違うとこ...
Right now, I'm in a different place...
雪山ね？
The snow mountain, right?
これ火山。
This is the volcano.
そう、あ、だからもうツェッペリン乗って雪山を周回、一緒にいってもいいかもね、みんなで。
Yes, so we can ride the Zeppelin and circle the snow mountain together.
オッケーです。今、雪山で走ってます。
Okay. Currently running in the snow mountain.
あ、ツェッペリン回収、回収しといてもらえたら嬉しい。
Ah, if you could pick up the Zeppelin, that'd be great.
あ、ツェッペリン回収ね、はい、ちょっと待って。
Ah, pick up the Zeppelin? Okay, wait a moment.
じゃ、ツェッペリン一緒に乗っていこうかな。
Then, shall we ride the Zeppelin together?
そうそうそう、みんなで一緒に乗っていこう。
Yes, yes, let's ride it together.
はい、オッケー。
Okay.
だったらみんな、麻酔矢は持った方がいいんじゃない？
Then, shouldn't everyone bring tranquilizer arrows?
そうだね、麻酔矢と。
Right, tranq arrows and...
分かりました。
Understood.
了解です。
Roger that.
ちょっとごめん、先行っててもらっていい？後で合流するわ。
Sorry, can you guys go ahead? I'll catch up later.
はーい。
Okay.
ちょっと待って、これ降ろせない。今、恐竜が下にいっぱい居すぎて。
Wait a sec, I can't land this. There are too many dinosaurs below right now.
あ、そっちで良かったら降ろせるよ。
Ah, I can land it over there if you want.
行けます？
Can you?
はい、オッケー。これで。
Yes, okay. Here.
はーい。
Okay.
乗りました？
Are you on?
麻酔矢、ちょっと後で分けてもらうかもです、誰かに。
I might ask someone to share some tranq arrows later.
私、今142本。足りないか？
I have 142 right now. Is that not enough?
あ、いや、たぶんみんなで撃てば足りるはず。
Ah, well, if everyone shoots, it should be enough.
足りるか。
It should be.
え、じゃあゴリさん、はい。
Then, Gori-san, here.
ありがとうございます。84本だけ置いとく。
Thank you. I'll drop 84 of them.
ありがとうございます。あ、取れねえ、なんだと。
Thank you. Ah, I can't pick them up. What?
ちょっと待ってください、あれだ。
Please wait, that's it.
この中に、これ入れっぱだ。危ねえ。
I left this in here. Dangerous.
ミミも麻酔198個持ってるから。
Mimi also has 198 tranq darts.
あ、オッケーオッケー。じゃあビビも乗ってくれ。
Ah, okay. Then Bibi, get on too.
よし、私も行きます。
Alright, I'll go too.
乗って乗って。
Get on, get on.
みんな乗って、出発！
Everyone's on, let's go!
頑張って後で行く、絶対に。
I'll do my best to catch up later, definitely.
いいよ。
Alright.
ビビ後ろから。
Bibi, from behind.
こっちか。ちょっと待って、今作ってて、あ、体が重い。
This way? Wait a moment, I was crafting, ah, my body is heavy.
体が重い、あいつ。
That guy's body is heavy.
重い、動けビビ、走れ、行け。
Heavy! Move, Bibi, run, go!
一旦キャンセルしてもいいや、あれ。
You can cancel crafting for now.
あ、はい、分かりました。一旦乗りました、乗れた。
Ah, yes, understood. I got on, I'm on.
いいよいいよ、終わったら自分のトライブで追いかけますわ、自分も。
Alright, when I'm done, I'll chase you guys on my own mount.
これアルゲン持って行かなくていいですか？
Is it okay not to bring the Argentavis?
いらない。
No need.
バグで動けない。
Bugged and can't move.
待って、待って。
Wait, wait.
麻酔矢、麻酔矢撃った後の流れは？
Tranquilizer arrows, what's the plan after shooting tranq arrows?
麻酔矢撃つ、撃つだけでいい。
Just shoot tranq arrows, that's enough.
撃つだけでいい、オッケー。
Just shoot, okay.
そう、一旦。で、寝たらお肉を誰か入れる感じかな。
Yes, for now. And when it falls asleep, someone puts meat in.
お肉持ってる？みんな。なんかお肉持ってない。
Do you have meat? Everyone. I don't have meat.
お肉ある、お肉ある、3個だけある。
I have meat, only 3.
お肉ある人じゃあ。
Then, whoever has meat...
あ、乗って、ジャンプで。
Ah, get on, by jumping.
あ、お肉持ちました。
Ah, I have meat now.
オッケー。
Okay.
水が...
Water...
うわ。
Wow.
やべ、これもし引っかけた？いや大丈夫か。
Uh oh, did this get caught? No, is it okay?
引っかけた？大丈夫か、上行けない、あ、行けた行けた。
Is it caught? Is it okay? I can't go up... Ah, I can, I can.
猫可愛い！
The cat is cute!
待って、まさかの引っかけ、引っかかったかも！引っかかった！
Wait, did it get caught? We might be caught! Caught!
引っかかった！
Caught!
引っかかっ...
Ca...
あ、行けた、行けた行けた。
Ah, it went, it went.
コツが、コツがありまして、それ。やりましょうか？
There is a trick to that. Shall I do it?
大丈夫か？
Are you okay?
大丈夫ですか？
引っかかった、あ、行けた行けた。
It was caught, but it went.
行けた行けた。
It went, it went.
いいね、行こう行こう。
Nice, let's go, let's go.
いいよ、いいよ、いいよ。
Alright, alright, alright.
これシフトで浮上で大丈夫だよね、たぶん。
We ascend with Shift, right? Probably.
あ、いい。
Ah, yeah.
で、一応、シフトっていうかダッシュボタン入れると走れます。
And, if you press Shift or rather the dash button, it runs.
だよね、オッケーオッケー。
Right, okay, okay.
ちょっとユーティラヌス、足速い恐竜で探しながらにしようかな、ちょっと待って。
Maybe we should look for the Yutyrannus using a fast dinosaur, wait a second.
いいよ。
Okay.
あれ、上、上に飛ばないんだよな。なんでだろ、これ。
Huh, it doesn't fly upwards. I wonder why.
ちょっともふもふの...
A bit fluffy...
上に、上に向かって進んでくれない？
Can you head up... head upwards?
あ、えっと、カーソルを上に向けたままWの発進で上に行けます。
Ah, well, keep the cursor pointed up and press W to move up.
あ、あ、これだこれだこれだこれ。こうだこうだこうだ。
Ah, this is it, this is it! Like this, like this!
なんか、ダスキンが死んでいる。ツェッペリンの上でダスキン死んでました。
Wait, Duskin is dead. Duskin was dead on top of the Zeppelin.
え、嘘、あ、しま…しまったよ。
Eh, really? Ah, I... I put it away.
あ、しまった？あ、じゃあ死んでないんだ。これなんだろ。お肉が残ってたのか。
Ah, you put it away? Then it's not dead. What's this? Leftover meat?
多分、お肉が残ってるんじゃないかな。
There's probably some meat left over.
あ、もらいました。
Ah, I got it.
よし、じゃあ周りにユティラいないか…
Alright, are there any Yutyrannus around...?
あ、やばい、やばい、今、五臓の皿の、膝の皿がバリバリバリバリ…
Ah, oh no, oh no! Right now, my kneecaps are rattling...
落ち着いて、落ち着いて。大丈夫だよ。
Calm down, calm down. It's okay.
遅いから、ワイバーンがいいかもしれない、もしかすると。ワイバーンどこ？
Since it's slow, maybe a Wyvern would be better. Where is the Wyvern?
Towaは今ワイバーン乗ってる。
Towa is riding a Wyvern right now.
そうですよね。探せたら嬉しいな。
Right. It'd be great if we could find one.
探して…めっちゃ探してます。私遅いけど。
Searching... I'm searching hard, though I'm slow.
ね、ビビの肩見て、ボタン先輩。なに？何乗ってんの？
Hey, look at Vivi's shoulder, Botan-senpai. What? What's riding on it?
めゃめゃ、可愛いでしょ。可愛い、可愛い。
It's super cute, right? So cute, so cute.
なんか、ワイバーン飛んでる。え、あれ誰の？知り合いのワイバーンなのかな。
Oh, a Wyvern is flying. Whose is that? Is it an acquaintance's?
あれはTowaのワイバーンじゃない？
Isn't that Towa's Wyvern?
いえ、水色のワイバーンなんです。
No, it's a light blue one.
じゃあ、知らないワイバーンか。知らないワイバーンだ。
Then is it an unknown Wyvern? It's an unknown one.
あ、水色ワイバーンはアイスワイバーンだね。雪山にいるんだよ。
Ah, a light blue one is an Ice Wyvern. They live in the snowy mountains.
この下のやつ、それじゃないの？
Isn't that the one below us?
あ！あれか！いるかも、あれじゃない？あのモフモフどう？
Ah! That one! It might be, isn't it? What about that fluffy one?
これもモフモフじゃない？あれ。
Isn't this one fluffy too? That one.
あ、あ、今見下ろした、下した下した、これこれこれ。これそれ。
Ah, ah, I looked down just now, below, below! This, this, this. That one.
いたいたいた！これ、麻酔打っていいやつ？麻酔打っていいやつ？
Found it, found it! Is it okay to shoot tranquilizers at this one?
麻酔、はい。オッケー。
Tranquilizer, yes. Okay.
オッケー、えっと、４７の５１、４７の５１にいる。
Okay, um, it's at 47, 51. It's at 47, 51.
４７、５１、了解です。
47, 51, Roger that.
今、すごい音するな。罠張っとくか。
It's making a crazy sound right now. Should I set up a trap?
え、なんかフブさんとかボタン先輩、イナ先輩の肩に乗ってるのも、猫？猫、猫。
Wait, is that a cat on Fubu-san, Botan-senpai, and Ina-senpai's shoulders? A cat, yes.
にゃおん、にゃおん。
Meow, meow.
設置しました。
I set it up.
おや？よし、これで。
Oh? Alright, with this...
寒そう、ギリースーツ。これいるかな。オッケーです。発見、発見。
You look cold in that Ghillie suit. Do we need this? Okay. Spotted, spotted.
まあ、まあ、大丈夫です。なんとか。なんとかな。
Well, we'll be okay. Somehow. Somehow, indeed.
これって自分運転席から離れてったら、落ちる？いや、一回着陸して…
If I leave the pilot seat, will I fall? No, land it once...
イナ先輩言ってたよね、今。
Ina-senpai was saying that just now, right?
あれは何？あれブロントじゃないよね。
What's that? That's not a Bronto, right?
ブロントはもっと、結構でかめのやつよ。
A Bronto is much bigger, quite a large one.
あ、やべ。アルゲンやって、アルゲンやって。
Ah, oh no. Take care of the Argentavis, take care of it.
なんか、ビビ落ちた。なんで？
Wait, Vivi fell. Why?
やばい、ビビ、ビビ乗って、助けて！痛い、痛い、痛い！
Oh no, Vivi, ride Vivi! Help! Ouch, ouch, ouch!
動き止まったのか？お前！
Did you stop moving, you!
痛い！ビビ！
It hurts! Vivi!
ビビ掴める？
Can you grab Vivi?
いや、あ、ちょっと待って、ビビさんを掴め…痛っ！
No, ah, wait a moment, I can't grab Vivi... Ow!
むずい、人をつつくの。痛い、痛い、痛い。
It's hard to pick up a person. Ow, ow, ow!
ちょっと誘導できないかな。
Can you lead it away?
ビビ！離れたどこ行く？死ぬ！こっち、こっち来れる？こっち来れる？
Vivi! Where are you going so far away? You'll die! Can you come here? Come here!
どこ？ここ、ここ、ここ、崖の上。
Where? Here, here, here, on top of the cliff.
いた、いた、いた！オオカミに追われてる！
Found you, found you! She's being chased by wolves!
オオカミ…あ、じゃあちょっと待ってね、タケ取りに行くか。
Wolves... Ah, then wait a moment, should I go grab the aggro?
あ、大丈夫、ヘイト取った、ヘイト取った。オッケー、オッケー。アイスヘイトします。アキロデスです。
Ah, it's okay, I got the aggro, I got the aggro. Okay, okay. I'll take the aggro. I'm Achilles.
２１時になりましたが、そちらの準備いかがでしょうか？はい、大丈夫です。
It's now 9:00 PM, how is your preparation over there? Yes, we are ready.
五臓のとこに飛んできてもらえると。
If you could fly over to Gozo's location.
はい、今もっと飛んで、見ております。
Yes, I am flying closer and watching now.
あ、じゃあやりましょう。あ、待って、ユティラいた？あ、正面いる、正面いる。
Ah, then let's do this. Ah, wait, was there a Yutyrannus? Ah, it's in front, in front.
はい、それでは今から１５分間カウントいたします。頑張ってください。はーい。
Alright, I will start a 15-minute countdown now. Good luck! Okay.
よし、お騒がせしました。スタートないんかい！
Alright, sorry for the fuss. Is there no start signal?!
あ、今から。用意、スタート！
Ah, starting now. Ready, go!
寄ってくる、寄ってくる、撃ってくれ、撃ってくれ。下、下、下、撃って撃って撃って。
It's coming closer, coming closer! Shoot it, shoot it! Below, below, below! Shoot, shoot, shoot!
撃った。やばい、なんか。キョーフ…あ、五臓です、五臓です、気にしないで。
Shot it! Oh no, something... Fear... Ah, it's Gozo, it's Gozo, don't worry about it.
あ、いけた？いけた？いけたっぽい。あ、いけてる、いけてる。
Ah, did we get it? Did we get it? Looks like we got it. Ah, we got it, we got it.
あ、食べられた、食べられた！
Ah, it got eaten, it got eaten!
食べられた！食べられた！おーい！
It got eaten! It got eaten! Oh my god!
誰？誰？食べたやつ。オオカミが食ったんだ。オオカミ？え、オオカミ？そんなに早く？
Who? Who ate it? A wolf ate it. A wolf?! Wait, a wolf? That fast?
あそこからだ。マジかよ。
It came from over there. Seriously?
最悪だ！なんで？なんでや！
This is the worst! Why? Why?!
オオカミ殺しますか？先にもう、周りにいたら。周りにいたらそうだね。はい、チェイスするわ、頑張って。
Should we kill the wolves first if they're around? If they're around, yes. Alright, I'll chase them, good luck.
え、どこ？どこ？
Wait, where? Where?
マジかよ。どっかいないか。
Seriously? Is there another one somewhere?
継続して探されますか？それとも一度キャンセルしますか？キャンセルしたら１０時だもんね。
Will you continue searching? Or will you cancel for now? If we cancel, it'll be 10:00 PM, right?
１０時ですよね。一旦キャンセル扱いにさせていただきまして、２１時３０分までであれば、もう一度再…早く予約が入ったところを優先になりますが、チャレンジは可能とさせていただきます。
Yes, 10:00 PM. We can treat this as a cancellation for now, and if it's before 9:30 PM, you can try again, though priority goes to earlier bookings.
じゃあ、３０分からにするか。３０分からにしましょう。ちょっとやばい、水がなくて枯れる、体が。あ、お水。
Then, should we do it from 9:30 PM? Let's do 9:30 PM. Oh no, I have no water, my body is drying up. Ah, water.
お願いします
Please.
あ、はーい
Ah, okay.
え、枠としてもう一度再チャレンジをさせてくださいということにしてますか？
So, shall we make it so that we can try again on stream?
はい、お願いします。わかりました。
Yes, please. Understood.
では一旦失礼します
Well then, excuse me for a moment.
はーい、すいませーん。いってらっしゃい。
Okay, sorry about that! Take care!
まさかの死んでしまわれた。いやー、しょうがない、しょうがない。
Wow, they actually died. Oh dear... It can't be helped.
これ着陸できるかな？アルゲンで。
I wonder if I can land this with the Argentavis?
あ、多分無理だから、着陸するね。
Ah, probably not, so I'll land it.
Oh my god. Oh my god?
はい、はーい。いやー。
Yes, yes. Oh boy...
いる？次。アイスワイバーンがいるわ。
Are they there? Next... There's an Ice Wyvern.
じゃ、なんかやっぱりちょっと釣って、人いないとこ行かないと駄目なんだな。
So we really have to lure them away to somewhere with no people.
そうですね。ちょっと乗ってもいいですか？
That's true. Can I get on for a bit?
乗ってほしい？逆に。早めに？
Do you want me to get on? On the contrary, early?
アイスワイバーンが後ろにいるから。シスト、シスト、あ、ジャンプ、あの、着陸してほしい！
The Ice Wyvern is behind us. Shift, shift, ah, jump, um, please land!
ちょ、ジャンプ、ジャンプ、乗れない！
Wait, jump, jump, I can't get on!
乗れない、乗れない、それ乗れないです！
I can't get on, I can't get on, I can't get on that!
ておー、ておー！
Teo! Teo!
てお、乗って！あ、乗れた、乗れた！乗った乗った。
Teo, get on! Ah, I got on! I'm on, I'm on.
これ、これ、これ。斜面、斜面。
This, this, this! The slope, the slope!
斜面がカツカツなんです。
The slope is really tight!
いやいや、もう、もう、プテラに戻るよ。
No, no, I'm going back to the Pteranodon now.
あいよ、あいよ、あいよ、あいよ。これで乗ってほしい。
Alright, alright, alright. I want you to get on this.
上乗れない。この引っかかり... よし、オッケーです。
I can't get on top. This snag... Okay, all good.
オッケー。運転、やろうか？プテラもしまっておいたから大丈夫。
Okay. Should I drive? I put the Pteranodon away so it's fine.
オッケー。じゃ、探すか、ユウティラ。
Okay. Well, let's look for a Yutyrannus.
はい。毛がフサフサですもんね。
Yes. Since they have fluffy fur, right?
そう、毛がフサフサ。フサフサ。
Yes, fluffy fur. Fluffy.
フッサフッサ、おいで。
Fluffy fluffy, come here.
フッサフッサ。フサフサーン。
Fluffy fluffy. Fluffyyy.
あ、やばい、あと水ありますか？あるよ。
Ah, shoot, also, do we have water? Yeah.
あ、助かります。さすが。
Ah, that helps. As expected.
あ、じゃあここに置いとくよ。あ、アイスワイバーンの巣がある、あそこ。
Ah, then I'll leave it here. Ah, there's an Ice Wyvern nest over there.
ええ、あれ？右に見えますのは、アイスワイバーンの巣でございます。
Really, that one? What you see on the right is an Ice Wyvern nest.
落とした、ありがとう。ありがとうございます、助かりました。
I dropped it, thank you. Thank you so much, that saved me.
ちなみにそれ、イナの水筒。
By the way, that's Ina's canteen.
リレーしてる、その水筒。よいしょ。
They are relaying that canteen. Heave-ho.
え、また残ってますか？お水。
Wait, is there still water left?
あ、自分のだな。あ、オッケーです。
Ah, that's mine. Ah, okay.
どっかで水あれば、汲む。
If there's water somewhere, I'll fill it.
マンモス、マンモス、ユウティラ。マンモス、ユウティラ。
Mammoths, Yutyrannus... Mammoths, Yutyrannus.
ワイバーンとかで周りをなんとか、ちょっと待って、ええと。
Maybe with a Wyvern we can do something about the surroundings... wait, let me see...
探しに行ってもいいけどね。
We could go search, though.
ねー。あ、そう、プテラ今持ってる人は、むしろ探しに行ってくれたほうが嬉しいかも。
Yeah. Oh right, those who have Pteranodons on them, it might be better if you go look for them.
あ、じゃ、行きます。
Ah, then I'll go.
ちょっと待ってね、着陸しますね。はーい。
Wait a moment, I will land. Okay.
おいよ。
There we go.
はい。
Yes.
気をつけて。はい、任せなー。
Be careful. Yes, leave it to me!
あ、ちょっと寒いから、服、持ってこようかな。
Ah, since it's a bit cold, maybe I'll go grab some clothes.
毛皮持ってきたの？それはやばい。
Did you bring fur? That's crazy.
寒いなー。毛皮、毛皮ないと死んじゃう。
It's cold! Without fur, I'll die.
ここはね、ちょっと寒いからね。
It's a bit cold here, after all.
ちょっと服持ってきます。はーい、了解。
I'll go get some clothes. Okay, roger.
え、イナもお水をね。ね、お水をね。
Wait, Ina needs water too. Yes, water.
お水行こう。ありがとうございます。
Let's go get water. Thank you very much.
えーっと。
Let's see...
こいつか？結構いる。
Is it this one? There are quite a few.
これ？むずい。おい、なんかすごい。あ、いった。いたかも。
This? Difficult. Whoa, this is crazy. Ah, there! There might be one.
あ、オッケー。座標教えてほしい。
Ah, okay. I'd like to know the coordinates.
あ、ちょっと待って。ユウティラでも30分だからな。ちょっと時間あります。
Ah, wait. Even for Yutyrannus, it takes 30 minutes. We have a bit of time.
これ、ユウティラですか？30分からだから...
Is this a Yutyrannus? Since it's from 30 minutes...
いたいたいた。なんとなく場所。
There it is, there it is! Sort of the location.
ただ、ここ人がちょっと多、あのね、多い。人が多い？
But there are a bit too many, you see, too many people here. Too many people?
モブが多すぎる。あ、なるほど。氷のところなんだけど。
Too many mobs. Ah, I see. It's in the ice area, though.
はい、はい、はい。
Yes, yes, yes.
今から早めてもらうこと無理なんか、わがままか。30分からだし。
Is it impossible to have them speed it up now? Is that too selfish? Since it's from 30 minutes.
とりあえず45の51だね。
Anyway, it's 45, 51.
オッケー、じゃ、その辺りにいるかもってことで。はい。
Okay, so they might be around there. Yes.
ただ、マンモスとか周り野生生物多すぎて多分厳しい、ここ。狼さえやれればオッケー。
But there are too many wild creatures around like Mammoths, so it might be tough. If we can just deal with the wolves, we're good.
多分。まあ、それか、誰かワイバーンで一掃してもらうかかな？
Probably. Or maybe we can have someone wipe them out with a Wyvern?
いや、ちょっと広いね。
No, it's a bit wide.
ユウティ、めちゃめちゃ下に誘導してくる、ユウティ。
Yuty, lure them way down, Yuty.
なるほど。うん。
I see. Yeah.
ユウティもって、囲っとく？
Shall we lure the Yuty and trap it?
まあ、囲うのありだと思うんですよね。罠なし、でも罠なしテイムでしょ？
Well, I think trapping it is a good idea. No traps... but it's a trap-less tame, right?
囲っとくのはいけない、だめかな？
Is trapping it not allowed? Maybe not?
ミッションに置いといて、戦う時は出せばいいと思うから。
We can leave it in the mission, and just release it when we fight, I think.
なるほど。そう。
I see. Right.
あ、そういうことね。じゃあ連れていけばいいのか？
Ah, I see. Then should we just take it with us?
かな？
Maybe?
でも、こいつ結構手負いなんだよな。違うやつ探したほうがワンチャンいいかも。
But this one is pretty beat up. Maybe we should look for another one.
手負いのやつワンチャン、倒れちゃい...
A beat-up one might accidentally die...
そう、倒れちゃいそうなんだよね、麻酔矢打ってるときに。あ、そっか。
Yeah, it looks like it might die while we're shooting tranq arrows. Ah, I see.
あった、あった。
Ah, found it, found it.
どうなんだろうか？
I wonder how it'll be?
その場でもう見つけて行くしかだめかな？
I guess we have no choice but to find it on the spot?
周りの状況もありでのテイムかな？
Is it a tame depending on the surrounding situation?
15分だら。
Since it's 15 minutes.
やば、何、なんか挟まった。
Oh no, what, I got stuck in something.
よいしょ。
Heave-ho.
えーっと、もう、もうちょい探してみるわ。
Let's see, I'll search a little bit more.
おっけい。
Okay.
よし、じゃあ、ちょっと...
Alright, then, let's...
よいしょ。
Here we go.
なんか、オオカミいる近くにいる率高いよな、これ。
For some reason, the chance of them being near wolves is quite high.
トワにギリースーツ渡したまんまやもしや。
I might have left the ghillie suit with Towa.
あー、ギリー。
Ah, the ghillie...
アルゲンに入ってるかも。
It might be in the Argentavis.
アルゲンがどこだ？
Where is the Argentavis?
よいしょ。
Heave-ho.
あ、トワ、アルゲンは置いてきてる。あの、拠点に。
Ah, Towa, I left the Argentavis behind. At the base.
あー、あれか、ありがとう。
Ah, is that it? Thank you.
戻してもしかな？
Should we retrieve it?
ああ、ちょちょちょ、ここが。
Ah, wait, wait, wait, this place is...
よいしょ。
Heave-ho.
うーん、いるかな？ あいつかな？
Hmm, is it there? Is that it?
えーっと。
Let's see...
えっと、あ、あったあった。
Let's see, ah, found it, found it.
よし、火をつけて燃やしておこう。
Alright, let's light a fire and burn it.
えーっと。
Let's see...
あ、生肉欲しいかも。
Ah, we might need some raw meat.
生肉？ あります、あります。
Raw meat? I have some, I have some.
てかアルゲンの中にめっちゃありそう。
Actually, there's probably a lot in the Argentavis.
生肉ここの餌箱の中にいったん入れてますよ。
I put some raw meat in the feeding trough here for now.
欲しかったらどうぞ。
Help yourself if you need it.
はーい。
Okay.
あっちゅ、あっちゅ、あっちゅ。
Hot, hot, hot!
えーっと、この間にやっていないミッションが何だ？...
Let's see, what mission haven't we done during this time?
大型恐竜テイム？
Tame a large dinosaur?
そう、大型恐竜のテイム。
Yes, taming a large dinosaur.
ティラノ、デイノ、バイソン...
Rex, Deino, Bison...
あー、とりあえずティラノかな？
Ah, maybe a Rex for now?
ティラノ、ティラノ近くにありましたね。
Rex, there was a Rex nearby.
いいよ、いいよね。ティラノ行くか？
Sure, sounds good. Shall we go for a Rex?
この間に。
While we're at it...
テイムしましょう。
Let's tame it.
サクッと行けそうだよね。
It seems like we can do it quickly, right?
ふんふん。
Yeah, yeah.
じゃ、ちょっと、これ、これでやります？練習がてら、この。
Then, shall we do it with this? Just for practice, with this...
そうだね、そうだね。
Right, right.
運転します、ちょっと待って。
I'll drive, wait a moment.
おっけい、ツェッペリンで行こう。
Okay, let's go with the Zeppelin.
ツェッペリーン、どこや？
Where is the Zeppelin?
ツェッペリーン。
Zeppelin!
よいしょ。
Heave-ho.
自分ちょっとあれしよう。
I'll go do that.
あららら。
Oh dear.
よいしょ、いったん拠点行きます。
Here we go, I'll go back to the base for now.
あ、違う、これワイバーンの卵か？
Ah, wait, is this a Wyvern egg?
ワイバーンの卵取った瞬間に来ちゃうからね。
Because they'll come the moment you take a Wyvern egg.
よいしょ。
Heave-ho.
今はそれじゃない。
That's not what we're doing now.
行けます。
We can go.
おっけい、じゃあ乗ってください。
Okay, please get on.
おっけい。
Okay.
どこにいたんだろう？
I wonder where it was.
えっと、み、左、左、左の草原。
Let's see, l- left, left, the grasslands on the left.
オッケーです。
Okay.
乗ってます？これ、みんな。
Is everyone on board?
乗ってます、なんとなく。
I'm on, somehow.
なんとなく、なんとなく乗ってる、了解。
Somehow, okay, got it.
ここってもどれる... 戻れるかい...
Can we return here... can we return?
挟まってる！
I'm stuck!
戻れます？
Can we return?
戻れてます、ちゃんと戻れてます。
I got back on, I'm properly back on.
怖い、怖い。
Scary, scary!
この先ね、まっすぐ行ったとこのどこかにね、多分いると思うんだよな。
Up ahead, if we go straight, I think it'll probably be somewhere around there.
了解、ジュ。
Got it.
ワープ、ワープポイントを見つけたい。
I want to find a warp point.
よいしょ。
Heave-ho.
あ、いたいたいたいたいたいた。
Ah, there it is, there it is!
おお、これよね？
Oh, is that it?
うん。
Yeah.
おっけい。
Okay.
ここちょっとすっきりしてるかも。えっとね、座標言っていい？
It looks a bit clear here. Um, can I tell you the coordinates?
うん。
Yeah.
43...
ちょっと待って、えっとね。
Wait a moment, let's see...
うん。
Yeah.
43、58。
43, 58.
43、58、オッケー、メモった。
43, 58, okay, noted.
じゃ、20分ぐらいになったらそこ行くか、あとちょっと10分ぐらい。
Then, shall we go there in about 20 minutes? Just about 10 more minutes.
あ、ティラノか？
Ah, is that a Rex?
あ、いるのですか？
Ah, is it there?
あれティラノだね。
That's a Rex.
あれティラノか？あれティラノじゃなくね？...
Is that a Rex? Isn't that not a Rex?
なんか、薄くね？顔。あ、あ、奥にいる、奥にいる、めっちゃ。
The face looks a bit thin, doesn't it? Ah, it's further back, further back, there's one.
いや、ティラノか？
Wait, is it a Rex?
え、ティラノ？
Eh, a Rex?
この声はティラノ...
This roar is a Rex...
奥にいるやつ、あれはティラノか？あれティラノじゃないですか？
That one in the back, is that a Rex? Isn't that a Rex? Trump?
なんかいる。
There's something.
あれティラノじゃないか？あ、ティラノだあれ、きっと多分。
Isn't that a Rex? Ah, that is a Rex, most likely.
え、後ろにいる。
Eh, it's behind us.
いや、アクロカントか？あいつでもいい、さっきのやつでも。
No, is it an Acrocanthosaurus? Either one is fine, even the previous one.
もう誰でもいいや、なんか来ちゃった。
Anyone is fine, something just came!
え、どこ？どこだ？どこだ？
Eh, where? Where is it? Where is it?
正面、正面、正面。
Right ahead, right ahead, right ahead!
あ、おっけー、おっけー、正面ね。そこで止まって欲しい。
Ah, okay, okay, right ahead. I want you to stop there.
はい。
Yes.
ティラノ。
Rex! Trump.
おら。
Take that!
届きます？
Can you reach it?
もうちょい寄る。
Move a bit closer.
よし、こんなもんでどうでしょう？
Alright, how about this?
はい。
Yes.
当たった？あ、ちょっと上、あ。
Did it hit? Ah, a bit too high, ah.
うわ、すごい音した。
Whoa, that made a huge sound.
ちょっと上、上。真上過ぎるかな？
A bit higher, higher. Is it too directly above?
やばい、ビビがまた落ちる。
Oh no, Bibi is going to fall again.
やばい、こっち来ちゃった。もう！何これ！
Oh no, it came over here. Geez! What is this!
回りますね。
I'll turn around.
ういしょ。
Here we go.
はい、これでどうでしょう？
Okay, how about this?
うわ、ビビがおとりになってる！ビビ、走り続けてくれ！
Whoa, Bibi is being the decoy! Bibi, keep running!
止まらないでほしい！戻ってきてほしい！
Please don't stop! I want you to come back!
戻ります！
I'm coming back!
ビビ、またエサやった。やっぱりビビって、エサだ。
Bibi was bait again. Bibi really is just bait.
エサだ、ビビエサやん、お前！
Bibi, you're just bait, you!
あ、撃て、撃て、撃て、撃て！
Ah, shoot, shoot, shoot, shoot!
ワープポイント。
Warp point.
ちょっと下がってるけど、バックのスピード遅っ！こいつ。
I'm backing up a bit, but its reverse speed is so slow! This guy.
あ！
Ah!
どうですか？頭狙えそうな位置ですか？これ。
How is it? Is this a good position to aim for the head?
いけそう。
It looks doable.
めっちゃ入ってる、入ってる。
It's hitting, it's really hitting!
あ、オッケー。
Ah, okay.
あっちの方かな？
Is it over that way?
弓割れた！
My bow broke!
うまい！
Nice shot!
誰か弓、あれ…
Does anyone have a...
ん？持ってますか？あの…
Hm? Do you have... um...
私の…
My...
武器壊れて…
My weapon broke...
あ、武器持ってる？
Ah, do you have a weapon?
よいしょ。一瞬もうちょっとめっちゃ下がる。
Up we go. Let me back up a bunch for a second.
あ、壊れちゃったのか、クロスボウ。
Ah, did your crossbow break?
クロスボウじゃなくて、普通のボウです。
It's not a crossbow, it's a regular bow.
あ、ボウ？ボウ持ってる、いっぱい。これ使って、これ使って。
Ah, a bow? I have plenty of bows. Use this, use this.
落とした、落とした。
I dropped it, I dropped it.
よいしょ。
Up we go.
届かんわ、足元。
I can't reach below us.
ビビやっときます。
I'll take care of Bibi.
ありました？
Did you find it?
届かない、届かない。あ、ちょっと真下になっちゃって、狙えないかも。
Can't reach, can't reach. Ah, it's right under us, I might not be able to aim.
よいしょ。
Up we go.
イナ先輩、取れました？あ、待って、後ろ。
Ina-senpai, did you get it? Ah, wait, behind us.
まっすぐ行ってほしいな。そう、あー！
I want you to go straight. Yes, ah!
左行くわ。右崖だから、戻ってほしいかも。ちょっと。
Going left. There's a cliff on the right, so I might need you to back up a bit.
あいつですよね？ちょっと待ってくださいね。
It's that guy, right? Hold on a second.
ね、逃げてる？逃げてる、逃げてる。
Hey, is it running away? It's running, it's running.
あ、オッケーオッケーオッケー。逃げてるならもうちょっとかな？
Ah, okay, okay, okay. If it's running, maybe a little more?
よいしょ。
Up we go.
逃げてないわ。後ろにいる。
It's not running away. It's behind us.
後ろです。
It's behind us.
え、後ろ？あ、後ろか、ごめん。
Eh, behind us? Ah, behind, sorry.
恐竜間違いした。
I got the dinosaur wrong.
こいつじゃないのか、こいつ！
Wait, it's not this one? This one!
ビビんとこ、ビビんとこ。
Bibi's place, Bibi's place!
恐竜間違い、恐竜間違い。オッケーオッケー。
Wrong dinosaur, wrong dinosaur. Okay, okay.
ビビんとこ。
Bibi's place.
オッケーオッケー、ビビ、ビビ頑張ってくれ！
Okay, okay, Bibi, Bibi hang in there!
あれ？あれ？もう一匹いたの？
Huh? Huh? Was there another one?
怖っ！もう一匹いて、撃ちまくってしまったかも。間違えてる。
Scary! There was another one, and I might have shot it like crazy. I got it wrong.
やべー！
Oh crap!
いてっ！
Ouch!
ビビ、ビビ、ヘイトになってる。いや、そっち行くか。
Bibi, Bibi has aggro. No, let's go over there.
よいしょ。
Up we go.
どこ行った？
Where did it go?
うわ、２匹！
Whoa, two of them!
ほい、これで頭狙ってほしい。
Here, I want you to aim for the head.
あった、あった。体が青っぽい方だよね？青っぽい方。
Found it, found it. It's the one with the bluish body, right? Bluish one.
あ、そうそう、こいつ。正面来てる方。
Ah, yes yes, this one. The one coming from the front.
オッケーオッケー。
Okay, okay.
よいしょ。
Up we go.
やばい、バックオーライ、バックオーライ、ぐるぐるぐるぐる。
Oh no, backing up, backing up, spinning round and round.
バックオーライ、バックオーライ、助かる？いい感じいい感じ。
Backing up, backing up. Are you safe? Looking good, looking good.
おりゃ！これ撃てる？
Hup! Can you shoot this?
ちょっと、まだ。
A bit... not yet.
待って、もう一匹にビビやられた！なんだこいつ！
Wait, Bibi got killed by another one! What is this guy?!
壊れてて、ちょっと、引くわ。
It's broken, wait, I'm pulling back.
逃げてる、逃げてるかも、あいつ。
It might be running, that guy might be running.
壊れてる？壊れてる？ちょっとちょっと落ちて。
Broken? Broken? Wait, wait, drop down.
ちょっと落ちて、なんか素材、あ！
Drop down a bit, some materials... Ah!
飛んでる！
I'm flying!
飛んでるの乗っていいですか？一瞬。
Can I ride the flying one? Just for a second.
え！逃げて、プテラ持ってる。
Eh! Run, I have a Pteranodon.
プテラ、私に飛んでる！え、大丈夫大丈夫大丈夫。
Ptera, it's flying towards me! Eh, I'm fine, I'm fine, I'm fine!
大丈夫？あれ、どこ行った？
Are you okay? Huh, where did it go?
大丈夫じゃない、私が…
I'm not okay, I am...
イナ先輩どこ？イナ先輩。イナ逃げて！イナ逃げていいよ、逃げていいよ、どっか遠くに。
Where is Ina-senpai? Ina-senpai. Ina, run! Ina, you can run, you can run, go somewhere far away!
やばいやばい。
This is bad, this is bad.
おんぶアクション、キーちょっと待って…
Piggyback action, wait, what's the key...
イナ先輩どこ？
Where is Ina-senpai?
いくわよ。
Here I go.
待って待って、イナこれ？
Wait, wait, is this Ina?
こっち来て。ごめんなさい、ビビが死んじゃった。
Come here. Sorry, Bibi died.
いやいや、大丈夫大丈夫。乗って乗って乗って、乗って乗って。
No, no, it's fine, it's fine. Get on, get on, get on, get on, get on!
え、大丈夫？ビビ！
Eh, are you okay? Bibi!
イナ先輩、乗るの？
Ina-senpai, are you getting on?
あ、じゃ私、私が…そうやる。
Ah, then I... I will... do it like that.
ちょっと、１人は時間かかるよ！
Wait, doing it alone will take time!
１人は時間かかるよ！２人とも！
Doing it alone will take time! Both of you!
撃ってくれ！ごめん。
Shoot it! Sorry.
撃ってくれ、頼む！ごめんね、離して。
Shoot it, please! Sorry, let go of me.
撃つ撃つ撃つ。
Shooting, shooting, shooting.
行こうかな、どっちや？
Should I go? Which way?
ちょっとごめんなさい。
Sorry, just a second.
体が青、体が青い方。
The body is blue, the blue one.
はい、青い方行ってます。青い方、青い方！
Yes, going for the blue one. Blue one, blue one!
ほい、あれ、ちょっと遠くなりすぎました、こっちですか？
Here, oh, we got a bit too far, is it this way?
あ。
Ah.
いける。
We can do this.
ほい。でも赤が、白か。撃っちゃった。
Here. But red is... white? I shot it.
よいしょ。ちょっと回り回ります。崖すぎ、崖すぎ。
Up we go. I'll circle around. Too much cliff, too much cliff.
オッケーオッケー、助かる助かる。
Okay okay, this helps, this helps.
待って、飛んでる。マジでむずい。
Wait, it's flying. This is seriously hard.
今何してるの？それ。
What are you doing now?
えっと、テイム。大型恐竜のテイム。
Uh, taming. Taming a large dinosaur.
どうやるの？それ。
How do you do that?
えっと、今ツェッペリン乗ってティラノにずっと麻酔矢撃ってる。
Uh, right now we're on a Zeppelin shooting tranq arrows at a T-Rex.
なんで撃つわ。２匹おる、２匹やめてくれ、マジで頼むわ。
Why do you shoot? There are two of them, please stop with the two of them, seriously I'm begging you.
麻酔弾、お願いします。あの、正面です。このツェッペリン正面の青とオレンジのやつ。
Tranq darts, please. Um, in front. The blue and orange ones in front of this Zeppelin.
オッケー。
Okay.
痛すぎやろ。
That hurts too much!
よいしょ。
Up we go.
痛すぎ、痛すぎ。
Too painful, too painful.
ちょっと、麻酔矢が足りないかも、自分。
Wait, I might be running out of tranq arrows.
私、来てるよ、撃ってるよ。
I'm coming, I'm shooting.
オッケー。
Okay.
もうすぐ行きます、少々お待ちを。
I will be there soon, please wait a moment.
おいしょ。
Up we go.
来てる！痛い！死ぬ！
They're coming! It hurts! I'm gonna die!
こっち、青い方、青い方。青い方狙って。右、右ね。
Here, the blue one, the blue one. Aim for the blue one. On the right, the right.
ああ、最悪や！よいしょ。
Oh, this is the worst! Up we go.
うさぎのななり、やられている。
Bunny Nanari is getting beat up.
もう、やだ。イナ先輩、ちょっともう1匹放してほしいかも。
Oh, come on. Ina-senpai, I might need you to release one more.
カルノサウルスに殺された。
I got killed by a Carnotaurus.
ちょっと、えっと、どこ、どこだ？こいつか。
Wait, um... where, where is it? This one?
ボタン先輩どうすか？そっから撃てます？
Botan-senpai, how is it? Can you shoot from there?
う、撃ってはいるけど、距離がね、ちょっと遠いかも。あ、おちおち。
I- I am shooting, but the distance might be a bit too far. Oh, wait, wait.
ふぅ、金属...
Phew, metal...
オッケー、寝た！寝た、寝た！もうすぐ寝る。寝る、寝る、寝る！
Okay, it's asleep! It's asleep, asleep! It's about to sleep. Sleep, sleep, sleep!
あ、お肉入れて、お肉入れて。
Ah, put meat in, put meat in.
入れるわ。
I'll put it in.
ほらっ！
Take that!
肉でいい？
Is meat okay?
肉でいいよ、入れちゃって。
Meat is fine, put it in.
入れたら、周りの敵に注意しといて。一応。
Once it's in, watch out for surrounding enemies. Just in case.
いろは、降りれる、それ？
Iroha, can you get down from there?
降りたい、降りたいけど...
I want to, I want to get down, but...
大丈夫ですか？ちょっと。
Are you okay? Wait.
あ、ちょっと待って、来てる来てる。あ、オッケーオッケー、ちょっと待って。
Ah, wait, it's coming, it's coming. Ah, okay okay, hold on.
オッケー、乗っていい、乗っていい。あ、乗った乗った。
Okay, you can get on, you can get on. Ah, she got on, she got on.
オッケー、オッケー。
Okay, okay.
あ、乗ってきたかも。あ、ごめん、降りた私。
Ah, maybe she rode on. Ah, sorry, I fell off.
あ、了解です。
Ah, Roger that.
あ、これ作業台か。
Ah, is this a workbench?
ちょっと痛いですけど、降りてもらえます？
It hurts a bit, but could you get off?
奥さん。
Ma'am.
よいしょ、作業台。
Heave-ho, workbench.
ボタン先輩、中央の... こいつが邪魔すぎる。こいつを...
Botan-senpai, the center... This guy is in the way too much. This guy...
こいつがティラノ食っちゃう。
This guy's gonna eat the Rex.
あ、食っちゃうな。
Ah, it will eat it.
大丈夫か？
Is everything okay?
やばい、ちょっとこいつ離せない。
Shoot, I can't shake this guy off.
痛い痛い痛い。
Ow, ow, ow.
なんか攻撃できないから。中で。
Because I can't attack. From inside.
ティラノ乗ってる人、誰か攻撃してあげれない？ヘイト取れない？
The person on the Rex, can someone attack for us? Can you take the aggro?
あ、ヘイト取ってくれてます。
Ah, she's taking the aggro.
あ、オッケー。
Ah, okay.
よし、自分も行きます。行きます。
Alright, I'm going too. Going.
なんか挟まれてるから無理。
I'm sandwiched, so I can't.
こいつ倒す、こいつ倒す。こいつ倒す。
Defeat this guy, defeat this guy, defeat this guy.
ナイスナイス。
Nice, nice.
倒した、倒した、倒した。
Defeated, defeated, defeated!
ナイス！ナイス！
Nice! Nice!
遠くまで連れてきました、別のティラノ。
I brought another Rex far away.
ありー。
Thanks.
そういえばクロスボウと麻酔薬、多分ござる落としたやつ落ちちゃった、イナ先輩に渡そうと思って。
By the way, the crossbow and tranquilizers, I think Gozaru dropped what she had, thinking of passing them to Ina-senpai.
ああ、気づかなくて、多分どこかに...
Ah, I didn't notice, they're probably somewhere...
ごめん。
Sorry.
大丈夫、大丈夫。
It's okay, it's okay.
なんか落ちた。
Something dropped.
もし、可能であれば、クロスボウを作ってきてもらえると、多分ユーティラヌスに間に合うかも、ごめんなさい。
If possible, if you could make a crossbow, we might make it in time for the Yutyrannus. I'm sorry.
あ、いいですよ。
Ah, sure.
あ、じゃあクロスボウ作っちゃうね、自分が。
Ah, then I'll make the crossbow myself.
ありがとう。
Thank you.
あ、後ろから来てるよ、ボタン先輩。またちっこい奴。
Ah, they're coming from behind, Botan-senpai. Another tiny one.
ちっこい奴どれ？
Which tiny one?
こっちこっち。
Here, here.
ん？どれ？
Huh? Which one?
ここここ。
Here, here, here.
あと10分だ、いけるか。あと10分でユーティラヌスの時間が。
10 minutes left, can we make it? In 10 minutes, the Yutyrannus's time...
やべっ、ユーティラヌスか。
Shoot, the Yutyrannus?
でも43の58ってのがなんとなく分かってるから、とりあえずは。
But I kind of know it's at 43 by 58, so for now...
あ、そうやね。
Ah, that's right.
多分。
Probably.
え？どうなったんですか？ティラノもう死んだ？
Eh? What happened? Is the Rex dead?
ううん、昏睡してるよ今。テイムしてるよ。
No, it's unconscious right now. We're taming it.
わかった、ありがとうございます。
Understood, thank you.
43.6%です。
It's at 43.6%.
クロスボウ何個か作っておいてもいいかもですね。ござる今日どうせユーティラヌスの時操縦するんで。
Maybe we should make a few crossbows. Gozaru is going to pilot during the Yutyrannus anyway.
イナ先輩あたり、予備として持ってもらって。
So Ina-senpai and others can hold them as spares.
了解、了解。クロスボウじゃ作っとくね。
Roger, roger. I'll make the crossbows then.
あ、私、捕まえてるヤツ、霜降り持ってませんか？ボタン先輩。霜降り肉。
Ah, the one I caught, does it have prime meat? Botan-senpai. Prime meat.
生肉ならある。霜降り、あ、どっかにあるかも、ここ。
I have raw meat. Prime meat, ah, might be somewhere, here.
霜降り、あ、これかな？霜降りだったら早いんじゃないかな、確か。
Prime meat, ah, is it this? If it's prime meat, it'd be faster, I think.
まじ？入れて入れて。
Really? Put it in, put it in.
今、テイム中43%だね。
Taming is currently at 43%.
やべ、こいつ、体... 霜降りってそういえば重てぇんだった。
Shoot, this guy, its body... Come to think of it, prime meat is heavy.
よいしょ。
Heave-ho.
霜降り。あ、これ入れた方がいい？
Prime meat. Ah, should I put this in?
そう、これ入れた方がいいって。一回おろしちゃった、色んな恐竜を。
Yes, it's better to put this in. I unloaded them once, the various dinosaurs.
あいよ。
Alright.
痛。
Ow.
えーっと。
Let's see...
私のワイバーン...
My wyvern...
私のプテラどこ行った？
Where did my Ptera go?
あ、待ってね、今からそっち行く。
Ah, wait, I'm going over there now.
あいよ。
Alright.
俺のプテラどこ行った？
Where did my Ptera go?
誰か乗って帰っちゃってるな。
Someone rode it back.
あ、オッケー、あ、じゃあ、あ、オッケーオッケー。
Ah, okay. Ah, then, ah, okay okay.
助かります。
Thanks.
いや、ビビの猫死んだかも。
Oh no, Bibi's cat might be dead.
いや、猫いるよ。
No, the cat is here.
死んでない？よかった。
Not dead? Thank goodness.
猫ここ。やっぱり。
Cat is here. Just as I thought.
なんか猫、名前見え、が気がする。
I think I can see the cat's name.
どこビビの死んだ、あれ？
Where did Bibi's die? Huh?
あ、ここだよ。なんかセペリンをフォローしてる。猫ちゃん。
Ah, it's here. It's following the Zeppelin. The kitty.
あ、セペリンの下にいるわ。
キャット。
Ah, it's under the Zeppelin.
ちょっと待って、セペリン浮かすわ。
Hold on, I'll float the Zeppelin.
どこだ？
Where?
ビビ。
Bibi.
セペリンの下。
Under the Zeppelin.
よいしょ。
Heave-ho.
ここ。
Here.
ここで、イナ先輩、このセペリンの追従外せるから？こいつの。
Here, Ina-senpai, can you unfollow this Zeppelin? For this guy.
あ、ちょっと待ってください。えっと、フォロー...
Ah, please wait a moment. Let's see... follow...
あ、ティラノそろそろ行く、よいしょ。
Ah, the Rex is almost ready. Yo-ho.
飛ば！
Fly!
ユーティラに羊肉いる？
Do you need mutton for the Yutyrannus?
いらない。
No need.
オッケー。
Okay.
あ、できた！
Ah, it's tamed!
はい。
Yes.
こいつでもどうする？
But what do we do with this guy?
置いといていいよもう、置いといて置いといて。
You can just leave it now, leave it, leave it.
猫ちゃん、ここだよ。
Kitty, it's here.
ビビ、ビビ、ビビ、ロスしたかも。
Bibi, Bibi, Bibi, I might have lost it.
ティラノさん、これ置いとくね。
Mr. Rex, I'll leave you here.
ここだよ、猫ちゃん。
It's here, kitty.
置いといて一旦。
Leave it for now.
そっか、持ってくるもの無い、無いから。サドルが無いもんな。
Right, there's nothing to bring, because there's no saddle.
猫、ありがとうございました。
For the cat, thank you so much.
ビビ、マップに自分の死亡した場所書いてない？
Bibi, isn't your death location marked on the map?
書いてて、それを今探してるんですが見つからなくて。
It is, and I'm looking for it now, but I can't find it.
ティラノのサドルが、でも入ってる、若葉の中に。
A Rex saddle is already in there, in the beginner supplies.
本当に？乗れます。あ、でも、待ってよ。
Really? I can ride it. Oh, wait, though.
ポット、ポット入れ、ポット入れます。
I'll cryopod... I'll cryopod it.
はい。
Okay.
行こう。
Let's go.
ユーティラノの時間がちょっとやばいから。
Because we don't have much time for the Yutyrannus.
はい、じゃ乗ってください。
Okay, please get on.
え？
Huh?
ちょっと待ってね。
Just a second.
うん？
Hmm?
じゃ。
Then...
あ。
Oh.
え、嘘でしょ？
Wait, really?
待って。まず探して、モンボにしてまいな？
Hold on. First find it, and then put it in a ball.
ししろにね、ティラノが追従。
A Rex is following Shishiro.
ついてる？
Is it following?
追従しちゃってるかも。
It might be following.
あ、ちょっと、ちょっと、あの。
Ah, wait a second.
間違えた。
I made a mistake.
私フォローしてるから、ちょっと呼んでて。ビビちゃん。
Since it's following me, can you call it? Bibi-chan.
はい。
Yes.
ビビちゃんのとこに。
Near Bibi-chan...
猫？
A cat?
うん、猫。はい。
Yeah, a cat. Yes.
えーっと、ビビの荷物はあった？
Let's see. Did you find Bibi's belongings?
荷物ありました。
Yes, I found the belongings.
オッケー。
Okay.
ほんじゃ、行こう。
Then let's go.
ティラノ、ティラノ大丈夫か？
Is the Rex... is the Rex okay?
もうじゃ、猫もいいや。
Oh, whatever, the cat's fine too.
ティラノはもう、ピストルして、持って帰った。
We already cryopadded the Rex and took it back.
あ、ありがとう。
Ah, thank you.
うん。
Yeah.
しまった。
Oh no.
よいしょ。
Up we go.
43の58にいるかな？
Are they at 43, 58?
まだいると思うよ。
I think they're still there.
ビビ、プテラだと嬉しい？
Bibi, would you prefer a Pteranodon?
ビビプテラ、はい。
Bibi, Ptera, yes.
うん。オッケー、このまま行っちゃいますね。
Yeah. Okay, I'll go ahead like this then.
行くよ。
Let's go.
43の58あたりにいるっていう。
They're said to be around 43, 58.
了解です。
Got it.
よいしょ。
Up we go.
ギュッとかあっちか。
Squeezed or over there?
イナ先輩、猫じゃあビビが持っていきます。すいません。
Ina-senpai, Bibi will take the cat then. Sorry.
よいしょ。
Up we go.
えーっと。
Let's see.
あ、来てる。
Oh, it's here.
はい。
Yes.
あ、ごめん。なんか落ちた。
Oh, sorry. I think I dropped.
え、何？
Eh, what?
あ、でも、プテラある、プテラある。
Oh, but we have a Ptera, we have a Ptera.
行きます。
Let's go.
いける？おお。
Can you go? Oh.
プテラあるんで。
Because we have a Ptera.
あの。
Um...
オッケー。
Okay.
どうせアキロゼの確認一回入るからその時に。
Since Akirose will check in once anyway, then...
うん。乗っちゃいましょう。
Yeah, let's get on.
こっちかな。
Is it this way?
ふんふんふん。
Hmm hmm.
よいしょ。
Here we go.
アルゲンってあったりします？基地に。
Are there any Argys? At the base.
プテラの方が速いから、プテラだとありがたい。
Pteras are faster, so a Ptera would be appreciated.
プテラ。
Ptera.
ごめん、ワンチャン... ワンチャン、これ、ユニコーンいたかも知れなくて、ちょっと見てる、今。
Sorry, there's a small chance... a small chance a unicorn was here. I'm checking right now.
いいよ。
Sure.
オッケー。ユニコーン、ギリースーツとベリーあればオッケー。
Okay. For a unicorn, a ghillie suit and berries are fine.
うん。
Yeah.
熱い、ユニコーンは。よいしょ。
A unicorn is hot. Here we go.
ちなみに、みんな麻酔はどれぐらい持ってる？
By the way, how much narcotic does everyone have?
117。
117.
0。
0.
なら、行けるかな？オッケー。
Then, should we be fine? Okay.
ビビはめっちゃ持ってるけど、今全然向かえてない。
Bibi has a ton, but I can't head over there at all right now.
そして、プテラが荷物パンパンで持て... 乗れない。
And my Ptera is full of luggage, so I can't... ride it.
荷物捨てろい！
Dump your luggage!
はい。
Yes.
よいしょ。
Up we go.
荷物を置いてくるんだ。
Go put your luggage away.
43の58。
43, 58.
このまま真っ直ぐ行くとね、アイスワイバーンいるわ。
If we keep going straight like this, there's an Ice Wyvern.
なるほど。ちょっと待って、それはもう聞いてないわ。
I see. Hold on, I didn't sign up for that.
えーっと、こっちか。
Let's see, this way?
そうね。
Yeah.
左側にいたやつですよね？
It's the one that was on the left side, right?
多分、右... 今ね、右の方にいて。
Probably right... right now, it's on the right side.
めっちゃ体熱いんだけど、雪山のくせに。なんで？
My body is so hot, even though we're in the snowy mountains. Why?
雪山のくせに体熱すぎるだろ、どうなってんの？
Too hot for a snowy mountain, what is going on?
なんか燃えているよね？
It looks like it's burning, right?
うん、体熱い。
Yeah, body's hot.
58こっちか。
58 is this way.
で、座標いくつだっけ？45の...
What were the coordinates again? 45...
43の58って言... あったかな？
It was 43, 58... was that it?
43の58。
43, 58.
スタミナが... ゆっくり下りている。
Stamina is... slowly going down.
ちょっと左迂回して、行ったほうがいいかも。
We should probably detour a bit to the left.
よいしょ。
Up we go.
なんか、とんでもねえでっけえカマキリいる。
There's an incredibly huge Mantis.
頑張ってゆっくり下りるんだ。
Do your best to descend slowly.
え、寒くなったんだけど。はあ？お前、何？
Oh, it got cold. Huh? What are you?
体、情報。
My body, update.
どうしたお前。
What is wrong with you?
あ、まだユーティラ、います。います、います。
Oh, the Yutyrannus is still here. It is.
よっしゃ。
Alright.
お、ワイバーンいるんだけど。
Oh, there is a Wyvern.
ワイバーンいるんだけど。
There is a Wyvern.
アイスワイバーンがね、私ユーティラの上、待機しとくよ。
An Ice Wyvern is here, I'll wait on top of the Yutyrannus.
はい。
Yes.
怖い、怖い、怖い、誰か乗ってるワイバーンがいる。
Scary, scary, scary, someone is riding a Wyvern.
どうしたんだ、君。
What happened to you?
なんか。
Something is...
よいしょ。
Here we go.
今座標いくつだ？48の... 45？
What are the coordinates now? 48... 45?
私ね、今いるよ。ポンって出せんのかな、ここ？
I'm here right now. Can I throw it out here?
あ、なるほど。使います。
Oh, I see. I'll use it.
はい、ここです。
Okay, it's here.
そこか、オッケー。ありがとう。
There? Okay. Thank you.
はい。
Yes.
はい、はい。
Okay, okay.
何番に行けばいいですか？緯度経度。
Which coordinates should I head to? Latitude and longitude.
えっとね、Mを押すと、多分ね。
Let's see, if you press M, probably...
今ピンが出てる。ここに行けってやつが。
There is a pin right now. Pointing to where to go.
はい、ありがとうございます。
Yes, thank you.
うん。
Yeah.
プテラ、いない、いない。ビビ。
No Ptera, no Ptera. Bibi.
え、人のやつでも乗れたら乗って欲しいかも。
Oh, if you can ride someone else's, please do.
はい、サドル。
Yes, the saddle...
すぐで今向かいます。
I'll head over right now.
はーい。
Okay.
そんだら アイスワイバーン湧いた
An Ice Wyvern spawned over there.
あ、本当だ。あ、それか、びびあん、ライトニングワイバーン乗ってきてもいい。
Ah, you're right. Or, Bibi, you can ride the Lightning Wyvern.
冷蔵庫の中にある。
It's inside the fridge.
これか？
This one?
それ。
That's it.
はーい。
Okay.
移動させたほうがいいんだったら...
If we should move it...
ちょっと、なんで移動し...
Wait, why isn't it moving...
大丈夫、大丈夫。周りのクマやっちゃうわ。
It's fine, it's fine. I'll take out the bears around here.
お願いします。
Please do.
おいしょ。
Heave-ho.
これアルゲンだった。
This was an Argentavis.
バグってる。
It's glitching.
もう、何で？
Jeez, why?
大丈夫か？大丈夫か？落ち着いて。
Are you okay? Are you okay? Calm down.
あ、それか、びび、グリフィンでも乗れるかも。
Ah, or Bibi, you might be able to ride a Griffin.
はーい。
Okay.
グリフィン...
Griffin...
おいしょ。
Heave-ho.
ちょっと様子を見ながら...
Let's see how things go...
グリフィン、グリフィン？
Griffin, Griffin?
グリフィンでもライトニングワイバーンでも、飛べるやつだったら。
Griffin or Lightning Wyvern, as long as it flies.
何これ、めちゃくちゃ重いんだけど。ん？
What is this? It's so heavy. Huh?
めちゃくちゃ重いの、毛皮持ってたりするかな？
It being heavy, maybe it's carrying pelts?
いや、重量じゃなくて...
No, it's not the weight...
あ、なんかバグってたわ。
Ah, it was glitching out.
痛痛痛！
Ow ow ow!
飛べた！
I can fly!
あ、バグってた。
Ah, it was bugged.
行けた？
Did it work?
うー。
Ugh...
ワイバーン！
Wyvern!
周りのモブもやってくれると嬉しいです。
It'd be great if you could also deal with the mobs.
あいよ。
Sure thing.
おいしょ。
Heave-ho.
まつり先輩、もしかしてワイバーンで飛んでるの...
Matsuri-senpai, is flying on the Wyvern by any chance...
ユウティラ探しの旅ですか？ユウティラこれやろうとしてる？
For a Yutyrannus search? Are you trying to do Yuty?
おいしょ。
Heave-ho.
あ、やべ。範囲が届かず。
Ah, damn. The range doesn't reach.
あひ、あひ。
Ah, ah.
ウルフ、あ、ウルフを倒した。
A wolf, ah, I killed a wolf.
あ、ウルフ、クマと戦ってる...
Ah, a wolf is fighting a bear...
大丈夫ですか？
Are you okay?
うわ、バグってる！
Whoa, it's glitching!
おいしょ。
Heave-ho.
狼と戦っちゃってる。
It's fighting wolves.
おいしょ。
Heave-ho.
グリフィンに乗って向かってます。
I'm heading there on the Griffin.
はーい。
Okay.
ユウティラがなんかサイに結構ボコボコに...
The Yutyrannus is getting beaten up by a rhino...
マジ？
Really?
このサイだけなんとかならないものか。
Can we do something about just this rhino?
あ、これ違うチームなのか。
Ah, is this a different team?
サイボロボロやろ。
The rhino is in tatters.
そう、これ違うチームなんですよ。
Yeah, they're on a different team.
なんか狙ってるのか分かんなくてどうしたらいいんだろう。
I don't know if they're aiming for it. What should we do?
おいしょ。
Heave-ho.
来た、来た、来た、来た！
They're here, they're here!
ちょっと話しかけてみよう。
Let's try talking to them.
あの、ユウティラ持ってっていいですか？
Um, can we take the Yutyrannus?
おいしょ。
Heave-ho.
あ、このユウティラ、ごめん。今ミッション予約してて...
Ah, this Yuty... sorry. We have a mission reserved right now...
あ、何、何？
Ah, what is it?
あのね、このユウティラ、ちょうど9時半からのミッションで使う予定で...
You see, we're planning to use this Yuty for the 9:30 mission...
もうちょっとで使う予定なんだよね。ごめんね。
We're planning to use it very soon. Sorry.
あ、了解です！他探します。
Ah, understood! We'll look elsewhere.
すいません。
Sorry!
Sorry.
すまんな。
Sorry about that.
おいしょ、おいしょ。
Heave-ho, heave-ho.
こよりさんか？
Is that Koyori-san?
おいしょ。ゴダールさん。
Heave-ho. Godar-san.
あ、なんかユウティ置いとこう。
Ah, let's leave Yuty here.
着陸させますね。あ、乗れてる。
I'll land it. Oh, I'm riding.
マンモスと戦ってる。
It's fighting mammoths.
えっと、あれだ。クロスボウ。
Uh, that's it. Crossbow.
あ、ちょっと待ってください。これ取れないんですよね。
Ah, please wait a moment. We can't take this.
あ、そっかそっか。
Ah, I see, I see.
どうせ撃てないんで、持っててもらって大丈夫です。
He can't shoot anyway, so it's fine if you keep it.
了解。
Understood.
修理してから来たらよかった。
I should have repaired it before coming.
おいしょ。
Heave-ho.
行けるかな？
Can I make it?
えっと。
Let's see.
ちょっと作ってこう。
I'll craft some.
ほいっと。
Here we go.
オオカミ強え。
Wolves are strong.
失礼いたします、アキロゼです。
Excuse me, this is Aki Rose.
ただいま21時30分をまもなく迎えますが...
It's almost 21:30. How are the preparations?
どうですか、皆さん？
How is everyone doing?
はい、私は行ける。
Yes, I'm good to go.
行けるかな？
Can we go?
行けます！
We can go!
大丈夫だと思います。テレポートで行きます。
I think we're fine. I'll teleport over.
あ、ちょっとオオカミ、オオカミちょっと...
Ah, wait, the wolves are a bit...
処理してほしいな。
I'd like them to be dealt with.
オオカミ殺せますか？
Can you kill the wolves?
あ、回収になったら...
Ah, once they are collected...
はい、それではカウントさせていただきます。
Alright, then I'll start the countdown.
よろしいでしょうか？ はい。
Are you ready? Yes.
ミッション、スタート！
Mission, start!
おい。
Hey.
おいしょ。じゃ、着陸してもらって。
Heave-ho. Okay, please land.
ウルフ殺す。
Kill the wolves.
で、オオカミちょっと殺さないと...
And we need to kill the wolves...
寄りますね、まず。
First, I'll pull closer.
はい。
Okay.
オオカミ、尻尾やめろ。
Wolves, stop wagging your tails.
私、麻酔矢持ってるから、私は麻酔矢を...
I have tranquilizer arrows, so I'll...
ごめん、このプテラ、サドルがなくて...
Sorry, this Pteranodon doesn't have a saddle...
あ、いいよ。
Ah, that's fine.
ユウティどこだ、ユウティ？
Where is Yuty? Yuty?
ユウティラ下いるんだけど...
Yutyrannus is below us...
周りのモブをちょっとやらないと...
If we don't deal with the surrounding mobs...
寝た瞬間グリフィンとかでやってもらって...
Once it falls asleep, do it with the Griffin...
そうだね、グリフィンで...
Right, on the Griffin...
びび、ユウティラの周りのマンモスとかを狩って。
Bibi, please hunt the mammoths around Yuty.
はい、分かりました。
Yes, understood.
これ麻酔もう撃っていい？
Can I start shooting tranquilizers now?
撃っていいよ。撃ってください。
You can shoot. Please shoot.
マンモスやるよ。おら！
I'll handle the mammoths. Take this!
ユウティラに当てないように気をつけてね。
Make sure not to hit the Yutyrannus.
はい、ちょっと離れます。
Yes, I'll pull back a bit.
寝てからの方がいいかもね、確かに。
True, it might be better once it's asleep.
うん、寝てからでもいいや。
Yeah, after it falls asleep is fine too.
びび、邪魔。
Bibi, you're in the way.
やべ、ユウティラ見失ったわ。
Damn, I lost sight of the Yutyrannus.
下にいる。あ、もう大丈夫だよ。
They're down there. Ah, it's okay now.
おけです。
Okay.
うん。これ見えてます？皆さん視点。
Yeah. Can you guys see this? From your perspective?
見えてる、見えてる、見えてる。
Yeah, we can see it.
おっけーおっけー。
Okay, okay.
これ撃っちゃっていいね、もう。
Can we shoot it now?
いいよ、いいよ。寝たら肉、寝たら肉。
Go ahead, go ahead. When it falls asleep, feed it meat.
回りますね、よいしょ。
I'll fly around it. Up we go.
はい。
Yes.
あ、落ちちゃった。まいまい落ちちゃっていいよ。
Ah, I fell off. Maimai, you can jump down too.
いや、大丈夫。
No, I'm okay.
恐竜に乗りながらね、ムズいですね。
Riding a dino while doing this is tough.
ムズい。
It's hard.
マンモスがヘイト買ってくれてるから大丈夫。
The mammoth is drawing aggro, so we're good.
ほい、よっしょ。
Here we go.
そろそろ...
Soon...
もうそうだったら今着陸させてるんで乗っちゃってください、フブキ先輩。
If it's almost there, I'm landing now, so please get on, Fubuki-senpai.
いいよ。
Okay.
お肉チェストはいるけど...
The meat chest is there, but...
お尻に撃ち込め！
Shoot it in the butt!
おっけー、ありがとう。
Okay, thanks.
どうだ？
How is it?
上昇します。
I'm ascending.
マンモス死んだね。
The mammoth died.
うん。今だ今だ今だ。
Yeah, now's our chance!
撃て！
Fire!
よいしょ。
Alright.
あ、やばい、ヘイトが...
Ah, crap, its aggro is on...
こっちもいたかな？
Was there another one here?
ゆうてんの体力が持ってくれればいいけど...
I hope the Yutyrannus's HP holds up...
持つかな？
I wonder if it will?
頭に当てられ...当てられてないんだよね。あ、逃げる。
We're not hitting its head. Ah, it's fleeing.
逃げてる。
It's running.
これ狙われてます？
Is it targeting us?
うん、一応。
Yeah, kind of.
頭に当てたい。
I want to hit its head.
同期ズレやばい、こいつ。
The desync on this guy is crazy.
見えない。
I can't see.
ふっ！
Hah!
よいしょ。
Here goes.
うわぁ！
Whoa!
行け！
Go!
あ、落ちたけど、むしろ落ちてもいい。
Ah, I fell off, but honestly, it's fine.
やばいやばいやばい。もうこれ...
Oh no, oh no, this is...
あの、視点変われぃ！
Change my perspective, damn it!
よいしょ。
There we go.
ちょっと距離が...あ、落ちちゃった。
The distance is a bit... Ah, I fell off.
やばい、みんなが落ちてる。
Oh no, everyone is falling off.
いや、でも、でもいけます。
No, but we can still do this.
あいつ、何もしてこないの。
It's not doing anything to us.
もうね、体力が少なくなって逃げてんのかも。
Maybe its HP is low and it's trying to run.
確かに。よいしょ。
True. Alright.
あ、奥に...
Ah, over there...
撃て！
Fire!
視点変わんない。
My perspective isn't changing.
あ、入ってきたら頭。
Ah, if you go inside...
「K」でね、視点変わるから。
Pressing K changes your camera angle.
はい。
Okay.
分かんなくなったら、K1回押して。
If you get confused, just press K once.
1回置いてるから、乗りたい人どうぞ。
I've landed it once, so anyone who wants to ride can get on.
はい。
Okay.
おーい、おーい。
Hey, hey.
ありがとうございます。
Thank you very much.
乗りたい。
I want to get on.
あ、あ、ごめん。手すりに挟まった。
Ah, sorry. I got stuck in the railing.
行ってほしい。
I want to go.
降りました、ありがとう。
I got off, thank you.
行けた行けた。
We made it, we made it.
あ、おっけー、おっけー。
Ah, okay, okay.
お肉入れちゃう。お肉入れる。
I'll put the meat in. Putting the meat in.
お、ナイス。
Oh, nice!
入れた。
I put it in.
ナイス、ナイス。
Nice, nice!
守るぞ。
Let's defend it.
で、周りの敵の警戒を。
And watch out for nearby enemies.
はい。
Okay.
よいしょ。
Alright.
マンモス近くにいるな。
There's a mammoth nearby.
守るぜ。
We'll protect it.
逃げれる...
We can escape...
守ってこう、守ってこう。
Let's defend it, defend it!
ふぅ。
Whew.
ナイス、よいしょ。
Nice. Here we go.
ナイス。
Nice.
倒れてたやつから霜降り持ってきたら早くテイムできるか？
If we harvest prime meat from the fallen ones, can we tame it faster?
霜降り持ってる人います？
Does anyone have prime meat?
あ、霜降りあれだな、置いてきちゃった。
Ah, I left the prime meat back there.
あ、なんかアルゲンタヴィスに入ってなかったっけ？
Wait, wasn't there some in the Argentavis?
どうだろうね。
I wonder.
あ、周りにもういない。あいつ食っちゃったか。
Ah, there are no more around. Did it eat them?
食っちゃったんだよね。
Yeah, it ate them.
こんがり肉でもいいかもね。
Cooked meat might work too.
こんがりしよっかな。
Should I cook some?
こんがり？
Cooked?
こんがり肉。
Cooked meat.
よいしょ。
Alright.
こんがり肉があったら一番早いんだっけ？
Is cooked meat the fastest?
ねえ、ここに何かいる。羊じゃないですか、ここに？
Hey, there's something here. Isn't this a sheep?
え？
Eh?
これ羊？
Is this a sheep?
羊？
A sheep?
それはね、違うやつだけど。
No, that's something else, but...
あ、羊みたいなやつ。
Ah, a sheep-like thing.
待って、何か来てる。
Wait, something is coming.
いった。
Ow.
何の音？
What was that sound?
何か来てるよ。
Something's coming.
何？
What?
虫か。
Is it a bug?
虫？
A bug?
虫かもですね、ちっちゃい虫。
Might be a bug, a tiny bug.
虫。
A bug.
よいしょ。
Alright.
だだだだだ。
D-d-d-d-d.
とわ離れる。
Towa, moving away.
あ、いいよ。
Ah, okay.
なんなの、この虫？やめて。どいて、どいて、どいて。
What is up with this bug? Stop it! Move, move, move!
うん。
Yeah.
だるいだるい...だるい、だるい、だるい、だるい。
So annoying, annoying... annoying, annoying, annoying.
だる、だる。だる。
Annoying, annoying. So annoying.
だるい、だるい、だるい。
Annoying, annoying, annoying.
エイムがば。
My aim is so bad.
だるい、やめて。
This is annoying, stop it.
これサイって殺したら霜降り肉になりますか？
If we kill a Rhino, will we get prime meat?
サイはなんないかな。
A Rhino probably won't.
や、やめとこう。
No, let's not.
あー。
Ah...
やめとこう、やめとこう。
Let's not, let's not.
なんか、なんか、すげえてんやわんやになる気がしてきた、今。
Now I feel like things are going to get incredibly chaotic.
サイ強いからな。
Rhinos are strong, after all.
うん、そう。あれ、思ったより、思ったより死なないってこっち帰ってきて、なんか。
Yeah, exactly. Like, "Wait, it's not dying as fast as I thought!" and then it chases us back here.
食べられる未来が今見えた。
I just saw a future where we get eaten.
まず、その可能性は。
First, that possibility is...
まず。
First...
ねえ。
Right?
やめとこう。
Let's not.
こいつ、まだ捕まえてないよね？
We haven't tamed this guy yet, right?
まだ、まだ気絶中だね。
It's still knocked out.
ごめん、この羊みたいなやつ。
Sorry, this sheep-like thing...
あ、あれはまだかな。
Ah, is that one not ready yet?
これを待って。
Wait for this.
ついでテイム、ついでテイム。
Taming it on the side, taming on the side.
そう、ついでテイム。
Yeah, taming on the side.
霜降り肉取ってきた。
I got prime meat!
お、ナイスナイス。
Oh, nice, nice!
よいしょ。
Alright.
ついでテイムしたいのに。
Even though I want to tame it on the side.
ナイスついでテイム。
Nice side-taming.
なんかついでテイムできそうなやついねぇか。
Is there anything else we can tame on the side?
おしりは？
Where's the butt?
あ、なんかマンモス近づいて。
Ah, a mammoth is getting close...
ラムス？
Ovis?
行くかな？大丈夫かな？
Will it go? Will it be okay?
大丈夫。右側にいる。
It's okay. It's on the right side.
あいつ来ても足ちょっと遅いかな？
Even if that guy comes, is it a bit slow?
まあ、何とかなりそう。
Well, we can probably manage somehow.
え、入ってきた。やります？これ。
Oh, it came inside. Shall we do this?
まだ、まだいける？
Can we still go?
いや、まだ大丈夫。
No, it's still fine.
まだ、まだ大丈夫かな。
Still... It should still be okay.
はいよ。
Okay.
これでいいかな？
Is this good?
霜降りだけ入れたい、今。
I just want to put prime meat in right now.
なんか...
Something...
あー！来たー！
Ah! It's here!
ナイス！
Nice!
はい、おめでとうございます！
Yes, congratulations!
ミッション、え、あ、達成しました！
We cleared... oh, we cleared the mission!
おめでとうございます。
Congratulations.
よかったー！
Thank goodness!
じゃあ次はあれだよ。ギガノトも予約しといた方がいいんじゃないか？
Then next is that. Shouldn't we reserve the Giganoto too?
ね、ギガノトもこの調子で10時から狩るとなると...
Right, if we hunt the Giganoto starting at 10:00 at this rate...
10時だな。
10:00, right.
予約がすでに埋まっているところもありますので。
Some slots are already fully booked, so...
えーと、ムキロゼミッションのそちら情報確認し。
Please check the information for that Mukirose mission...
テキストにて申請をお願いいたします。
...and submit the request via text.
はい。
Okay.
それではおめでとうございます。引き続きがんばってください。
Well, congratulations. Please keep up the good work.
はい、おねがいします！
Yes, thank you!
ありがとう！
Thank you!
ありがとうございます。やったー！
Thank you. We did it!
やったー！
We did it!
22時からは...
From 22:00...
誰かポット持ってる？
Does anyone have a cryopod?
ポット持ってます、ビビ。
I have a cryopod, Bibi.
あ、じゃあ、おねがい。
Ah, then, please.
ムキロゼミッションを入れてほしいな。
I want you to sign us up for the Mukirose mission.
わかりました。
Got it.
ありがとう！
Thanks!
結構埋まってるかも。今ディスコード見たんですけど。
It might be quite full. I just checked Discord.
うん。
Yeah.
22時からAチームのムキロゼミッションやってて。
Team A is doing the Mukirose mission from 22:00.
はいはいはい。
I see, I see.
あ、でもクロスボウ無理、無理なのかな？ギガノト。
Ah, but is a crossbow impossible for the Giganoto?
クロスボウでもいいんだけど、一番はそのショットガンで麻酔弾を作って...
A crossbow is fine, but the best way is making tranquilizer darts with that shotgun...
やったほうが昏睡は早いんだよね。
...doing it that way makes taming go faster.
え、さっきショットガンのなんかいい設計図、手に入れてたよ。
Ah, we got a good shotgun blueprint earlier, didn't we?
あ、そうそう。あと弾が作れるかどうかかな。
Ah, right. Also, it's about whether we can craft the ammo.
あー、なるほどね。
Ah, I see.
だったらさ、ティラノを倒しに行こうか。
In that case, should we go defeat Rexes?
え、ティラノ倒すの、まだミッションあるっけ？
Wait, is there still a mission to defeat Rexes?
ティラノは絶対倒さないといけないミッションが、まだチームミッションで残ってるので。
The mission where we must defeat Rexes is still left in the team missions.
あ、じゃあ、これでいいかもね。
Oh, then this might be good.
全員でやって、ま、もしあれだったら、えーと...
We can do it with everyone, and if we need more, well...
20体テイムが、あと残り9体なんで、様々なやつをテイムするのが...
We only have 9 left for the 20-creature taming mission, so taming various creatures...
良いかなという感じですね。一応これ、繰り返しができるミッションなんで。
...would be good, I think. And this is a repeatable mission.
アークの世界にどんだけ恐竜がいるかよくわかってないんですけど。
I don't really know how many dinosaurs are in this ARK world, though.
ユニコーンのテイムは？
What about taming a unicorn?
あ、どう、どうですか？ユニコーンは。
Ah, how about that? A unicorn.
ユニコーンはね、全然湧かないね。
Unicorns rarely spawn, you know.
ま、だったら、あいつら、ラバ、ラバエレメントとか。
Well, then, maybe Lava Elementals?
ラバ行く？
Shall we go to Lava?
ラバエレメントもいいな。
Lava Elemental is good too.
ラバ、ティラノだね、今。
Lava and Rex right now.
ラバ行くのはいいと思うし、あれ作るから。ロケランあるから。
I think going to Lava is good. Since we can make rocket launchers.
ワンチャン、行くか。
Maybe we should go.
お前ティラノじゃなかった。
You weren't a Rex.
あれだったら、じゃ、ラバエレメンタルチーム4、ティラノガシガシチーム2かな。
In that case, maybe 4 for Lava Elemental, and 2 for beating Rexes?
お、ギガノトがカルノにやられてる。
Oh, the Giganoto is being attacked by a Carnotaurus.
なんか強い恐竜、結構手に入れたから、それでこう、駆け付けながら...
Since we got some strong dinosaurs, we can rush over with them...
という感じでどうでしょうか。
...how does that sound?
あ、やられた。
Ah, it died.
オッケー。
Okay.
オッケー。一回まず拠点、カリカリ、カリカリ拠点に戻り...
Okay. First, let's head back to our Karikari base...
戻りましょう。
Let's head back.
オッケー。
Okay.
ギガノトがお亡くなりになった。
The Giganoto has passed away.
あ、ギガノト。あ、ってことは多分あそこに何かいるわ。
Ah, the Giganoto. That means there's probably something over there.
あの、カルノがいたな、カルノが。
There was a Carnotaurus there.
あー、じゃあ、カルノ。
Ah, then the Carno.
カルノ、テイムしてないから、いい感じにアルゲンの中に入ってくんないかな、あいつ。
We haven't tamed a Carno yet, so I hope it lands in the Argent trap nicely.
ユウティラみたいに。
Like the Yuty.
ちょっとやってみます。
I'll give it a try.
やってみて。ばか、ばか、ばか、入って。
Give it a try. You dummy, get in there.
え、どれだ？なんかサイもいる。
Eh, which one is it? There's a Rhino too.
この下にもいた、ユウティラ。いっぱいいるね、よかった。
There was one down here too, a Yuty. There are so many, thank goodness.
これ、こいつ。
This, this guy.
そんなにがぶ飲みしたのに、喉渇いて。
Even though you drank so much, you're still thirsty?
こいつら結構すぐ喉渇くぞ。
These guys get thirsty really quickly.
飲みすぎだと思うんで、もうダメなのかお前。
I think you drank too much. Are you already done for?
飲みすぎだろ。
You drank too much.
飲みすぎだ。
Too much.
こっちだよ。
Over here.
なんかナメクジみたいなツノ生えてる恐竜ですか？
Is it that dinosaur with horn-like tentacles, like a slug?
そうそうそうそう。
Yes, yes, yes, yes.
こっちだよ。
Over here.
あ、ここもユウティか。
Ah, is this a Yuty too?
ユウティいっぱいです。
Lots of Yutys.
これ、フラフラしてたら落ちるんだよな。
If I sway around, I'll fall off.
いた！いた！
There! There!
あ、死ぬかも。え、何だこいつ？
Ah, I might die. Wait, what is this?
ちっちゃい血出ている。何で？
It's bleeding. Why?
大丈夫か？グリフィン。
Are you okay? Griffin.
やばい、よし、カバーしてあげる、カバー。
Oh no, okay, I'll cover you, cover.
いいよ、ビビ、逃げていいよ。
It's okay, Bibi, you can run away.
はい、逃げます。
Yes, I'm running away.
空の旅。
Journey through the sky.
はやく、はやく、はやく...
Hurry, hurry, hurry...
空の旅。はやく。
Journey through the sky. Hurry.
いや、よかった。ツェッペリン役に立つ。ナイス。
Wow, thank goodness. The Zeppelin is useful. Nice.
いや、よかった、ツェッペリン本当に。
Wow, thank goodness, the Zeppelin really.
よかった。本当に神。
Thank goodness. Truly a godsend.
アスレチックってさ、こんな感じだったっけ？
Was the obstacle course like this?
失敗だった気がする。10。
I feel like it was a failure. 10.
えっ、あ、アクロなんとかなんとかみたいなのいなかったっけかな？
Wait, wasn't there like an Acro-something here?
お返し？ / うん。
- Returned?
- Yeah.
ビビコが死んだ。ってことは、やっぱあのアルゲン罠にいるぞ、奴が。
Bibiko died. That means he is indeed in that Argen trap.
え？え、ビビコ？ビビコも、え、ビビそこいまいましたよ？
Eh? Bibiko? But Bibi was just right there.
ここは、あのバイソンがあります。
Here is that Bison.
あれ？
Huh?
バイソンもテイムできるかな、じゃあ。
Can we tame the Bison too, then?
できるん、あ、こっちじゃない。こっち。逆だ。
We can... Ah, not this way. This way. It's the other way.
なんとまだドードーに出会えていません。
Believe it or not, I still haven't met a Dodo.
つーかドードー... あ、お。飛べない。何で？
I mean, Dodo... Ah, oh. I can't fly. Why?
フック、フック、フック。
Hook, hook, hook...
グリフィン、ちょっと...
Griffin, wait...
まだドードーに出会えていない。この世界で一番最初に出会うべき...
I still haven't met a Dodo. In this world, the very first we should meet...
テイムできる生物のはずなのに、何故か出会えない。
...even though it's supposed to be a tameable creature, for some reason we can't find one.
ドードーに嫌い？ / な、何故？
- Disliked by Dodos?
- W-Why?
お前どこに、あ、膝が。もういなかったのか。
Where are you... Ah, my knee. Are they not here anymore?
バイソンもテイムできますか？
Can we tame Bisons too?
やったな！バイソンはいけるはず！
Alright! Bisons should be tameable!
パイソン、ビビここ。 / あ、パイソン、あ、ここ。
- Python, Bibi is here.
- Ah, Python, here.
いた。 / バイソンも、麻酔矢とかかな？
- Found it.
- Is it tranquilizer arrows for Bisons too?
パイソンここ入ってくれない？
Python, won't you go in here?
あ、待って待って。ビビこれでも、ここ入っちゃったら、ビビが抜けれないから。
Ah, wait, wait. If we go in here, Bibi can't get out.
稲先輩、あ、ビビじゃあそれを、押す。 / ビビです。
- Ina-senpai, ah, Bibi will push that.
- I'm Bibi.
うー、むずい、この。 / うー。
- Oof, this is hard.
- Oof.
あ、できた、できた。 / ナイス。
- Ah, I did it, I did it.
- Nice.
あ、これで麻酔矢打てばいいのか。
Ah, so I can just shoot tranquilizer arrows now.
あ、待って、ちょっと待って。
Ah, wait, wait a second.
鉄ケージって、どうしたらいいんだこれ？なんかも分かんない、バグってる。
Iron cage, what should I do with this? I don't know, it's bugged.
何か作業台か何かに、入れてませんでしたっけ？
Didn't you put it in a smithy or something?
そうだね。作業台に入れて使うやつだね。
Right. It's something you put in the smithy to use.
バイソンは何を食べるんですかね？ベリー？
What do Bisons eat? Berries?
ベリーかな？ベリーと肉、一緒に一応入れといたら安全かも。 / あ、そうですね。
- Berries, maybe? Putting berries and meat together might be safe.
- Ah, right.
顔かわいい、パイソン。
Python has a cute face.
つぶらな瞳。 / こっちだよ、これ。
- Round eyes.
- Over here, this.
セメント。 / めっちゃ動く。
- Cement.
- It moves a lot.
置いてきたティラノって、ずっとあの場にいるのかな？
Will the Rex we left behind stay there forever?
あ、ティラノはね、回収した。 / あ、ありがとう。
- Ah, the Rex, I retrieved it.
- Ah, thank you.
痛っ！あ、近づいちゃだめよ。
Ouch! Ah, don't get too close.
じゃあそのティラノとかを使って、ティラノ討伐しに行こうかな。
Then maybe we can use that Rex to go hunt Rexes.
ビビ、どうしよう。ビビもさ、ボスみたいなのやってきたら？
Bibi, what should we do? What if Bibi goes and does something like a boss too?
さっき、見てないじゃん。 / 呼んで、欲しい。
- We didn't see it earlier.
- Please call me.
そうですね。
Right.
もうティラノ狩りしてくるからさ、大きいのに言ってみよう。
I'm going to go hunt Rexes, so let's call a big one.
ありがとうございます。 / はい、ありがとうございます。
- Thank you very much.
- Yes, thank you very much.
あ、待って、グリフィン、ちょっと呼んで欲しい。
Ah, wait, Griffin, I want you to call it.
グリフィン、ちょっとこっち来て。
Griffin, come over here a bit.
えっと、セメント。
Um, cement.
ティラノのサドルいるよね、じゃあ。
Then we need a Rex saddle, right?
そうですね、ティラノのサドルがいる。ティラノのサドル...
Right, we need a Rex saddle. A Rex saddle...
あ、大きいやつ何に行く？
Ah, which big one are we going for?
ラバエレメンタルですかね？ / あ、できたできた。
- Is it Lava Elemental?
- Ah, I did it, I did it.
ラバエレメンタル、めちゃめちゃフィールドが狭くて、恐竜がなかなか出せないのね。
The Lava Elemental arena is super narrow, so it's hard to bring dinosaurs in.
だから、ティラノがでかいやつだと、ちょっと厳しいか。いや、まぁ行くだけ行って、囮になってもらう感じかな。
So a huge Rex might be tough. Well, we could just go and have it act as a decoy.
ふむふむ。何が出せたら一番いいんだろう、ちょっと待ってくださいね。
I see. I wonder what's best to bring out, wait a second.
ちっちゃいやつが、基本はロケランぶっぱなんだよね。
For small ones, basically we just blast them with rocket launchers.
はい、はい、はい。
Yeah, yeah, yeah.
そうそうそう。で、ロケランの弾がちょっと足りなくて今。
Yeah. And we are a bit short on rocket launcher ammo right now.
ビビ、なんか生肉持ってる？
Bibi, do you have raw meat?
あ、えっと、ロケランの弾を生成してもらうのは、フブキ先輩にお願いして大丈夫ですか？ / オッケーオッケー。
- Ah, um, can we ask Fubuki-senpai to craft the rocket launcher ammo?
- Okay, okay.
って、ってなったら、えっと、自分のこのパイロンかな？
If so, um, my Pyron, I guess?
こっち？メジョベリー。
This way? Mejoberry.
パイロか、あと一応、パイロ、多分パイロがいれば大丈夫な気がする。 / 了解です。
- Pyro, and maybe, Pyro is probably enough.
- Got it.
で、プラス、他の人でティラノの討伐を、まず最優先でチームミッションクリアしたくて。 / テイム？
- And plus, I want others to prioritize the Rex hunt to clear the team mission first.
- Tame?
それをちょっと強い恐竜に乗って、できればやってほしいのと。
I'd like you to ride a strong dinosaur and do that if possible.
トワ先輩が、あのシートに貼ってくれたやつ今チャットに貼ったんですけど。
Towa-senpai pasted what she put on the sheet in the chat.
テイム簡単な生き物ってやつを乗っけたんで、それをちょっとテイムしてもらいつつ。
I've listed some easy-to-tame creatures, so let's tame those...
数を稼ごうかなという作戦でいかがでしょうか？
...and boost our numbers. What do you think of this strategy?
オッケー。 / オッケー。よし。
- Okay.
- Okay. Alright.
とりあえず1回ティラノ行ってきちゃうね。 / お願い。ありがとう。
- I'll go hunt Rexes first.
- Please. Thank you.
はーい。 / ティラノのサドルを作って、こっちも何人か行いたい気持ち。
- Okay.
- I want to make a Rex saddle and have some of us go there too.
1回アスレチック見ていきたいかも。
I'd like to check out the obstacle course first.
アスレチックね。じゃあ、ラバ行く人？ / ラバ行きます。
- Obstacle course. So, who's going to the Lava?
- I'm going to the Lava.
イナちゃんにも来てもらおうかな。 / はい。
- I'll ask Ina-chan to come too.
- Okay.
あ、でもラバ行きたい。ラバも行きたい。ラバ行こう。 / じゃあ、ラバ行きましょう。
- Ah, but I want to go to the Lava too. Let's go to Lava.
- Let's go to the Lava, then.
だったら、みんな各自、えっと、グラップリングフックっていうのを作ってほしいのね。
Then, everyone, please make a grappling hook for yourselves.
グラップリングフック。 / そう。
- Grappling hook.
- Yes.
うわ、防虫剤とかいるかな？
Wow, do we need insect repellent?
蜘蛛とかムカデとかがめちゃめちゃいて、毒になったりとかするのよね
There are tons of spiders and centipedes, and they poison you.
へぇー
Heh~
うん
Yeah.
ま、でも、パイロいたら大丈夫かな？攻撃したら
But maybe it's fine if we have Pyro? If we attack.
ふむふむ
Mhm, mhm.
グラップリングフック、セメント...
Grappling hook... cement...
行く人は各自グラップリングフックを作ってほしい
I'd like everyone who is going to make their own grappling hook.
了解です
Roger that.
グラップリングフック？
Grappling hook?
そう、で、多分石がすごい今足りなくて、セメントとかも作れないから、ちょっと石とかも必要かも
Yes, and we probably don't have enough stone right now, so we can't make cement either. We might need some stone.
あ、じゃあ
Ah, then...
えっと、風真、一旦ちょっと、アンキロと、あれで、アルゲンで行ってきます。石集め。
Uh, Kazama will go with Ankylo and... the Argent for now. To gather stone.
うん、石が圧倒的に足りないね
Yeah, we're definitely short on stone.
やべ、アルゲンどこだ？あ、おーい。
Shoot, where's my Argent? Ah, hey.
もしもし、あ、あった。500あった、500あった。
Hello? Oh, there it is. There was 500, there was 500.
石か。今石取るか、じゃあ。
Stone? Should I go gather some stone now, then?
うん。
Yeah.
もしもし、お前はサドルがついていますか？ついている。よし。
Hello, do you have a saddle on? You do. Good.
キチン、キチン、ケラチン...
Chitin, chitin, keratin...
え、これ... なんだ、キチン...
Eh, this... what is it, chitin...
リングフック...なんか武器とか、他に持っ...作っといた方がいい、矢、みたいなものとか...
Grappling hook... like, are there any weapons or other things we should... make? Like arrows...
あとはギリースーツさえ持っていれば大丈夫かな。道中はパイロでやりつつ、ボス戦もパイロで行きつつ、
Other than that, as long as you have a ghillie suit, we should be fine. We'll use Pyro on the way, and also for the boss battle.
で、えっと、アスレチックみたいなとこがあるのよね、ちょっと。
And, uh, there's a parkour-like area, a bit.
道中、穴が空いてたりとか、そういうとこがあるから、そこはグラップリングフックっていうフックショットで
There are holes along the way, so we'll use a hookshot called a grappling hook...
使って、使っていくから、そこでワンチャン事故って死ぬ可能性もある。
to get across, so there's a chance we might accidentally die there.
了解です。うん。
Got it. Yeah.
あ、バイソン！
Ah, Bison!
これ、やることない人、今やることなくて困ったような人がいたら、あの、焼き肉を大量に作っておいてもらいたいかな。
If anyone has nothing to do right now and is bored, I'd like you to make a bunch of cooked meat.
右の作業台からグラップルフック...
The grapple hook from the right workbench...
あ、そう、この作業台！
Ah, yes, this workbench!
いけるいける。
We can do it, we can do it.
これ、これ、これ。お肉500個くらい冷蔵庫に入れてるよ。
This, this, this. I put about 500 meat in the fridge.
わあ、ありがとう！ありがたい！
Wow, thank you! Thank you so much!
バイソンテイムできました！
I successfully tamed a Bison!
ナイス！
Nice!
ナイス！ナイス！ナイス！
Nice! Nice! Nice!
助かりすぎる。
You're a lifesaver.
バーンさんが...バーンさん乗っちゃった。
Bern-san... I accidentally rode Bern-san.
キンテツ？
Kintetsu?
ちょっとバーンさん避けますね、トワ様。一旦。
I'll move Bern-san out of the way, Towa-sama. Just for now.
あ、ごめん、ごめん、ごめん。
Ah, sorry, sorry, sorry.
あ、これ、これ攻撃しちゃダメね。今捕まえようとしてる。
Ah, don't attack this. I'm trying to catch it now.
あ、はーい。
Ah, okay.
オッケー、終わった。これ終わったでしょ。
Okay, finished. This is done, right?
修理できねえ。
Can't repair it.
じゃ、ちょっと石取りに行ってきます。
Then, I'm going to gather some stone for a bit.
はーい、おーい。
Okay~ hey~.
あ、焼き肉も大丈夫だな。
Ah, the cooked meat is fine too.
10時には出発したいかな。
I'd like to set off by 10 o'clock.
セメ、セメントとインゴットがない。セメントどれ？
Ce- Cement and ingots are missing. Which one is cement?
あ、待ってよ、セメント入れる。
Ah, wait, I'll put cement in.
インゴットは燃やしているはずですね。えっと、炉の中にある。
The ingots should be smelting. Uh, they're in the furnace.
セメント作業台の中入れた。
I put the cement into the workbench.
ありがとう。
Thank you.
足りなかったらちょっと待ってね。
If it's not enough, please wait a bit.
ライフルも弾がないんだよね
We don't have rifle ammo either.
弾は結構いるよね？
We need quite a bit of ammo, right?
そうだね、で、火薬がいるんだけど、その火薬を作るのに結構時間かかっちゃって
Yeah, and we need gunpowder, but making gunpowder takes a lot of time.
はいはいはい
Right, right.
なるほど
I see...
火薬、火薬... 待って、私水ないわ、1回ちょっとお水
Gunpowder, gunpowder... Wait, I don't have water. Let me get some water first.
グラップリングフックいっぱい作るか、じゃあ
Then I guess I'll make a lot of grappling hooks.
少数精鋭の方がいいんだったら、ござる置いてってくれて大丈夫ですよ
If you prefer a small, elite group, you can leave Gozaru behind.
うーん、とりあえず作れるだけ作ってみるか
Hmm, let's try making as many as we can for now.
あ、クロスボウ
Ah, a crossbow.
あ、でも30、30いけそうだな、えーっと
Ah, but we can make 30... It looks like we can make 30, let's see.
これ、消費式なんだ
Oh, these are single-use.
あ、そして石が消えた、ついに
Ah, and the stone is gone, finally.
石、あ、でも持ってきた。水筒、水筒めっちゃ持ってった方がいい説
Stone... Oh, but I brought some. Maybe I should bring a lot of canteens.
ねえ、拠点の近くって石湧いてますか？
Hey, does stone spawn near the base?
どうだろう、いっぱい湧いてるかな？
I wonder, does a lot spawn?
石って何で取ったらいいんやったっけ？恐竜ありましたよね、何か
What was the best way to gather stone again? We had a dinosaur for that, right?
あ、恐竜はね、こっちでやってて、今
Ah, we are using the dinosaur for that over here right now.
あ、そうなんだ。じゃあ大丈夫ですか？石
Oh, I see. Then is it okay? The stone.
やってるんだけど、手掘りでも必要かも
We're working on it, but we might still need some hand-harvesting.
手掘り了解。すぐ喉渇くからな
Hand-harvesting, Roger. Since you get thirsty so fast.
アスレ、や、アスレやるんだったら、ござる行った方がいいんじゃないのか？
If we're doing the parkour run, shouldn't Gozaru go?
ねえ、せっかく、せっかくならね、使う機会、ま、1人20、20本あれば行けるかな
Since we have the chance, with about 20... 20 per person, we should be fine?
ま、最悪、パイルでも正直、ぴょんぴょんって行けば行けないことはないんだけど
I mean, worst case, we can get through by jumping around even with just a pile, though.
はいはい。全然やってみてもらって大丈夫ですよ。そしたらござるはアスレチックに行ってきます
Right, right. You can definitely try that. In that case, Gozaru will go to the athletic run.
あ、なるほど。そしたら俺はアスレチックに行く
Ah, I see. Then I'll go to the athletic run.
いいんね。アスレチックも助かる
Nice. An athletic run is helpful too.
じゃあ、これ今、私何すればいい？石集めればいいか？
Then, what should I do now? Should I gather stone?
グラップリングフックを作れるだけ今、この作業台で作れたら嬉しいけど、な、何が足りないんだ？
It'd be great if we could make as many grappling hooks as possible at this smithy, but what are we missing?
何が足りない？何足りない？今セメントか？
What's missing? What's missing? Is it cementing paste now?
えーっと、多分、今んとこ石がめちゃめちゃ足りなくて
Let's see... Probably, for now, we are really short on stone.
石、オッケーオッケー。鉄は燃やせばある感じですか？
Stone, okay, okay. Do we have metal as long as we melt it?
鉄はね、全然ある、いっぱいある
We have plenty of metal, a lot.
オッケー。じゃあ、落としちゃう。石が圧倒的に足りないかも
Okay. I'll drop off some then. We're overwhelmingly short on stone.
え、石って、自分でカンカンしないとダメ？いや、今アンキロで集めてます
Eh, for stone, do we have to hand-mine it? No, I'm gathering with an Ankylo right now.
あーん、ちょっと、掴めないのやめて。やめて。あつい、ここ
Ah, stop not being able to grab it. Stop. It's hot here.
アンキロって、てかアンキロって1人1体だから、実はいるんだよね。報酬取りに行けば
Since we only have one Ankylo per person, we actually need them if we go get the rewards.
あ、チーム1体じゃなかったんだ、勘違い
Ah, so it wasn't one per team, my mistake.
じゃなかったかな、多分。あ、でもどうだったっけ？
Probably not, I think. Wait, how was it again?
あ、報酬のドエディ、ドエディ、ドエディ
Ah, Doedi from the rewards! Doedi, Doedi!
ドエディクスもいたよね、確かにドエディクス。冷蔵庫の中に
There was a Doedicurus too, right? Indeed, Doedi. Inside the fridge.
いたはず。いたはず。
Should be there. Should be there.
ドエディの方が石がいっぱい取れる。なにー！
Doedi gathers much more stone. What?!
じゃあ、変えよう
Then, let's swap.
なんか、ずっと暑くて。今セメント入れたけど、これ作れるかな...あ、ごめん、し、知らない
I've been hot this whole time. I put the cementing paste in, I wonder if we can craft this... Ah, sorry, I didn't know.
頭痛い、と思ってたら
I thought I had a headache...
え、どこだ？えーっとね、今は、イマが、イマがめちゃめちゃテイムしてくれてんのかな？
Eh, where is it? Let's see, is Ima doing a lot of taming right now?
あ、こいつで石って削れんのか？こいつは石は削れないのか？
Ah, can this guy harvest stone? This guy can't harvest stone?
ねむ、別の物もテイムします、なんか、やってみます
Nemu, I'll tame something else too, I'll try doing that.
近くに何かあったら。オッケー、ありがとう
If there's something nearby. Okay, thank you.
視界が、もやしすぎて、テイムに変えれない。あいましたぶん、それ
My vision is too blurry, I can't switch to taming. That one is impossible.
テレポーターに変えれない。やばい。なるほど
I can't switch to teleporter. Oh no. I see.
これしか、私、視界悪すぎ、なんでこんな視界悪い？
This is... My vision is too bad, why is my vision so bad?
鉄分恐竜いるんでしたっけ？服脱げば？
Do we have a metal-harvesting dinosaur? Why don't you take off your clothes?
えーっと。じゃあ恐竜で集めた方がいいんか？石
Let's see... Then is it better to gather stone with a dinosaur?
やばい、見えなすぎ。こいつテイムできんのかな？
Oh no, I can't see a thing. I wonder if we can tame this one?
いやー。なんでこんな暑い？
No way. Why is it so hot?
エアコンで使うか。やばい、めちゃやばいとこで疲れてるアルゲン、やめて
Should we use an air conditioner? Oh no, the Argentavis is exhausted in a really bad place, stop.
石待ち、石待ちます。やばい、石待ってます
Waiting for stone, waiting for stone. Oh no, waiting for stone.
動けない、帰れない、パニック。ちょっと待って。落ち着いて
I can't move, I can't go back, panic. Wait a minute. Calm down.
落ち着いて帰る。ありがとう
Calm down and go back. Thank you.
荷物重すぎ、荷物重すぎ。動けない
My inventory is too heavy, too heavy. I can't move.
じゃあ、あと
Then, also...
え？なんで？これ降りもしないし
Eh? Why? I can't even dismount.
え？なんで？動けない、アンキロ
Eh? Why? I can't move, Ankylo.
え、やばい、ちょっ、ござるが落ちてどうすんねん。ちょっとござるが落ちてどうすんねん
Eh, oh no, wait... Gozaru fell off, what should we do? Gozaru fell off, what should we do?
ちょっと。なんか着地もできなかったんです、ござる
Wait a sec... I couldn't even land properly, Gozaru.
え、Doediどうしたんですか？
Eh, what happened to the Doedi?
乗れる。
You can ride it.
お待たせ。
Sorry to keep you waiting.
ちょっと拠点出た...スタミナ切れてるくせに、下に降りれなかった。
I was at the base, and even though I was out of stamina, I couldn't land.
拠点で石取り合...
Collecting stones at the base...
石、でも言うてそんなだな。
But honestly, there's not that much stone.
ビビも人手だったから、1500ぐらい...
Since Bibi was helping too, about 1500...
あ、嘔吐し、ここで。何このデバフ？
Ah, vomiting here. What is this debuff?
Blueprint...あ、なるほど。
Blueprint... Ah, I see.
なんでこのデバフ？え、何これ？
Why this debuff? Eh, what is this?
オッケー。
Okay.
ちょっとやばい、視界不良すぎて、前に真っ直ぐ行けない。
This is bad, my vision is so blurry that I can't go straight.
熱中症とかになってない？それ。
Aren't you getting heatstroke?
水は満タンなんですけどね。えーっと。
My water is full, though. Let's see...
これ、石まだ必要ですか？
Do we still need stone?
石あると嬉しいかな？
It would be nice to have some stone.
あ、でも、ビビはテイムの方がいい、嬉しいかも。
Ah, but maybe Bibi should tame, that would be nice.
テイム？はいはい。
Taming? Okay.
何が良いかな？オヴィラプトル？
What should we tame? Oviraptor?
ドエディ？ドエディかな？
Doedi? Maybe Doedicurus?
ビビ、トワのテイムしてるから大丈夫だよ、それ。
Bibi, I'm taming Towa's, so it's fine.
落ち着いてやっちゃって。
Just take your time and do it.
あ、オッケー。じゃあこれで石取ってきてほしい、こいつで。
Ah, okay. Then I want you to go get stone with this one.
わかりました。視界が悪い。
Got it. My vision is bad.
ドエディで、なんか後ろから追っかけ回されてる。
With Doedi... I'm being chased by something from behind!
石を持って帰りたいだけなのよ、私。
I just want to bring some stone back!
これ頼む、頼む。殺さないで。
Please, please. Don't kill me.
インゴットが足りないから、インゴット...
Since we don't have enough ingots, ingots...
た、たたたたたた！
Ta-ta-ta-ta-ta-ta!
石のエレベーターが！やめて！
The stone elevator! Stop!
え！？
Eh!?
よいしょ。何これ？
Phew. What is this?
うーん、何も信じられない。
I can't believe anything anymore.
いろは！
Iroha!
死んでしまった。石持って帰れないかも。
I died. I might not be able to bring the stone back.
アルゲンもロストするかも。もう無理。
I might lose the Argentavis too. It's impossible.
乗せすぎだ！絶対乗せすぎだ！
You overloaded it! Definitely overloaded!
え、なんか知らないけど...
Eh, I don't know why, but...
飛びます。降りないと飛ばされますよ。
I'm flying. If you don't get off, you'll be blown away.
視界が死ぬほど悪くて、何も見つけられない。
My vision is terribly bad, I can't find anything.
熱中症の可能性がある、ぼやぼやって。右下に何か出てない？
There's a chance of heatstroke. Is there something on the bottom right?
白い丸いやつが出てて。
There's a white round icon showing.
それは一定時間、川の水の中にいないと解消されないから、そっち優先の方がいいかも。
That won't go away unless you stay in river water for a while, so prioritizing that might be better.
なるほど。水の中。
I see. In the water.
待って。すぐいっぱいになっちゃう。
Wait, it gets full so quickly.
インゴットが足りないのかな？
Are we short on ingots?
体びしょびしょにして行きたい。
I want to get completely soaked.
7番で出して...
Bring it out with number 7...
これで？これ入れる判定なのかな？水に。
With this? Does this count as being in the water?
どっちなんだ？引っかかった。
Which one is it? I got stuck.
すごい。世界変わる、これ、ドエディ。
This changes everything, this Doedi.
ドエディ？うん、一発で1000とかよ。
Doedi? Yeah, like 1000 in one hit.
じゃあござるのアンキロ、もう意味ないかもしれない。
Then my Ankylo might be useless now.
置いてきていいレベル。
To the point where we can just leave it behind.
だめだ。
No good.
あ、とか言ってたら、今度は...
Ah, having said that, now...
水、めっちゃ石出てきますよ、これ。
Water... there are tons of stones coming out here.
今は持ってるな。盛り癖が。
I have it now. I have a habit of exaggerating.
いいですね。
Nice.
転がった方が早い？
Is it faster to roll?
転がった方が早いらしいぞ。
Apparently it's faster to roll.
へえ、転がるってどうやるの？
Oh, how do you roll?
死んだ。
I died.
死んだ！？いやいや、ちょっと。
You died!? No way, wait a minute.
これ、どうやって倒すの？
How do we defeat this?
どうしたらいいの、これ？
What should I do about this?
ドエディさんも草食ですか？
Are Doedis herbivores too?
ドエディさん、草食だ。
Doedis are herbivores.
これで、ボーラ使って寝かせて。
With this, use a bola to put it to sleep.
ドエディさん、木の実食べてるよね。
Doedis eat berries, right?
食べてる、食べてる。
Yes, they do.
転べる？やばい。
Can it roll? This is bad.
飛んでる。やばい。
It's flying. Oh no.
しゃがめない。どうしよう。
I can't crouch. What should I do?
ということで、なんと22時なんですね。
So, it's actually 10 PM.
助けてください。
Please help me.
しゃがめないし、水入っても治らないんですけど。
I can't crouch, and getting in the water isn't curing it.
家の横の川ならいける？
Will the river next to the house work?
家の横の川？え、何もないんですけど。
The river next to the house? There's nothing there.
外でもどこでも、川の中ならいけるはず。
Outside or anywhere, as long as it's in the river, it should work.
そう。こっちかな。
I see. Is it this way?
しばらくかかるよ、熱中症治すの。
It takes a while to cure heatstroke.
そんなにかかる？うん、かかる。
Does it take that long? Yeah, it does.
置いていって、ドエディじゃなくて。
Just leave it, not the Doedi.
石来た？
Did the stone arrive?
戻ってます。でも、あれ見つかりました？
I'm on my way back. But did you find that?
ギガノト。ギガノト。
Giganotosaurus. Giganotosaurus.
ギガノトはちょっと今探したんですけど... wagon_missing
I just searched for the Giga, but...
もう23分まで もっともっといっぱいで
It was already full up to the 23-minute mark...
あ、なるほどね
Ah, I see.
多分 ござるたちが入れら後 パパパパッてみんな入れたみたいで
I think after Gozaru and the others put theirs in, everyone else quickly did too...
23分まで待ってました
so we were waiting until the 23rd minute.
おけ
Okay.
多分無理気味で あと1個何でしょう？チームの…
It seems almost impossible now. And what was the other team mission?
オッケー
Okay.
その、ラ…ラバ
That... Lava...
ラバ・エレメンタルと あとは あ、あれ
Lava Elemental, and also... ah, that one.
オッケー
Okay.
入んない。肉？
It won't go in. Meat?
かな？
I wonder?
ですかね
I guess so.
でもマジでちょっとやめて、本当に
But seriously, please stop, for real.
一応今石いっぱい集めてます
For now, I'm gathering a lot of stones.
オッケー。あ、でもそろそろ帰ってきてもらっていいよ
Okay. Ah, but you can come back now.
オッケー
Okay.
戻って、もう戻ってきました。これドエディ入れないよ
I'm already back. I can't put this in Doedicurus.
ドエディから石出してもらって こっちでも入れてきてほしいかな
I want you to take the stones out of Doedicurus and put them in here.
あ、多すぎる
Ah, it's too much.
ちょっと待って
Wait a second.
おっと
Whoops.
やばい この場所の脱水症状タイム早すぎ 笑う
Oh my, the dehydration rate here is too fast, lol.
オッケー
Okay.
ちょっとずつでいいや ちょっとずつで
A little bit at a time is fine, just a little bit.
膝が割れる 膝が
My knees are splitting, my knees...
ござる これどこに入れたらいいでしょうか？ここ？
Gozaru, where should I put this? Here?
あ、その、旋盤の中で
Ah, inside the fabricator.
はい
Okay.
膝、膝が
My knees, my knees are...
石、旋盤の中？
Stones in the fabricator?
オッケー
Okay.
テラポまだテイムしてないんですよね？
We haven't tamed a Terror Bird yet, right?
ちょっとミッション見よう
Let's see the missions.
あ、いたいたいたいた
Ah, there they are.
え？
Eh?
どこいったっけ？今出したの。あれ？
Where did it go? The one I just released. Huh? Trumpet?
これだけあればいけるかな
I wonder if we can do it with just this.
石、持ってきました
I brought the stones.
はい、ありがとう。ということで、行きますか
Yes, thank you. So, shall we go?
ラバグミはじゃあ、一旦ボイチャにいて
As for the Lava group, please stay in voice chat for now.
はい
Okay.
ボイチャに
In voice chat.
きた
They're here.
やばい、なんか咳が出ない
Oh no, I can't cough properly.
あ、できた！
Ah, I did it!
あ、なんだこれ。いいですね
Ah, what is this? Nice.
テイム
Tamed.
テイマー
Tame more.
なんで？
Why?
やった
Hooray.
お前
You...
あ、水、水、やばい。石、持って帰れないから
Ah, water, water, oh no. Since I can't carry stones back...
どうせお前すぐ諦めるやろ。水、飲む。知ってんだぞ、こっちは
You'll give up soon anyway. Drink water. I know it.
ほら
See?
来いよ。なんだこいつ、結構根性ある。雪山の時は
Come on. What, this guy actually has some guts. Back at the snowy mountain...
そんなことなかったのに、なぜ？お前、ここのアルゲンは根性がある
It wasn't like that. Why? You, the Argentavis here have guts.
根性ありあり
Totally full of guts.
水飲む、水飲む
Drinking water, drinking water.
なんでこういう時に限って お前は根性があるのか
Why is it only at times like this that you have guts?
食べる
Eat.
えっと、どうする、どうする、どうする、どうする
Um, what to do, what to do, what to do, what to do...
やあ、拠点の近くの雪山のアルゲン すぐ昨日捕まえようとしたら
Yesterday when I tried to catch the Argentavis on the snowy mountain near our base,
やっぱりやーめたされたんですけど
it was like, "Never mind," and left.
今いるところのアルゲン 執着心が強すぎて、う
But the Argentavis where I am now has too much obsession, ugh.
個体差なのか
Is it individual variation?
あ、無事回収できました。よかった
Ah, successfully retrieved it. Thank goodness.
悲しみの
Sorrowful...
ボス、みんな行っちゃった？
Did everyone go to the boss?
あ、ボス行ってきたな
Ah, they went to the boss.
あ、いや、いいですよ、ござるは。一旦これで、あ、あ、行きます
Ah, no, I'm fine, Gozaru is. For now, with this, I'll go.
おっけー、おっけー
Okay, okay.
ひなが、ひながVCが大丈夫かな？
Is Hina's voice chat okay?
あ、大丈夫です。今ちょっと、なんかテイムしやすい奴ら、ちょっとテイムしてます
Ah, yes, it's fine. Right now, I'm taming some easy-to-tame creatures.
オッケー。うちらもね、結構テイムできてるよ、今
Okay. We've also tamed quite a lot now.
もう、3...
Already 3...
6体ぐらいテイムしたかな
We tamed about 6, I think.
え、ちょっと待って！今ここで体が弱くなるのはホントにダメ！ちょっと！
Wait, wait a second! Getting weak right here is really bad! Hold on!
やめてって言ってるじゃん！今はダメだって！着地させて！
I said stop! Not now! Let me land!
熱中症になったし！助けて！
And I got heatstroke! Help!
大丈夫？
Are you okay?
ちょっとホントに、ほ、お前
Seriously, you...
死体がある。よし
There's a corpse. Alright.
もうよく分からん、もう全てにおいて。あ、避けるな
I don't even know anymore, in every way. Ah, don't avoid it.
あ、なんかテイムしてないの
Ah, something not tamed...
何だろう
What is it?
掴めないし、クソ。全然掴めない、お前。しかも酸素ゲージがゼロだから戻ってきて
I can't grab it, damn it. I can't grab you at all. Also, my oxygen gauge is at zero, so come back.
はぁー！
Phew!
膝の皿が、バリバリバリバリ
My kneecaps are cracking...
よし
Alright.
なぜ、お前は
Why are you...
微妙にブロントサウルスも、いて。あ
Subtly, there's also a Brontosaurus. Ah.
あと3匹だ。あと3匹
Three more left. Three more.
すごい、ナイス
Amazing, nice.
まずテイムできてないのか、どっちか
First of all, is it not tamed, or which one?
分かんないよね
I don't know.
そうですね
Yeah, that's true.
もうなんか、適当に...
At this point, I'm just kind of...
適当に行くしかなくなっている
I have no choice but to go randomly.
もうリスナーさんに任せてる、もうこれ
I'm just leaving it up to the viewers now.
これみんなの見て、これどれ...
I'll look at everyone's comments and... wait...
あれ？待って。ティラノって倒しました？まだゼロだけどこれ
Wait, did we defeat the Rex? It's still at zero.
そう、ティラノね、いないんだよ。今探し、探し中
Yeah, there are no Rexes. I'm searching for one right now.
探し中なのと、あとテイムに寄り道しちゃってる
I'm searching, but also getting distracted by taming.
あ、了解です、了解です
Ah, got it, got it.
であれば、ティラノの方手伝った方がいいか。チームミッションの方が大きい
In that case, should I help with the Rex? Since it's a team mission.
ティラノの方が... あれ、イナ、ティラノ見つけたらやれる？
The Rex is... Wait, Ina, if you find a Rex, can you handle it?
私だけで？ですか？
By myself?
トワ、トワも今ワイバーン乗ってやってるよね
Towa is also riding a Wyvern and hunting them, right?
あ、じゃあ見つかったら...
Ah, then if I find one...
痛い痛い、そう、見つかったら
Ouch! Yeah, if you find one...
見つかったらどんどんやってって
If you find any, just keep defeating them.
やんないと、多分間に合わなくてね、1人じゃ
Otherwise, we probably won't make it in time on our own.
1人じゃ10匹見つけられん
One person can't find 10 of them.
これだよ
This is it.
あれ？テイム？
Wait, taming?
手伝った方がよさそうであれば...
If it seems better for me to help...
君の名は...
Your name is...
忘れる前に手伝いたい
I want to help before I forget.
パラケラテリウム
Paraceratherium.
え、これアクロ？
Eh, is this an Acro?
またこれ騙された！
Fooled again!
テイムに何回騙してくれんだ、お前マジで！
How many times are you gonna fool me, seriously!
騙された、やばい
I got fooled, oh my gosh.
もうこれ騙された、もうこれ。マジで顔つきティラノすぎるだろ、お前。違うからそれ、やめて
Fooled again. Seriously, your face looks way too much like a Rex! You're not one, stop it!
顔つきがティラノすぎるわ
Its face looks way too much like a Rex.
テラバードやめて、マジで
Terabirds, stop it, seriously.
テラバード何？
What is it with Terabirds?
テラバードやめて、本当に。邪魔だから君
Terabirds, stop it, really. You're in my way, buddy.
マジ笑う
So funny.
人違いで何も悪いことしてないのに殺されたってコメント書かれてる
Someone commented, "Killed due to mistaken identity even though they did nothing wrong."
仕方ない、ごめん。だけど仕方ないね
Can't help it, sorry. But it is what it is.
出てきた方が悪い。おいでテラバ
It's their fault for showing up. Come here, Terabird.
なんなんだよ、お前。本当にいい加減にしなさい！
What's your problem? Seriously, cut it out!
戦闘要員も持ってないんだから
I don't even have my combat tames with me.
すみません、ティラノサウルスさん。お願いします。あの、殺させてください。本当にお願いします
Excuse me, Mr. T-Rex. Please. Let me kill you, please.
一回終了
First round done.
あ、やべ。えっと...
Ah, shoot. Let's see...
火山地帯？
Volcano area?
火山地帯行きます
I'll go to the volcano area.
欲しいな、あの...
I want that...
何だっけ？キャラコンする... アクロバ、アクロバティックじゃなくて...
What was it? The one that does character control... acrobatic, not acrobatic...
これか？
Is it this?
お前も違うじゃないか、くそ！
You're not it either, damn it!
騙され続け...
Kept getting fooled...
喜ばせられてがっかりさせられる。何なんだよ、こいつ。喜びがない
Getting my hopes up just to be disappointed. What's up with this guy? No joy.
喜びがないよ
There is no joy.
ハチワレもぶち切れだよ、これ
Even Hachiware would be furious at this.
喜びがない
There is no joy.
うわ、すご
Whoa, incredible.
え、でも待って。なんかミッションでもらったやつって、あれチームで1体でしたっけ？
Eh, wait. For the one we got from the mission, was it one per team?
え、みんなで1体じゃない？
Wait, isn't it one for everyone?
え、みんな1人1体？
Eh, one for each person?
だと思う、うん、だと思う
I think so, yeah, I think so.
ワイバーンじゃあ、もらってないかも。もらってこようかな
Then I might not have gotten a Wyvern yet. Maybe I should go get one?
うん
Yeah.
で、ティラノやろう
And then let's do the Rex.
えっと、気が遠くなるな、これ
Let's see... This is overwhelming.
逃げるな
Don't run away.
あ、お水
Ah, water.
ビーバー混入？
Beavers mixed in?
いや、ビーバー多すぎて無理だろ、あれ
No, there are too many Beavers, that's impossible.
捕獲中の恐竜たちが、1人1体なのか、チームで1体なのか、ちょっとごちゃごちゃになってて...
I'm getting a bit confused whether the dinosaurs we are taming are one per person or one per team...
わからん
I don't know.
ワイバーン
Wyvern.
いっぱいあるからね、難しい
There are so many, it's hard.
邪魔、こいつ
You're in my way, buddy.
キリヤン？キリヤンどこ飛ぶの？
Kiriyan? Where is Kiriyan flying?
バイリンガルで喋ってるのにすごいね、イナちゃんは
It's amazing how you speak bilingually, Ina-chan.
そうだ！イナ先輩、ごめんね
That's right! Ina-senpai, sorry...
英語で喋れなくて...
...for not being able to speak English...
お上手お上手
Oh, you're good! You're good!
いやいやいやいや、ばか
No, no, no, no. Silly...
なんというか、日本語の練習
It's like, Japanese practice.
えらい
Great job!
できるからね
We can do it.
でもなんか、ARK始めるときは、なんか、ARKの単語もあるから
But when starting ARK, there are ARK-specific terms,
めちゃくちゃ、なんか言葉が出なくて
so I couldn't find the words at all!
むずいよね。こっちもさ、伝えたいけど英語わかんないみたいな。
It's hard, right? Like, we want to tell you, but we don't know the English.
そう、なんか聞いても、わからない
Yeah, even if I listen, I still don't understand!
「うっとっ」て書いてあるでしょ？
It says "wood," right?
うーん、なんか英語と日本語、違うからなんか、アイテムの名前とか。これ、何で...
Yeah, the item names are different in English and Japanese. Why is this...
わかる。そう。だから、シートでGoogle自動翻訳を入れたスプレッドシートを作ったときに、「ん？これはゲームと一致しているのか？」っていう一抹の不安をよぎったけど、
I get it. Exactly. That's why when I made a spreadsheet with Google Translate, I had a passing anxiety like, "Wait, does this match the game?" but...
イナさんが、それを理解してくれてて、たすかる。
Ina-san still understood it, which helps a lot.
でも、なんか恐竜の名前は、なんとなく翻訳ができてて。
But the dinosaur names are somehow translated.
おお、すげえ。
Oh, amazing!
え、何で寝ないの？おら！
Why aren't you going to sleep? Take that!
何で寝ないの？おらが、あまりにも日本語。
Your "Why aren't you going to sleep? Take that!" is so Japanese.
いやー！
Nooo!
象はビール了解。象は無理だね。象は却下。
Beer for the elephant, got it. Elephants are impossible, then. Rejecting elephants.
まだまだか。
Still not yet?
こいつももう一発行ったほうがいいのか？
Should I hit this guy again?
いや、足りないかな。
No, maybe it's not enough?
何だ。ビール飲む恐竜いるらしい。テイムで。ビール？
What? Apparently there's a dinosaur that drinks beer to tame it. Beer?
うざ。ビール飲むなよ。
How annoying. Don't drink beer.
だからビール。
So, beer.
待って、マジでティラノいないんだけど。10匹無理すぎるだろ、これ。
Wait, there are seriously no T-Rexes. Taming 10 is way too impossible.
さっき、うじゃうじゃいたんですけどね。
They were crawling all over earlier, though.
いや、戻って。
No, come back!
狩り、狩り尽くしすぎた。
Did we hunt them too much?
13...はあ。
13... *sighs*
いや、足りないかな。
No, maybe it's not enough?
逃げるな。
Don't run!
でもあと3匹、3種類なんだよな。あと3種類。
But there are still 3 types left. 3 more types.
今、めっちゃでかいやつ、とっと、やってるんですけど、めっちゃ...
Right now, I'm working on a really big one, but it's...
かかります。で、足りないかも。
taking a lot of time. And it might not be enough.
みんな、これは、みんなこいつはこいつ、こいつ。
Everyone, this one... everyone, it's this guy, this guy.
さ、こいつ昏睡、昏睡、こいつ昏睡。
Now, is this one knocked out? Knocked out?
あ、これはティラノか？
Oh, is this a T-Rex?
いや、足りなかった。
No, it wasn't enough!
なんかに似てるだけで、違う人？
Does it just look similar, but it's actually different?
君はティラノサウルスさんですか？
Are you a Tyrannosaurus Rex?
あなたのお名前は？
What is your name?
許して。君は...
Forgive me. You are...
どうしよう。
What should I do?
許して。
Forgive me.
なんかちょっと薄いから違うかも。
It looks a bit thin, so maybe it's not.
殴ったら、できる？テイム。
If I punch it, can I tame it?
ちょっと君、体薄くない？
Hey, isn't your body a bit thin?
殴ったら、テイムできますか？
If I punch it, can I tame it?
アクロなんちゃら...
An Acro-something...
殴ったらテイム？こん棒ならできるのかな？
Punching to tame? Maybe I can do it with a club?
あ、こいつ、やばい、もう。
Ah, this guy... oh no...
スタミナ足りねえって言われた。やべえ、スタミナ足りねえんだ。
It says not enough stamina. Oh no, I'm out of stamina.
あ、痛いんですけど。
Ah, that hurts, though!
寝なさすぎだろ、こいつ。はよ寝てや。
This guy is sleeping way too little. Go to sleep already!
あ、こいつに関しては頭はダメ？ふざけるな。
Ah, headshots don't work on this guy? You've got to be kidding!
出た！
It did!
マイエスケープ。
My escape!
何、ベリー？ベリーでいいのか？何でもいい。
What, berries? Are berries okay? Anything is fine.
ティラノはもうちょっと頭がでかい、確かに。あいつはちょっと顔が、小顔すぎる。また騙された？騙された！
A T-Rex's head is a bit bigger, indeed. This one's face is a bit too small. Was I tricked again? I was tricked!
こいつ、テイム...おら！
This guy, tame... Take that!
It tamed?
テイミング・パンチ？
Taming punch!
テイミング・パンチ！
てめえ、騙しやがって。
You tricked me!
テイミング・パンチ！
Taming punch!
痛いけど、痛いけど。ARK初心者を騙しやがって。てめえ、てめえ、おら！
It hurts, though! Tricking an ARK beginner like that! You, you, take that!
こいつ、てめえ。あ、う、う。
You... Ah, oo, oo...
騙されてます。
I'm being tricked.
いったたた！
Ow, ow, ow!
あ、やばいやばい。膝の皿が割れる。
Ah, oh no, oh no. My kneecap is going to shatter.
落とした？
Did you drop it?
膝の皿が割れる？あの、五段のところのは、イライラすると視聴者と五段の膝の皿割れるんで。
My kneecap is going to shatter? In Godan-san's chat, when they get frustrated, the viewers' and Godan-san's kneecaps shatter.
イライラ、イライラだめよ。あ、あ、大丈夫よ。
Frustration is no good. Ah, ah, it's okay.
助かっていく。
That helps.
リスナーをイライラさせないためにカエラにイライラしている。
I'm venting my frustration on Kaela to avoid annoying the viewers.
うっ、膝の骨が…
Ugh, my kneecaps...
イライラしないで。
Don't get frustrated.
無理かな。
Probably impossible.
難しかったから。
Because it was difficult...
いや、なんか矢がもっと欲しい。足りなかったです。
Actually, I want more arrows. I didn't have enough.
あ、矢が少ないから。
Ah, because you have few arrows.
そう、矢ね。
Yeah, arrows.
ちょっと作って、戻ります。
I'll make some and head back.
カエラにイライラしそう。ティラノはどこだよ！
I'm about to get annoyed at Kaela. Where is the Tyranno?!
いや、まじでティラノどこだよ。
Seriously, where is the Tyranno?
ティラノ全然いないじゃん！
There are no Tyrannos at all!
あ、桃門が来た。
Ah, Momong is here.
え、桃門…イナって声真似できる？
Wait, Momong... Ina, can you do voice impressions?
声真似そんな得意じゃないけど、なんちゃってくらいだったら。
I'm not that good at impressions, but maybe just a silly attempt...
いや、何があるの？
Wait, what can you do?
え、セミ。
Uh, a cicada.
なんか、みんなすごいレベルのチョイスですね。
Everyone makes such interesting choices.
セミ。
A cicada.
セミやってみて。
Try doing the cicada.
いきますよ。あ、これマイク入るかな。
Here I go. Ah, I wonder if the mic will pick this up.
うわああ！
Whoa!
すごい！うま！
Amazing! So good!
いや、めちゃくちゃうまいよ、それ。
Wow, you're incredibly good at that.
あ、いけます？これでご飯食べていけますかね、自分。
Really? Can I make a living off of this?
いや、いけるわ。
Oh, definitely.
やった。
Yay.
すごい。
Amazing.
やべぇ、Oh my boyがいる。うっ。
Oh my, "Oh my boy" is here. Ugh.
誰か、おかわり。
Someone, seconds please.
やったぜ。夏感じたわ、今。
Alright! I felt summer just now.
夏感じました？
Did you feel summer?
うん。
Yeah.
終わったはずなのですが。
It's supposed to be over, though.
ね、ごめん。ティラノのとこ。
Hey, sorry. About the Tyranno location.
ティラノ…
The Tyranno...
のついでにもう一回だけユニコーン見させて。
While we're at it, let me see the unicorn just one more time.
もち、もちです。
Sure, of course.
え、待って、こいつはさ…こいつテイムいけんじゃね、こいつ。
Wait, this guy... can't we tame this guy?
ベリーテイムじゃないの、こいつ。
Isn't this guy a berry tame?
しゃあ、おらあ。
Alright, let's go!
もう一回ティラノ探しに行くか。拠点の近くにいないですかね、何かの間違いで。
Should we search for the Tyranno one more time? Maybe it's near our base by some mistake.
あ、なんかいるぞ。
Ah, there's something.
やばい、こいつ。お前は誰だ。
Oh no, this guy. Who are you?
こいつあれだった、肉食でした。
Ah, it was a carnivore.
おん？お前は…
Oh? You are...
なんかちょっと顔が薄い気がする。お前、ちょっと薄顔だな。
Your face looks a bit plain. You have a plain face.
薄いのは最新型のノートパソコンだけにしてくれ。
Please keep the thinness to the latest laptop models only.
おう、体が薄すぎる、あいつは。
Whoa, its body is too thin.
うわ、これは…お前は、お前は何だ？
Whoa, this is... You, what are you?
お前も、体が薄いな。
You also have a thin body.
お、ユニコーン。
Oh, unicorn.
ユニコーーーン！ユニコーーーン！
Unicorrrrn! Unicorrrrn!
ユニコーン、お前に会いたいんだ。
Unicorn, I want to see you.
どんだけここにいると思ってんだ、お前。
How long do you think I've been here?
頼むよ、ユニコーン。
Please, Unicorn.
お前に…俺たちのチームに光を、与えてくれ！
Give... our team some light!
ユニコーーーーン！
Unicorrrrn!
やだ、イナ先輩、そのノリに乗られると…
Oh no, Ina-senpai, when you join in like that...
うっ、頭が…助けて。
Ugh, my head... help.
おかしくなっちまったよ、みんな。
Everyone's gone crazy.
みんな、壊れちゃったんだ。
Everyone's broken.
ありがとう。ありがとう。
Thank you. Thank you.
いないね、ティラノ。集会場あたり周回見てみるか、もう一回。
No Tyranno, huh. Let's try searching around the meeting place one more time.
本当にね。もういなかったらもう…
Really. If it's still not there, then...
いない。
Not here.
でもそれか、ちょっとガチ究極、もう向こうの部隊が帰ってきたらとりあえず捕まえたティラノを…殺す。
Or wait, if we really reach the absolute limit, once the other squad returns, we could just... kill the Tyranno we already captured.
1体だけじゃ意味ないだろ。
Just one is pointless, right?
え、でも10体ですよね。最悪数合わせにはならないか。
But we need 10, right? At worst, it won't help make up the numbers?
集会場にもいたはずなんだよ。ティラノ。
It should have been at the meeting place too, the Tyranno.
ね。なんかでも集会場の近くに拠点あるから。
Yeah. But since there's a base near the meeting place...
その拠点周りの人が結構狩っちゃったのかもね。
maybe the people around that base hunted most of them.
ああ、可能性はある。
Ah, that's possible.
もう狩られ済み。すべて。
They're already hunted. All of them.
でもやれることはやっている、我々も。
But we are doing what we can as well.
ねえ。
Yeah.
アスレチック行ってもよさそうだけどな。
I think we could try going to the obstacle course, though.
まあ、半くらいになってちょっとあんま見つかんなかったら、ござるちょっとアスレ行ってこようかな。
Well, if it's around half past and we haven't found many, I think I'll go check out the obstacle course.
いますか？
Are they there?
お、お前は…え？誰、なんか戦ってる…
Oh, you are... Huh? Who is that fighting?
てめえ、つらの皮が薄いじゃねえかよ！
You! Isn't your skin too thin?!
違いましたか。
Was I wrong?
あ、なんかクマが…だれの…
Ah, a bear is... Whose is...
ちょっと皮が薄すぎるんだ！
Your skin is way too thin!
いや！逃げるんだよ！
No! Run away!
あー！
Ahhh!
思えば叫び声のところだけ必死なんだよな。
Come to think of it, you're only desperate when screaming.
お前も皮薄いし、皮薄すぎやろ、みんな！
Your skin is thin too. Everyone's skin is too thin!
いやー！
Nooo!
今、草原で暴れてる。
It's raging in the grassland now.
草原で暴れてる。
Raging in the grassland.
お前に…いなかったか、昨日なんか邪魔してきてた…
Weren't there... like, some bothering us yesterday?
いった！いたたたた…
Ouch! Ow, ow, ow, ow...
いのもちいかわ好き？
Do you like Chiikawa, Ino?
好きです。
I do.
お、誰が好きなの？
Oh, who's your favorite?
ちいかわとハチワレかな。
Probably Chiikawa and Hachiware.
おお、王道コンビ。
Oh, the classic duo.
いいね。
Nice.
ちいかわ見直してるわ、今。めっちゃ…なんか可愛いわ。
I'm rewatching Chiikawa now. It's so... cute.
お、見直しているんですね。
Oh, you're rewatching it?
なんかほっこりする。
It's kind of heartwarming.
あ、ほっこりしてるんですか。じゃ、え、一回全部見たんですか？
Ah, is it heartwarming? So, did you watch it all once?
いや、見てない。途中でね、やめ…見…やめて。
No, I haven't. I stopped... halfway through.
あ、なるほど。あ、じゃあまだ全然。
Ah, I see. Then you're still not all the way in.
きっと可愛いちいかわを見れて、「ちいかわって可愛いな」を楽しめている民ですね。
You're still in the phase of enjoying how cute Chiikawa is.
おん。
Yeah.
ちいかわ見てイライラする人は、多分ストレス溜まってるみたいなやつを言ってた。
They say people who get annoyed watching Chiikawa are probably stressed out.
ストレス溜まってるはヤバい。
"Stressed out" is bad.
ちいかわ見てなんかイライラしてる人は、ストレス溜まってるらしい。
Apparently, if you get annoyed watching Chiikawa, you're stressed.
「うわ、うわ、うわ」みたいな感じになってるの見て、「こいつモタモタしやがって」とか思ってたら、確かにそれは溜まってそうだな。
If you watch them go "Uwa, uwa, uwa" and think "Stop hesitating!" then you're definitely stressed.
そうそう。
Exactly.
これで、きた。
With this, alright.
ちいかわな…可愛いだけじゃ、見れなくなっちゃったよ。
Chiikawa... I can't watch it as just being cute anymore.
いのも昔までちいかわにイライラしてた。「何でこいつは『わっ』しか言わないの？何なんだ」って。
Ino used to get annoyed at Chiikawa too. Like, "Why does he only say 'Wah'? What's his deal?"
思ってたけど…
I thought that, but...
映画見てから、映画見てその考察を見てから…あ、ちいかわも可愛いやって。
After watching it, and looking at the theories... I realized Chiikawa is actually cute.
色々考えてるんやな、こいつ、みたいな。
Like, "Oh, this guy actually thinks about things."
そう、「こいつはこういう性格なんだな」って思って、なんか可愛く見れるようになったよ。穏やかに見れるようになっている。
Yeah, thinking "So this is their personality," I can see them as cute now. I can watch it calmly.
穏やかな気持ちで、あー、よかった。
With a calm feeling... Ah, that's good.
よかった、マジで。穏やかな気持ちで見れなかったらどうしようかと思いました。
Seriously, thank goodness. I was worried what would happen if you couldn't watch it calmly.
大丈夫、穏やかになったから。
It's okay, I've become calm.
もし穏やかに見れてない時は、多分あれだったんだろうね。疲れてたんだろうね。
If I can't watch it calmly, it means I'm probably tired.
多分疲れてたんですよ。
You must have been tired.
もう…なんかバキ。
Already... wait, cracking?
放置された恐竜発見。
Found an abandoned dinosaur.
マジでいないな。
There really are none.
いるの探しに行くか。
Let's go look for one.
てか、めっちゃ真っ黒な馬はいるのにな。
I mean, there's a super pitch-black horse though...
おと…え？
Oto... huh?
おって…おとこぶし入ってんか。
Wait... is there a manly tone in that?
その一言だけで泣ける。
I can cry at just that one word.
笑うわ。大丈夫だよ、トワ。もうみんな落ち着いてるよ。
It makes me laugh. It's okay, Towa. Everyone's calm now.
クマ、くそ…いないのか。
Bear, damn... is it not here?
馬の色塗りたくって白にしてやろうかな。
Maybe I should dye the horse white.
え？で、ユニコーンって名前つけてやろうかな。
Huh? And then name it Unicorn?
君は今日からユニコーンだ。
From today, you are a Unicorn.
そう、君、お前はユニコーン、お前はユニコーンって。
Yeah, "You, you are a Unicorn, you're a Unicorn."
刷り込みね、刷り込みをすることによって…まるで本物…がいるかのような。
Brainwashing... by brainwashing them, it's as if a real one... is there.
そう。
Exactly.
ここにいそうだけどな、どうなんだろう。
It seems like it'd be here, I wonder.
羊多すぎじゃん。
Way too many sheep.
戻るか。
Shall we head back?
うわー、邪魔！
Whoa, you're in the way!
でもちょこちょこ湧いてるんだけどな。
But they are spawning here and there.
あと3回、これも。
Three more times for this too.
Yeah, get him! Scary!
これは... 光に紛れてないユニコーン
This is... a unicorn not blending into the light.
なんかこの中にいない？
Is there someone inside here?
お前も顔薄いじゃねえかよ！
You've got a plain face too!
どんだけ顔薄いんだよ、お前たち。最近、薄顔が流行っとるんか？
How plain are your faces? Is a plain face trendy lately?
修理できないのか。クロスボウって修理できないのか。
Can't I repair it? Can't I repair a crossbow?
あ、作業台の中で...
Oh, inside the smithy...
作業台の中です。
It's inside the smithy.
分かりました。
I understand.
いやー、なんかちょこちょこ粘ってるけど、マージでいないな。
Man, I've been trying stubbornly, but they are really not here.
なんかいない。
There's none.
いない。
None.
起きてくれよって思って、回ってニンジンも取ったのに。
Hoping they'd wake up, I flew around and even got carrots.
うわー！
Whoa!
動けん。
I can't move.
あ、うちの子大丈夫かな。
Ah, is my tamed dino okay?
あ、これティラノじゃない？ねえ、これティラノだよね？
Ah, isn't this a Rex? Hey, this is a Rex, right?
これティラノな気がしてます。
I have a feeling this is a Rex.
ティラノいた？
Did you find a Rex?
え、待って、ブロントに殺さ...
Wait, killed by a Bronto...
てめえ！やっと見つけた！
You bastard! I finally found you!
お前たち！
You guys!
超クソ気持ち悪い虫が目の前にいます。
There is a super gross bug right in front of me.
本当に許しませんよ、本当に！
I will seriously not forgive you, seriously!
あんたたち！
You guys!
あ、飛んでる、どこだ。
Oh, flying, where is it?
許しませんよ、本当にさ。
I won't forgive you, seriously.
人が体力回復してる間に...
While I'm recovering my health...
なんてことしてくれますの、ホント！
Look what you've done to me, seriously!
おら！てめえ！
Take that! You bastard!
痛っ！
Ouch!
てめえ...
You...
飛んでる！
It's flying!
よし！
Alright!
痛っ。今、めっちゃ体力回復な...
Ouch. Now, recovering my health...
あのボロボロブロント...
That battered Bronto...
おめえ、てめえだよ、てめえ。てめえ、絶対にやってやるからな。
You, yes you, bastard. I'll definitely get you, bastard.
よし、おめえだ、おめえ。
Alright, it's you, you.
イロハも荒れてきましたね。
Iroha is getting wild too, huh?
ゆ、許せん。さっきからこいつに邪魔され...
Ugh, unforgivable. This guy keeps getting in my way...
うわ！
Whoa!
こいつ！
This guy!
松井からの呪いを...
The curse of Matsui...
イロハさん。
Iroha-san.
30分になりました。どうしますか？
It's been 30 minutes. What should we do?
あ、行きます。
Oh, I'm coming.
私が行くか。イロハが行くか。
Shall I go, or should Iroha go?
あ、あ、じゃあ...
Oh, oh, then...
なんかゴダのとこ今、1匹ティラノいて。
There's one Rex at Goda's place right now.
お、お。
Oh, oh.
もしかしたら見つけられるかも、ワンチャン。
Maybe we can find it, possibly.
じゃあ...
Then...
テレポーター遠いんでござるが、行ってもいい...
The teleporter is far away, but is it okay if I go?
とわが、じゃあ行こうかな。ちょ、頑張って。
Towa, then maybe I'll go. Try your best.
なんかちょうどブロントあと1匹倒したら1ポイントもらえるんで、やっちゃおうかな。
I only need to kill one more Bronto to get 1 point, so maybe I'll do that.
オッケー、オッケー。
Okay, okay.
谷底に落とされている。
I was dropped into the bottom of the valley.
ノトサウルス？ノトサウルス。
Nothosaurus? Nothosaurus.
ち、ち、ち。ここでワープってできなかったっけ？
Tsk, tsk, tsk. Can't we warp here?
できた気がしたんだけどな。
I thought we could.
できなかったっけ？
Could we not?
よし、もう一回行くか、あいつ。
Alright, I'll go after him again.
おめえは絶対に許さない！
I will never forgive you!
できなかった。
I couldn't.
あ、そうじゃない。
Ah, not that.
え、もう1時間？
Eh, already 1 hour?
残り1時間。
1 hour left.
えぐ。
Insane.
ちょっと待って、ワープする先が...
Wait a second, the warp destination...
やばい。
Oh no.
やばいやばい。
No, no, no.
お前、ブロント、下に行きやがった、お前。行くな。
You, Bronto, you went down there. Don't go.
行くなよ、でかいところ苦手なんだから、こっちは。
Don't go, I'm bad with wide open spaces.
おら！
Take this!
なんかユタラプトル倒した。
I killed a Utahraptor.
いける？
Can you do it?
なんで？
Why?
何で、何で、何でー！
Why, why, why!
違う人がお亡くなり...
The wrong person passed away...
1時間は確かにティラノもしんどいかもな。
Indeed, 1 hour might be tough for Rex too.
ですね。
Right.
その場合はあれかもね、何種類かテイムみたいなやつやった方がいいかもね。
In that case, maybe it's better to do some tames of a few different types.
テイム分からないな、全然。
I don't know anything about taming.
いや、何、何やん、これ。
No, what, what is this?
テイムどこ？
Where is taming?
テイム何やったか分かんないからむずいですよね。
It's hard because we don't know what we've tamed, right?
一回帰るかな。
Maybe I should go back once.
ござるもちょっと持ってないや、クロスボウ持って。
I don't really have a crossbow on me.
なんかディモルフォドン倒した。何このディモル？
I killed some Dimorphodon. What is this Dimorphodon?
全然いない、ティラノ。
There are no T-rexes at all.
しかも、1時間で10体見つけるのはきついかも。
Besides, finding 10 in an hour might be tough.
もうちょっと変えた方がいいか？テイムにするか？
Should we change it a bit? Should we make it taming?
あと何体だっけ？
How many left again?
テイムあと3くらいだから。
We have about three more to tame.
3か。
Three, huh?
何テイムしてないんだろう、逆に。
What haven't we tamed yet, conversely?
なんかめっちゃデカいやつやったんですけど、
I took on a really big one, but...
弓が足りなくて、今ちょっと弓作ってます。
I didn't have enough arrows, so I'm making some now.
アルゲン狩るやつも一応ある。
We also have the Argentavis hunt.
なるほど。
I see.
でも多分、アルゲンよりはブロントの方が早いかも。
But Brontos might be faster than Argents.
大きくて見つけやすいかつ5体なんですよね、ブロントは。
They're big and easy to find, plus we only need five.
アルゲン15体なんですよ。
For Argents, we need 15.
確かに。
True.
で、しかも飛んでるから、あいつはちょっとむずい。
And since they fly, they are a bit difficult.
ワープしたいのよ。ワープの場所がよくわかんない。
I want to warp, but I don't really know the warp locations.
そうそう、また探しながら、あ...
Yeah, while looking again... Ah.
波に行くか。
Shall we head to the shore?
テイム、え、お手軽... え、結局ドードーは誰か見つけられましたか？
Taming, uh, easy... In the end, did anyone find a Dodo?
あ、ドードーテイムした、ドードー。
Ah, I tamed a Dodo.
ナイス、ナイス！
Nice, nice!
マジでチュートリアルなのにいつまでも見つけられなくて、「ど、どこの人？」ってなってた。
Seriously, even though it's a tutorial, I couldn't find one for the longest time and was like "Wh-where are they?"
あとはなんか何体かテイムしたけど、名前覚えてないや。めっちゃ申し訳ない。
And I tamed a few other things, but I don't remember their names. I'm so sorry.
なんかリスナーさん、教えて。教えて。
Chat, tell me. Tell me.
なんかグリフィンいる？
Are there Griffins?
グリフィンいるわ。
There's a Griffin.
おちっこ？
Pee-pee?
うーん... 今なんか「おちっこ」って言わなかった？
Hmm... didn't you just say "pee-pee"?
おち... おしり？「こっち」と言いました。
Pe... Butt? I said "this way".
お尻？「こっち」と言いました。
Butt? I said "this way".
あ、こっちか！
Ah, "this way"!
すみません、すみません。
Sorry, sorry.
もう耳がおかしい。「おちっこ」に聞こえてた。
My hearing is messed up. I heard it as "pee-pee".
おし...「おちっこ」を可愛く「おちっこ」って言ったのかと思いました。
I thought you were saying "pee-pee" in a cute way.
すみません。
Sorry.
もう耳もおかしくなっちゃってるよ。
My hearing has gone weird too.
疲れているのよ、あなた。
You are tired.
そう、疲れてるの。
Yes, I'm tired.
疲れているのよ。
You are tired.
マジでテレポート、テレポートの場所がわかんなすぎて。なんかテレポ、マップに記載ないから、わかんなくなっちゃうんだよな。
Seriously, I don't know the teleport locations at all. Since they aren't on the map, I get confused.
いやわかる。テレポーター謎すぎる。
I know, right? Teleporters are too mysterious.
ワンチャン、迷子、迷子の迷子の...
Maybe, lost child, lost child, a lost child's...
でも、頑張りましたからね、ここまでね。
But we worked hard to get this far.
テレポーターで辿り着け...
Reach it via teleporter...
られられられ...
can can can...
う、この辺も見たけどいなかったんだよな。
Yeah, I looked around here too, but there were none.
テイムか... パラサ... ウロロロロロみたいなやつだったらできるのかな？簡単に。
Taming... maybe something like a Parasaur... if it's that, can we do it easily?
うーん...
Hmm...
あれ、集会場の...
Is that the gathering area's...?
あ、ボ2か。
Ah, is it boss 2?
ワンチャンこれ...
Maybe this...
いや、これテイ... レース会場辿ってったら、帰れる説。
Wait, if I follow this race track, maybe I can go back.
あ、何なんだこの...
Ah, what is this...?
そうだね、これコース辿ればワンチャン集会場よな。これで帰ればいいか。
That's right, if I follow this course, I might reach the gathering area. Maybe I should just head back like this.
おる、帰る目途立ちました？なんと。
Oru, did you find a way to get back? Wow.
やったぜ、よかった。
Awesome, glad to hear it.
やったけど、あれ... あ、道を見失ってた。危ない危ない。
I did, but wait... Ah, I lost the way. Dangerous, dangerous.
自分、自分も見失う。
I'll lose myself too.
えーっと... どこにあるんだっけ？あの...
Uh... where was it again? Um...
アスレ？
Athletic course?
アスレチック。
Athletic course.
集会場から... あ、集会場の出口の中で1つ？
From the gathering area... Ah, is it one of the exits in the gathering area?
オッケー、ありがとう。
Okay, thank you.
なんか、昨日なんか準備中って書いて... あった。
I think yesterday it said "preparing"...
ああ、あれね！ありがとう、ありがとう、ありがとう！
Ah, that one! Thank you, thank you, thank you!
これか？
Is it this one?
これな... これを辿れば帰れる。
This... if I follow this, I can go back.
なんか必要ななんかあるのかな？
Is there something we need?
誰か... 主に...
Someone... mainly...
いませんか？あの...
Is there anyone? Um...
本当にティラノいませんか？
Are there really no T-rexes?
ついでにいたっていいんだよ。
You can exist on the side too.
帰りがいっそいたっていいんだよ。
You can exist more on the way back too.
いないよ...
There's none...
誰もいなくなった
No one is left...
いない
None.
なんか、なんか、アスレチックに1時間かかるとか言う話がなんか、隣から聞こえてくるんだけど、死にそうじゃ、死ぬんだけど
I can hear from next door that the obstacle course takes an hour... I'm gonna die, I'm dying!
きゃ、きゃら
(giggles)
「1時間？」「1時間」
"An hour?" "An hour."
でもいける、昨日馬を制したとわ様ならいける
But we can do it. If it's Towa-sama who conquered the horse, she can do it.
「あ、そうっすね」「うん」
"Ah, that's right." "Yeah."
馬を制した？馬、馬？
Conquered the horse? Horse, horse?
馬、馬レース。レース
Horse, horse race. The race.
「お馬か足りないですか、とわ様」「そうそう」
"Is she short on horses, Towa-sama?" "Yeah, yeah."
馬を制した、とわ様なら、いけますよ
If it's Towa-sama who conquered the horse, she can do it.
とわ様を信じろ、私たちを信じてください
Believe in Towa-sama, please believe in us!
そう、とわ様を信じろ
Right, believe in Towa-sama.
「お前を信じる俺たちを信じろ、キター！」「やばい！」
"Believe in the us that believes in you... It's here!" "OMG!"
まさか、イナ先輩からそんな構文が出てくるなんて
I can't believe that copypasta came out of Ina-senpai!
お前を信じる俺たちを信じろ
Believe in the us that believes in you.
麻酔矢全然ないんだよな、今
I don't have any tranquilizer darts right now.
今、作ってます、はい
I'm crafting some now, yes.
ありがとうございます
Thank you!
100あったらあれいけるかな？もう回復したかも...
If we have 100, can we do that? It might have healed already...
はあー、じゃあ、またチャレンジ行きます
*Sigh* Okay, I'll go challenge it again.
おねがいします
Please do.
またあるかな？
Is it still there?
え、なんか、ティラノ...来てます？
Wait, is that... Tyranno... coming?
いる？
Is it there?
ちょっと、外にティラノじゃないですか？
Wait, isn't that a Tyranno outside?
あ、おっと、ティラノ、ティラノ、ちょっとちょっとちょっとちょっと！
Ah, oops, Tyranno, Tyranno, wait wait wait wait!
来てないですか？
Is it not coming?
やばい、出向いてきた。何となく殺そう、見つかったから
Oh no, it came out. Let's just kill it since it saw us.
「なんか、やつあたりじゃ！」「BGMが買って...」
"Like, 'It's a vent of anger!'" "The BGM is winning..."
え、待って、これティラノ？いやこれ顔薄くね？お前顔薄くない？
Wait, is this a Tyranno? No, isn't its face thin? Isn't your face thin?
ティラノ？
Tyranno?
待って、ちょちょちょちょちょ
Wait, wait, wait, wait, wait!
うちの適当に捕まえたプテラいじめるのやめてくれる？
Can you stop bullying the Pteranodon I casually tamed?
お前顔薄いじゃねえか、それ！拠点の前で！<
Your face is totally thin, you! In front of our base!
無視もできないし、コノヤロー！
I can't ignore you, you bastard!
ティラノ、い、いけます？
Tyranno, c-can we do it?
あ、いけると思う、たぶん。このプテラがね、あ、大丈夫そう
Ah, I think we can, probably. This Ptera, ah, seems fine.
プテラー！
Ptera!
おら、てめえ！
Hey, you!
どっか行けよ！お前に用はねんだよ！
Go away! I have no business with you!
お前に！用は！ないんだよ！
I have! No! Business with you!
はい
Okay.
いやあ...
Wow...
なんか違うやつ殺した、なんだ？
I killed something else, what was that?
昨日のあれいないかな？アクロの、なん、なんちら
I wonder if yesterday's one is still there? Acro... whatever it's called.
ちょっとさすがにお隣さんにも被害が及びそうだから、こいつは倒そう、あ
Wait, since this might affect our neighbors too, let's defeat it, ah.
あ、回らない、ちょっと時間ロスだな。お隣さんが...
Ah, it doesn't spin, a bit of wasted time. Our neighbors...
お隣さん守ってあげよう、しゃーなし。しゃむなし
Let's protect our neighbors, can't be helped. No choice.
あ、あ、あ、あ、あ...
Ah, ah, ah...
飛んだ、飛んだ、飛んだ。行ったか？行ったか？
It flew, it flew. Did it go? Did it go?
え、来い、お前。こっち来い
Hey, come here, you. Come here.
ちょ、こっち来い。あ、イェーイ！
Wait, come here. Ah, yay!
あれも顔が分厚くて...
That one also has a thick face...
な、分厚くない、分厚くない。こいつは薄いんだ
What, not thick, not thick. This one is thin.
なんでこんな顔の皮薄い奴らしかいない...
Why are there only thin-faced ones here...
もう一匹
Another one.
やめてくんない？
Can you stop?
ちょっと待って、なんかスタックしたんだけど、やめて
Wait a minute, I got stuck, stop it.
ああ、よかった
Ah, thank goodness.
ちょっと、あの...
Wait, um...
スタックしたんですけど。あ、いいよいいよ、この角度良い
I got stuck. Ah, it's fine, this angle is good.
来い
Come.
この角度いいよ、この角度
This angle is good, this angle.
え、なんか、あれ、飛んでる...
Huh, wait, that thing flying...
なんか体痛くなってきたかも。また体温持つの？やばそうだったな、これ
I feel like my body is getting sore. Am I catching a fever again? That seemed bad.
あれは何？虫っぽいな
What is that? Looks like an insect.
え、飛んでるのどこ行った？え、何？虫っぽいな
Wait, where did the flying one go? Huh, what? Looks like an insect.
やばい、飛べないからワンチャン死ぬかもワイバーン。あ、生きてる
Oh no, I can't fly so I might die, Wyvern. Ah, I'm alive.
どうやってテイムするんだろ？
How do you tame it?
生きてるんかーい！
Are you alive?!
どうやってテイムするんだろ？
How do you tame it?
オッケー
Okay.
「キル？」「よしよしよし」
"Kill?" "There, there, there."
ボーラ、それと速い、なるほどなるほど
Bola, and fast, I see, I see.
とやってみようか、あ。飛んでる、戻って、飛んでる、どこ行く？
I'll try doing that... ah. It's flying, go back, it's flying, where are you going?
「食え、お前。いいから。」「飛んでる、あ、行った」
"Eat it, you. Just do it." "It's flying, ah, it went."
ボーラって...
Bolas are...
わりわりわりわりわりわりわり
Chop chop chop...
あれか。
Is that it?
ぶっ壊して。
Let's break it down.
よいしょ、体が… 体が水分求めてるよん。
Whew, my body... my body is demanding some water.
えっと。
Let's see.
え、え、え、え、え、わりわりわりわり。
Uh, uh, uh, chop, chop, chop...
よいしょ。
Yoisho.
ん？
Hm?
えいほ、えいほ。
Heave-ho, heave-ho.
わりわりわりわり。
Chop chop chop.
また落ちて。
It fell again...
テイムあと3体、何がいいんだ？
Taming 3 more... what should we get?
あ、もう... もう1つですよ。1匹。
Oh, it's... it's just one more. One beast.
あ、あと1！すごい！
Oh, just one left? Amazing!
あと1、何がいいんだ？
Just one left... what should we get?
えっと、飛んじゃった。
Let's see... it flew away.
飛んでる！
It's flying!
飛んでる！すごい、イナ先輩がめっちゃやってくれてる。
It's flying! Amazing, Ina-senpai is doing so much for me.
あれがない間に。
While that isn't here.
やばい、固まった。ARK落ちた。
Oh no, it froze. ARK crashed.
Oh my god.
ARK落ちまちた。
ARK crashed.
Oh no.
Oh my god!
あれ、は！
Huh? Yah!
落ちてしまい... 戻り... あり...
I'm gonna fall... go back... ah...
あ、また飛んじゃった。
Oh, it flew away again.
あ、この画面消して。
Ah, let me close this screen.
ん？ え、何？
Hm? What?
重いなぁ、ARK。
ARK is so laggy.
あ、クラッシュ・オブ・クラッシュ・オブ・クラッシュかもしれない、この揺れ方。
Ah, with the way it's shaking, it might be a Crash of Crash of Crash.
クラッシュ・オブ・クラッシュ・オブ・クラッシュだ。
It is a Crash of Crash of Crash!
なんだと。
What the?
え、赤い。
Huh, it's red.
おみがー。えーれ、よいこせ。
Oh my god... Whew, yoikhose.
え、見えた。
Oh, I see it.
やった、取って。
Awesome! Catch it.
よいしょ。
Yoisho.
よみがえり。
Resurrection.
おもてえ。
So heavy.
オッケー、オッケー。
Okay, okay.
やっとこいったの！
We finally made it here!
これで行けたんだけど。
I was able to do it with this, but...
戻れました？
Were you able to get back?
お、OBSに写らなくなったわ。
Oh, it stopped showing on OBS.
うわあ、what?
Whoa, what?
え、マジでどこ行った？
Wait, seriously, where did it go?
これで、ふぅ、きたきたきた。
With this... phew, it's back, it's back.
オッケー、オッケー、オッケー。直った、直った。
Okay, okay, okay. It's fixed, it's fixed.
さ、向こうはどうかな？
Now, I wonder how it is over there?
イナ先輩どこにいるんだろう？
I wonder where Ina-senpai is?
えっと、雪の山の近くに…
Well, near the snowy mountain...
うん、うん。
Yeah, yeah.
なんか虫をテイム… しようとしたの、しようとしたんですけど、ちょっと逃げて、どこにいたか…
I tried to... I was trying to tame an insect, but it ran away a bit, and I don't know where it went...
なるほど。
I see.
見つからなくて。
I can't find it.
虫テイム…
Insect taming...
どこだろう？
I wonder where.
え、重っ。
Uh, so laggy.
持ってくれ 俺のARK
Hang in there, my ARK!
頑張って
Hang in there!
ARK もう あと少し
ARK, just a little bit more...
あきちゃん
Aki-chan.
はい
Yes?
ちょっとラグの挙動で抜け出せなくて
Um, I can't get out due to some lag...
はい
Yes.
助けてほしいです
I need some help.
どのような状態になってますか？
What's your current situation?
マグマに落ちてるんですけど
I fell into the magma,
落ち方が悪すぎて壁に挟まれてて
but I got wedged into the wall...
左右ボタンが利かなくて
The left and right buttons aren't working.
なるほど
I see.
まいっか
Oh well.
ちょっと確認しますので少々お待ちください
Let me check on that, please wait a moment.
お願いします
Okay, thank you.
麻酔...
Narcotics...
ベリーなかったっけ？
Did we not have berries? Wait...
あるよね？
We should have some, right?
ベリーないのか
No berries?
ちょっと作って...
I'll make some...
さっき言ったよね？
I mentioned it earlier, right?
あら、こんにちは
Oh, hello.
こっち
This way.
こんにちは！
Hello!
ビビは離脱しました
Bibi has withdrawn.
足を引っ張るだけでした
I was just holding everyone back.
いやいや、どんまい！
No way, don't worry about it!
ナイストライ、ナイストライ
Nice try, nice try!
ありがとうございます
Thank you so much!
どんな感じでした？
How did it go?
今途中で るぶさんとボタン先輩で向かってて
We're on our way now, Rubu-san and Botan-senpai...
ボタン先輩がちょっとスタック？
But is Botan-senpai currently stuck?
はいはい
I see, I see.
アキローズ先輩に対応していただいてるみたいで
So it seems Akirose-senpai is handling it now.
なるほど 増員必要そうだった？
I see. Did it look like they needed reinforcements?
いや、なんだったら一人のほうが早いみたいで
No, actually, it seemed like going solo would be faster.
ああ、まぁそうだよね
Ah, that makes sense.
経験のために連れてってくれたみたいです
It sounds like they brought me along just for the experience.
なるほど了解
I see, roger that.
20種テイムがあと1匹なんで
Well, we only need one more tame for the 20-species goal.
それをやりたい
So I want to do that.
めっちゃいいじゃないですか！
That sounds amazing!
もっと...
More...
どこ行った？
Where did it go?
ビビちゃん ギリースーツとか全ロスしちゃった
Bibi lost all of her gear, including the ghillie suit...
予備もない 泣いた
No spares left either. I'm crying.
そしたらどうしたらいいんだろう？
Then, what should we do?
ユニコーンじゃなくて...
Not a unicorn...
何取りに行きますか？
What should we go get?
装備ちょっと揃えたい
I want to get some gear ready.
近いとこでなんかテイムしたいよね
I want to tame something nearby.
あと1匹だもんな
Since we only need one more.
いやー どこ行った？！
Man, where did it go?!
あと30分
30 minutes left.
その辺にあるアルゲン乗ってもらって...
You can just ride any Argentavis around here...
あと何テイムしてないんだ？
What haven't we tamed yet?
麻酔矢持ってないんです 全ロスしたんか
I don't have narcotic arrows. Ah, because of the full loss?
そうなんです 間違えたよもう
That's right, I messed up...
簡易拠点で今作ってるはずです
But we should be crafting them at the temporary base now.
麻酔をもらってちょっと作ったけど
I got some narcotics and made a few...
200個持ってたのにな
I had 200 of them...
なんてこと！
Unbelievable!
ちょっと待って ウサギの巣すぎる ここ
Wait a sec, this place is crawling with rabbits.
まず
Not good.
ナルコベリーとか...
Maybe some Narcoberries...
ナルコベリー集めて 麻酔作ってもらうのが...
Gathering Narcoberries and crafting narcotics...
今一番拠点近くだし
is probably the best option near our base right now.
クロスボウってお願いできたりしますか？
Could I ask for a crossbow instead of a slingshot?
クロスボウもなくなったのか
Oh, you lost the crossbow too?
クロスボウなら作業台の中で作れるよ
You can craft a crossbow in the smithy.
素材は全部入っているはず
All the materials should be in there.
了解です ナルコベリー探します
Got it, I'll search for Narcoberries.
ナルコベリーさえあれば 勝手に作っちゃって大丈夫
As long as we have Narcoberries, you can go ahead and craft them.
ビビの体ムキむきですっごいテカテカや
Bibi's body is super muscular and shiny.
なんだこれ？
What is this?
この辺の子とか行けないのかな
Can't we tame something around here?
あ、死んじゃいそう
Ah, I'm about to die.
メガロケロスって結局テイムしたっけ？
Did we end up taming a Megaloceros?
視聴者さんどうだったっけ？
What was it, viewers?
メガロ 誰かテイムしてたっけ？
Did someone tame a Megaloceros?
お、なんだあいつ？
Oh, what is that guy?
分からんよな
We don't know, do we?
死んではいないよね？
It's not dead, right?
失踪して逃げてた？
Did it run away?
ワンチャンやってみたいなぁ
Maybe we could try it, just in case.
石とか拾ってるし
I'm picking up stones and stuff.
死んだかも？
Maybe it died?
いや、死んだら...
Well, if it died...
おら！
Take that!
そや。やってみるか。
Right. Let's try it.
えっ、どうしようとしたっけ？
Wait, what was I trying to do?
おって、なんか似てるけど違う。
Wait, that looks similar but different.
お肉欲しいんだよね、お肉。
I want some meat, meat.
あ！お肉は…
Ah! The meat...
いや…
No...
焼いてあるやつは冷蔵庫、それ以外は餌箱に入っている。
The cooked ones are in the fridge, the rest are in the feeding trough.
はい、もらいました。
Okay, I got it.
はーい。よいしょ。
Okay. Heave-ho.
やべ、船ハメとかやりてぇ。
Shoot, I want to try boat trapping.
ナルコベリーと腐ったお肉か。
Narcoberries and spoiled meat?
腐ったお肉がいるんだ。
So we need spoiled meat.
う。
Ugh.
腐ったお肉ない。
No spoiled meat.
うーん、諦めた方がいいかも。
Hmm, maybe we should give up.
あれ？どうしたんですか？
Huh? What's wrong?
なんかテイム中だった…
Something we were taming...
ものがあったんだけど、ちょっと…
was there, but...
はいはい。
Right, right.
見失って、見つからない。
We lost sight of it, and I can't find it.
オオカミだるい！
Wolves are so annoying!
もう、ね、
Geez...
ちょっと飲んで。
Let me drink some...
えっ、何かいかい？あ、あ、
Wait, is there something there? Oh, ah!
あ、今、あの…
Ah, right now, that...
あの虫、虫やってみる？
Should we try that bug?
あ、あ、ワイバーン君！
Ah, Wyvern-kun!
着陸、着陸、着陸して君は。
Land, land, please land.
ナルコベリーが足り…
Not enough narcoberries...
着陸してもらって、
Please land for me,
乗りたいのよ、君に。
I want to ride you.
君に乗りたいのね。
I want to ride you, okay?
あ、こちら、こちら君に乗りたいから、
We want to ride you, so...
着陸をしてください。
please land.
ワイバーン君！
Wyvern-kun!
き、君に乗りたい。
I... I want to ride you.
モンダイジいない？
Is Mondaiji not here?
ちょっと乗りたい。
I really want to ride.
ベリーめっちゃ取れるやつ、何でしたっけ？マンモス？
What was the one that gathers lots of berries? Mammoth?
あ、マンモス！マンモス！
Ah, Mammoth! Mammoth!
あれ、何だっけマンモスって。あれ？
Wait, what was Mammoth? Huh?
ちょっと待って。
Wait a second.
なんで着地してくんないの？
Why won't you land?!
もういいけど、倒してくれたから。
It's fine, since you defeated it for me.
ちょっと！
Wait!
ベリーいっぱい取れるの何ですか？皆さん。
What gathers a lot of berries, everyone?
アンキーじゃない？
Isn't it Anky?
マンモスとアンキーと。
Mammoth and Anky.
マンモスとアンキー？
Mammoth and Anky?
どこにいるんだろう？マンモス。
Where are they? Mammoth.
いた。
There.
マンモスか、やっぱり。
Mammoth, after all.
なんか一瞬止まったところを…
When it stops for a second...
ずっと一生使わずに、
Never using it for a whole lifetime,
おのれの身で集めているからな。使わないと。
and gathering with our own bodies. We have to use it.
こいつ寝てくんないか。
Won't this guy go to sleep?
邪魔だよ、ラッキーキ。
You're in the way, Lucky-ki.
邪魔。ラッキーキ、めっちゃ成長してるやん。
In the way. Lucky-ki, you've grown so much.
邪魔すぎる、ラッキーキ。
You're too much in the way, Lucky-ki.
麻酔矢もそんなんないしな。
And I don't have many tranq arrows either.
て、てめぇ！
Yo, you!
なんてこった。
Oh my goodness.
お供に入ったでしょう、今のは。
That must have gone into the companion inventory, right?
これちょっと、何が入ってるか見ようかな。
Let me check what's inside this.
よいしょ。
Heave-ho.
頼む！気絶してくれ！
Please! Get knocked out!
なんか石の矢になってる、これ。
Wait, these are stone arrows.
ああ、麻酔矢切れてる。だめだ。
Ah, my tranq arrows ran out. No good.
何もかもが上手くいかないターン来た。
The "nothing is going right" phase has arrived.
何もかもが上手くいかない。
Nothing is going right.
麻酔矢が、麻酔矢が全然足りなくて。
Tranq arrows, I'm completely out of tranq arrows.
今何個、何個なんやろ。
I wonder how many there are now.
そう、ビビが死んでいなければ。
Right, if Bibi hadn't died.
あ、そうだ。インベントリにあったわ。
Ah, right. They were in the inventory.
10本しかない。
I only have 10.
ううーん。
Mmm...
お腹空いてるし、喉乾いてる。
I'm hungry, and thirsty.
テイムしたいけど、無理かな。あれは。
I want to tame it, but maybe it's impossible? That one.
何かないかな？テイムできるもの。
Is there anything we can tame?
もう簡単にテイムできるやつ一覧はね、結構みんなテイムしてそうな感じがするんですよね。
I feel like everyone has already tamed all the ones on the easy-to-tame list.
そうよね。
That true.
え、なんかキモい虫が戦ってる。何これ？
Uh, some creepy bug is fighting. What's this?
あ、これ違う人のやつか。
Ah, is this someone else's?
水飲みたい。
I want to drink water.
マジで水欲しいです。
I seriously want water.
水がなくて死にそうなの、トワ様これ。
Towa-sama is about to die from lack of water.
水。
Water.
これ、砂漠なのかもしれん。
This might be a desert.
あれ？これは…え、ビビは何か…
Huh? This is... uh, Bibi, did you...
麻酔矢を作ったらどうしましょう？
What should we do once we make tranq arrows?
もうテイム、テイム。なんか近くにいるちっこい鳥とか虫とか何でもいい。テイムをしたい。
Just tame, tame. Some small bird or bug nearby, anything is fine. I want to tame something.
え、あと1匹だけですか？
Eh, only one more left?
あと1匹だけっぽいよね。
Looks like only one more.
あ、そっか。
Ah, I see.
あれ、イナ先輩は何を今テイム中？
By the way, what is Ina-senpai taming right now?
イナ先輩はもう諦めた。
Ina-senpai already gave up.
探してくれてって…
She asked to look for it...
寝てて…誰か、何かが食べた気がする。
I think... someone or something ate it while I was away.
あ、なるほど。
Ah, I see.
すぐに消えちゃったから。
Because it disappeared right away.
食べられたんだ。
It got eaten.
うん、しゃあなしですね、それは。
Yeah, that's unavoidable.
うん。
Yeah.
いい子、ここ壊れてね？
Isn't this place broken?
修理…それ、ここ開けない。
Repair... I can't open this here.
開けた？
Can you open it?
あ、開けた。
Oh, I opened it.
たまに開けない時ありますね。バグ？
Sometimes it won't open. Is it a bug?
うん。
Yeah.
１、２、５…
1, 2, 5...
ドドいないね、確かに。ドド…
There's indeed no Dodo. Dodo...
開けない。
I can't open it.
何をテイムしたらいいんだ。
What should I tame?
そうよね、別のエリアちょっと…
That's right, maybe another area...
そうそう、別のエリア…でも、めっちゃ砂漠とか結構すぐ熱中症になっちゃってめっちゃきつかったから、普通に平原っぽいところで探したほうがよさそう。
Right, another area... but the desert made me overheat so quickly and was really tough, so it might be better to look in a normal plain-like area.
あの…あの場所、なん…何て言うんだっけ？始めた場所…
That... what is that place called? The starting place...
あ、集会場！
Ah, the hub!
はい。そこってなんか、別のものがあった気がします。
Yes. I feel like there was something else there.
行けるかな？
Can we go there?
確かに。行ってみるか。イナ先輩、麻酔矢はいくつ持ってますか？
Indeed. Shall we go try? Ina-senpai, how many tranq arrows do you have?
今、８８。
Right now, 88.
じゃ、それを持って行きましょう。ビビさん、もし、ちょっと拠点じゃないや、集会場の近くでやってくるんで…
Then let's take those and go. Bibi-san, we're going near the hub, not the base...
ちょっとこの麻酔と矢をいい感じにしたら、集会場のテレポーターに来てもらっていいですか？
So once we get these tranqs and arrows ready, could you come to the hub's teleporter?
ビビ、なんか開けなくなってしもて…このすり鉢とすりこぎ…
Bibi, I can't open it anymore... this mortar and pestle...
あ、でも、一人称にしてやると、多分、できるかも。開けないです…痕。
Ah, but if you do it in first-person, maybe you can. I can't open it...
一旦リログ？
Re-log once?
ま、確かにリログがいいかも。駄目そうであれば。
Well, re-logging might be better if it doesn't work.
はい、出ます。
Okay, logging out.
じゃ、集会場に…
Then, to the hub...
行きましょう。はい。
Let's go. Okay.
あ、え、ねえ、そうじゃん！ちょっと待って。マンモス、カウントされてないから、マンモス…
Ah, wait, that's right! Hold on. Mammoth isn't counted, so mammoth...
イナ先輩！
Ina-senpai!
はい。
Yes.
マンモス、テイムしたら行ける！
If we tame a mammoth, we can do it!
え？
Eh?
カウントされてないんですか？
Is it not counted?
あのね、これ子供から育てたから、マンモス、カウントされてないや！そうだ！ここで！
You see, we raised this one from a baby, so the mammoth didn't count! That's right! Here!
Nice, nice, nice. そうだ。
Nice, nice, nice. That's right.
じゃ、ちょっと待って。矢を撃って、マンモスの…
Then wait, shoot arrows, the mammoth...
え、じゃ、これに乗って行くか？この、これで。イナ、イナ先輩、come on, let's go.
Eh, then, should we ride on this? This one. Ina, Ina-senpai, come on, let's go.
ちょっとお水…
A bit of water...
あ、お水いっぱい持たないと。
Ah, we have to carry a lot of water.
ですね。そうじゃん。
Indeed. That's right.
私たちはミスをした がゆえに…
Because we made a mistake...
え、ちょっと待って、なんか、このサーバーに参加するのに必要なMODをダウンロードしてください。え？空きがありません…え？MODストレージに十分な空きがありませんで、ビビ、ゲームログインできなくなっちゃった！嘘でしょ？！
Eh, wait a minute, it says "Please download the mods required to join this server." Eh? No space... "Not enough space in mod storage," Bibi can't log into the game anymore! No way?!
嘘でしょ？
No way!
どういうこと？もう…
What does that mean? Seriously...
笑った。何？何が起きてるの？え、どういうこと？え、なんで？
That's funny. What? What is happening? Eh, what do you mean? Eh, why?
え、嘘でしょ。え、さっきまで出来てたよね？どういうこと？なんで？
Eh, no way. Eh, it was working just now, right? What do you mean? Why?
やだ、なんか水飲んだと思ったのに飲めてないんだけど。え、なんで？
No, I thought I drank water but I didn't. Eh, why?
MODストレージに十分な空きがありません？え？ビビのPCがってこと？これ。PCの…
Not enough space in mod storage? Eh? Does that mean Bibi's PC? This. The PC's...
サーバー？
Server?
え、サーバー足りなくなった？
Eh, did the server run out?
あ、３０分…
Ah, 30 minutes...
おしっ！イナ先輩行こう。
Alright! Ina-senpai, let's go.
はい！行ってらっしゃい！
Yes! Have a safe trip!
あ、マンモスはあ…あれに乗ってやるんですか？
Ah, are we going to tame the mammoth riding on... that?
のほうがいいかな。なんか強いから、頭…
That might be better. Since it's strong, the head...
あ、そうですね。
Ah, that's true.
多分これに乗って撃ってもらったほうがいいかも。乗れる？ほい。
Maybe it's better to ride on this and have you shoot. Can you ride? Hup.
あ、待って、イナ先輩落とす、危ない。
Oh, wait, I'm gonna drop Ina-senpai, dangerous.
あ、なんかユティラなんか掴んで連れて来てる。
Ah, look, a Yuty... is carrying something over here.
オッケー。
Okay.
マンモスと…確かにあと、なんかアルゲンとかでこう捕まえられる…
Mammoths... True, if we can grab it with an Argentavis...
右クリックでこう掴めるやつを掴んで、矢、頭に打ち込んで…
...like, grab it with a right-click, and shoot arrows into its head...
そうですね。でもなんか、何回も回ったんですけど…
That's true, but I flew around there several times...
なんか、何もなくて、あの場所に。
...and there was nothing in that area...
バイソン…バイソンはあったんですけど。
...though there were Bisons.
あ、マンモス。
Oh, Mammoth.
マンモス。行きましょう！
Mammoth. Let's go!
がんばれー！
Good luck!
はい！マンモスってベリー…
Yes! For Mammoths, berries...
肉かな？
Meat, maybe?
あ、オッケー。
Oh, okay.
あ、持ってたからその辺は大丈夫。
I had some, so that should be fine.
うちも持ってます。
I have some too.
よし、じゃちょっと待って。今、下降しますね。
Alright, wait a second. I'll descend now.
ちょっとお待ちを。で、旋回して…
Hold on. And turning around...
これで、イナ先輩、撃てますか？ここから、このマンモス。
Ina-senpai, can you shoot it from here? This Mammoth.
後ろ？
Behind?
あ、前、前、前、この。
Oh, front, front, front. This one.
あ。はい。
Ah, yes.
うん、こっちに引き付けようかな。
Hm, maybe I'll lure it this way.
来て。
Come here.
ああ！落ちた！
Ah! I fell!
あ、落ちた？大丈夫？こっち側に寄せて…乗れるように。
Oh, did you fall? Are you okay? I'll steer closer so you can get back on.
あ、なんか、トラップに入ったんです。
Ah, somehow... it fell into a trap.
あ、なんか、撃てー！
Ah, somehow... Shoot it!
撃てー！
Shoot!
野生のトラップで草。
A wild trap, lol.
ナイスサポート。
Nice support.
ござるも降りるよ。
Gozaru is coming down too.
あんま矢ないけど、結構…
I don't have many arrows, but quite a few...
あ、当たってた？
Oh, did it hit?
まさかのウサギの罠で草。
An unexpected rabbit trap, lol.
よしよし。
Good, good.
あ、こっち見た。
Oh, it looked over here.
イナ先輩、こっち側来れますか？走らせちゃおうかな。
Ina-senpai, can you come over here? Maybe I should make it run...
あ、なんか逃げてる？
Oh, is it running away?
あ、逃げてる、逃げてる。撃ったら気絶するかも。
Ah, it's running, it's running. If we shoot it, it might pass out.
ござるも矢がないや。
Gozaru doesn't have arrows either.
うちもいっぱい持ってますから。
I have plenty with me.
センキュー。
Thank you.
お、できたー！
Oh, we did it!
ナイス！
Nice!
ナイス。
Nice.
肉…かな？
Meat... maybe?
アンキロってテイムしたことになってんのかな、もらったやつで。
Does the Ankylosaurus count as tamed? The one we received.
あ、そうですね。どうなんだろう？
Ah, that's true. I wonder.
マンモスはベリー。
For Mammoths, berries.
マンモス、ベリー？オッケー、オッケー。
Mammoths, berries? Okay, okay.
なんか紫のやつが良いって聞きました。
I heard the purple ones are good.
ちょっと紫、オッケー。
A bit of purple, okay.
ナイス！これでたぶん20に…
Nice! With this, it should probably be level 20...
なるはず。
...or something.
待ってくれ、これでワンチャン駄目だったらその目の前にいる…
Wait, if this somehow doesn't work, the one right in front of us...
アンキロ…すみません。
...the Ankylosaurus... sorry.
はい。
Yes.
アスレチックに誰かの、革に、革袋に入れた水をめっちゃ持ってきてくれませんか？
Can someone please bring a ton of water in a waterskin to the athletic course?
ああ、いいですけど、ちょっと待って。どうしようかな。
Oh, sure, but wait a second. What should I do?
あ、じゃあ、ござるが行こうかな。イナ先輩、それちょっとお願いしていいですか？
Oh, then, maybe Gozaru should go? Ina-senpai, can I leave this to you?
あ、いいですよ。行ってらっしゃい。
Oh, sure. Have a safe trip.
はーい。
Okay.
すみません。
Sorry.
水、来なかったし。マジでここ、マジ無所。マジ無所。刑務所すぎる。
Water didn't come. Seriously, this is a real prison. Real prison. Too much like a prison.
助けて。
Help me.
無所…
Prison...
助けて。
Help me.
凍えそう。助けて。助けて。
I'm freezing. Help. Help.
私、こんなことのために生まれたわけじゃないのに…
I... I wasn't born for this...
助けて！何で！何でこんなの？！
Help! Why! Why is it like this?!
こんな…私はみんなの役に立ちたくて。
Like this... I just wanted to be useful to everyone.
水…水を持ってきて、手稼ぎに来ただけなのに…
I just brought some water and came to grind...
手稼ぎに来たんですよね、トワ様ね。そうですよね。
You just came to grind, right, Towa-sama? Yes, that's right.
なんでこんなに…
Why is it so...
明かりも全くない暗いところで…
In a dark place with absolutely no light...
鉄の…鉄の棒見て…
Staring at iron... iron bars...
明かりもない、やばい。明かりもない。
I don't even have a light, this is bad. No light.
え、どんな感じか、え？
Wait, what is it like?
ちょっと待って、逆に気になるまである、何これ？
Wait, now I'm actually curious. What is this?
もう水がなくて死にそう、早く助けて。
I'm about to die of thirst! Help me quick!
どうでした？あ、あ、
How was it? Oh, wait...
助けて！助けて！
Help! Help me!
やばい、トワ様があ、なんで？どうしたの？
Oh no, Towa-sama is... Why? What happened?
おねがい！
Please!
ちょっと待って、水、作って、作って、
Wait, make some water, make some!
あ、帰ってきた。あ、帰ってきた。
Oh, she's back. She's back.
あ、帰ってきた？え、え、じゃあ、ちょっと待って、皮袋に水をパンパンに詰めて、トワ様に運んで！
Oh, she's back? In that case, wait, fill up the waterskin to the brim and bring it to Towa-sama!
皮袋に、パンパンに詰めて？
Fill up the waterskin to the brim?
そういうミッションが。
That's your mission.
あ、水筒、水筒、わかりました。
Ah, canteen, canteen, got it.
詰めて、私のところに来てください。お願いします、早く！
Fill it and come to where I am! Please, hurry!
あ、またインベントリ開けない。あ、開けた。皮袋？
Ah, I can't open my inventory again. Oh, opened it. Waterskin?
あ、いい。皮袋作ってる、皮袋作ってる。ちょっと待って。
Ah, it's fine. I'm making waterskins, making waterskins. Wait a second.
あ、ビビ持ってる、ビビ持ってる、ビビ持ってる。
Oh, Bibi has them, Bibi has them, Bibi has them.
本当に？え、もう、あり得ない...
Really? Oh, this is unreal...
あー、マンモスできました！
Ah, the mammoth is tamed!
あ、ナイスナイス！ってことは...
Oh, nice, nice! That means...
できたかな？
Is it done?
うわー、黄色、ナイス！できました！
Whoa, yellow, nice! It's done!
やった、30種！
Yay, 30 species!
うわー、ナイス！ナイス！
Whoa, nice! Nice!
ちょっと待って、水飲めない、ここ。あ、これだけの事なのに、苛ち。
Wait, I can't drink water here. Ah, so irritating even though it's just this.
えっと、全てに苛ち。
Let's see... Everything is so irritating.
待ってね、これ今、めっちゃEボタンを連打して、
Wait, I'm spamming the E button like crazy right now,
あ、違うわ。ビビ皮袋持ってねえやん。
Ah, wait, no. Bibi doesn't have any waterskins.
渡す、渡す。ちょっと待ってね。これ、これもう全部渡すわ、これ。
I'll give them to you. Wait. I'll just give you all of these.
はーい！
Okay!
おら！水！
Here! Water!
水を早く、死んじゃいます！死んじゃう、早く水をください！
Bring the water quickly, I'm gonna die! I'm gonna die, give me water quick!
あと、こんがり肉も。
And some cooked meat, too.
ちょっと待って、なんか、待って。とんでもない量の皮袋が...
Wait a minute, look... There's an insane amount of waterskins...
え、もう、あり得ないぐらい作ったから。もういい、1個だけでいいから。
Yeah, because I made an unreal amount of them. It's fine, just one is enough.
はい、これを持ってきてください、お願いします！
Here, bring this over, please!
はい、1個だけでいいから、お願い、1個だけで。
Yeah, just one is fine, please, just one.
なんか、乗るやつ、乗るやつ、乗るやつ。どこに行けばいいですか？
Wait, how do I ride this thing? Where do I go to ride it?
あ、待って。集会場、集会場、集会場。
Ah, wait. The assembly point, the assembly point.
あ、集会場？じゃあもう、乗らなくていいや。
Ah, the assembly point? Then I don't need to ride it.
マンモスは入らない？
Won't the mammoth fit?
集会場で、水がいる？
Do you need water at the assembly point?
ここから降りちゃうと...
If I jump down from here...
集会場、水なかったっけ？
Wasn't there water at the assembly point?
え、待って、トワ様、待って。それ、集会場から、アスレでも結構、上まで登ってるってことですか？
Wait, Towa-sama, wait. Does that mean you climbed pretty high up the obstacle course from the assembly point?
あれ？あれ？
Huh? Huh?
あれ？トワ様いなくなった。
Huh? Towa-sama is gone.
え、落下のやつが、
Eh, she fell...
死んだかもしれん。
Maybe she died.
死んだ？
I died?
いや、わからん、わからん。
No, I don't know, I don't know.
トワ様どこだ？
Where is Towa-sama?
え、なんかね、集会場の近くにある、アスレの方にいるんだけど、トワ様今。
Well, I'm near the assembly point, on the obstacle course side right now.
アスレ？アスレがどこなのか、
Obstacle course? Where is that...
あの、あれして。あの、ビビ、Mで見る。
Can you do... that? Bibi, look at the map.
アルゲン、アルゲンで来て。アルゲンで。
Come on an Argentavis. On an Argentavis.
え、アルゲン？アルゲン？
Eh, Argentavis? Argentavis?
うん。
Yeah.
アルゲンで来て、トワのところ。
Come on an Argentavis to where I am.
逃げないでください！
Please don't run away!
ちょっと待って、アルゲンない、アルゲンない。
Wait a second, there are no Argentavis, no Argentavis.
ちょっと待って、ちょっと待って、どういう状況？何にも分からない、何にも分からない。
Wait a second, wait, what's going on? I have no idea what's happening.
もう何でもいいよ。
Anything is fine now.
え、身一つで来ていいんですか？
Eh, can I just come empty-handed?
うん。
Yeah.
これ、なんとか行けるとこですか？
Is this a place I can actually get to?
行けるとこ。上にいます。
You can get here. I'm up top.
え、ちょっと待って。これでしょ？
Wait, it's here, right?
え、どこや？あ、でも、アスレチックってこれ？もしかして。
Wait, where is it? Ah, but is this the obstacle course? Maybe.
アルゲン...アルゲンがいない。
Argentavis... There are no Argentavis.
あ、いたいた！トワ様の名前見えた！
Oh, there she is! I saw Towa-sama's name!
何？何何？何？
What? What is it? What happened?
何があったんだ？
What on earth happened?
来たよ。
I'm here.
どこ？ビビ、入り口に入ってきました。
Where? Bibi made it to the entrance.
上、上！
Up, up!
上？上、上なんか、え、身一つで来たから、上行けない。あれ、どこ？
Up? Up? Since I came empty-handed, I can't go up. Wait, where?
こっちだ！
Over here!
いたいたいた！何が起きてるんだ、こいつ、操縦が...
Found you! What is going on with this thing's controls...
え、ここを登れるんだ。
Oh, we can climb up here.
ハシゴ登れる、はや、はや。
We can climb the ladder, so fast.
はい。水ください。
Here. Water, please.
はい。
Okay.
そんなに水ない？これ、やり直すしかないの？なんかもう、コメントも「それは不正だ」とか言って。
Not that much water? Do we have to start over? Even the comments are saying, "That's cheating" and stuff.
もうダメみたい。
I guess it's no good.
え、嘘でしょ？はい、おら。
Eh, no way, right? Here.
や、ちょっとごめん、アスレチック無理だ、これ。
Yeah, sorry, the obstacle course is impossible for me.
じゃあ行くか、ゴルルガ。どこだ？
Well, shall we go, Golruga? Where is it?
いや、これ、無理かも。無理。
No, this might be impossible. Impossible.
そんなことあるの？
Can that even happen?
もうごめん、萎えた。この、今ので、全て萎えてしまいました。
I'm sorry, I lost all motivation. Everything that just happened took all my motivation away.
やばい、萎えてる。もう萎えた。
Oh no, she's demotivated. I'm completely demotivated.
一体何があったと言うんだ。
What on earth happened?
もう、やり直しならね、これ、辞めた方がいい。
If we have to restart, we should just quit.
え、そんな？
Eh, really?
これ、めっちゃ水ね、めっちゃ水持たないと、
We need a ton of water. If we don't bring a ton of water,
これ、水も飲む場所ないし、ご飯も食べる場所ないから。
there's nowhere to drink water or eat food here.
ここからね、どんどん渡っていかなきゃいけないんだよね。
We have to keep crossing from here, you see.
Yes, start.
今水もうないから、ビビもきついの？
You don't have any water right now, Bibi, so is it tough?
いや、きつい。でも、これ...
Yeah, it's tough. But...
これ、たぶん何十分かけても、1ポイントしか手に入らなくて。
Even if we spend tens of minutes on this, we'll only get 1 point.
Hello?
うん。
Yeah.
リタイアしてる。
They've retired.
じゃ、このライトニングワイバーン、ビビさんに貸すんで、ブロント時間、時間までこう...
Well, I'll lend this Lightning Wyvern to Bibi, and until the Bronto time...
チクチクしていく？
Can you chip away at it?
そうだね。
That's right.
もらう仕事お願いして、5回行ってきますよ。
I'll ask for some work and go five times.
はい。
Okay.
ちょっと行って... 行って何？ブロント？
Go over there... Go and do what? Bronto?
で、ライトニングワイバーン...
And the Lightning Wyvern...
どこいっちゃったの？
Where did it go?
あ、そう、あいつ乗っちゃって。
Oh, right, they rode off on it.
はい。
Okay.
あ、ちょっと、水大量にもらっていい？さっき、トワ様に落としたで...
Ah, can I get a lot of water? I dropped some for Towa earlier...
demo, towa no naka haitte iru wa.
But Towa has some inside.
すみません。
Sorry.
ありがとうございます。あ、もらっちゃいました。
Thank you. Oh, I got it.
おけ、おけ、おけ。あ、でも、持ってる。これ持ってる。
Okay, okay, okay. Oh, but I have it. I have this.
Can you open the door?
これ、落としていきます？無理？
Shall I drop this off? Is it impossible?
あ、本当？じゃあ、落としたやつ...
Oh, really? Then the one I dropped...
Can you hear me? Hello?
ありました。
I found it.
Hello? Can you hear me?
もうちょっとしか入ってないから意味なさそう。
There's only a little bit left, so it seems useless.
一旦、飲んでるよ。
I'm drinking for now.
Hello? Please.
乗ってるよ。
I'm riding it.
一旦、何があって、そんな壊れちまったんだ...
What on earth happened to make it break like that?
Is my mic not working?
壊されてる。
It's broken.
ビビは、ビビもこれ飛んでていいですか？
As for Bibi, is it okay if I fly with this too?
いいよ。いいよ。
Yes, it is. Go ahead.
何が、あ、あの、ブロントサウルスを倒してほしい。大きいやつ。
What we want, ah, we want you to defeat the Brontosaurus. The big one.
ブロントサウルス？どこに？
A Brontosaurus? Where?
えっと。
Let me see.
Thank you!
ブロントサウルス？
A Brontosaurus?
そう、めっちゃ大きいやつ。首長くて。
Yes, a really big one. With a long neck.
あれ？さっきいた、あ、そう、そう、そう、そう。
Wait? There was one earlier... Ah, yes, yes, yes, yes.
あれを、5体で1ポイントもらえるから。
Defeating five of them gives us 1 point.
出会ってないな。
I haven't encountered one.
水くれ！
Give me water!
これ、どうしたらいいの？あ、ん？これは...
What should I do about this? Ah, huh? This is...
In-game chat options... Do I have like push-to-talk on or something? Oh.
あ、こう行くのか。はい、はい、はい、はい。
Oh, that's how you do it. Okay, okay, okay, okay.
あ、違うな。
Oh, that's not it.
ブロントサウルス。
Brontosaurus.
あ、はい、はい、はい、はい。
Oh, yes, yes, yes, yes.
マイクラの、あ...
Minecraft's, ah...
なんか、横ですげえ声。
What a crazy voice right next to me.
なんか、横からすげえ声聞こえるんだけど。
I can hear a crazy voice from beside me.
I think... I think she still can't hear me.
I guess we never used in-game chat, huh? Or in-game voice.
急にいないな。ブロントサウルス。
Suddenly, there are none. The Brontosaurus.
何が起きていたんだ？
What on earth was happening?
これ登るのむず。
This is so hard to climb.
あれ？
Huh?
あ、結構...
Ah, quite a lot...
え、わかんない。まあいっか。
Uh, I don't know. Oh well.
まあいっか。
Oh well.
はい。I actually turned it off.
Yes. I actually turned it off.
Oh, it didn't save.
なるほど。
I see.
You don't want to talk to people, when...
あ、これが、無所と言われているのか？
Ah, is this what they call the "prison"?
ござるキャラクターでっけえからな、向いてないかもね、確かに。
Gozaru's character is huge, so it might not be suited, indeed.
Meow meow.
Meow meow?
どうなんだろう？これが...
I wonder how it is. Is this...
Is still that working?
Is that still working?
あ、はい、はい、はい、はい。
Ah, yes, yes, yes, yes.
やった！
Yay!
Yeah.
Okay. I can talk too.
調子がいいのが、絶妙にわからないな、このゲーム。
I can't quite tell if things are going well in this game.
I set up the input and stuff.
お、そうですね。あ、いけました。えーっと、で...
Oh, right. Ah, it worked. Let's see, and then...
お、はい、はい、はい、はい。
Oh, yes, yes, yes, yes.
あ、でも、これキャラコむずくて草。
Ah, but the character controls are so hard, lol.
わかんない。
I don't know.
これどこに行きゃいいんだ？次は。こっちか。
Where should I go now? Next. This way?
あ、はい、はい、はい、はい。上？
Ah, yes, yes, yes, yes. Up?
お、これか？
Oh, is it this?
ん？
Huh?
どこに...
Where is it...
どこに... どこに...
Where... Where is it...
あ...
Ah...
う...
Uh...
え、これどっから上あがるの？まじ。
Seriously, where do I go up from here?
Oh, it's back.
It works!
I thought it was too quiet so I pumped up the game, but it's...
これどこに行くの？
Where is this going?
目の前が隙間、扉みたいなとこ。ははははは。
There's a gap in front of me, like a door. Hahaha.
ん？
Hmm?
お、飛んでる
Oh, it's flying.
飛んでる
Flying...
1時間ぐらいの難易度なんだ。
It's about an hour's worth of difficulty.
おお。
Oh boy.
I sounded like I... my microphone for a second?
I did.
I did though. I did.
心折れてた。やばい。
My heart was breaking. This is bad.
Oh, is there anything we can do for the last 15 minutes?
I don't think so.
あ、あれ？奥に行けんか。あ、これか。はい、はい、はい、はい。
Ah, wait, can we go further in? Ah, this? Okay, okay, okay, okay.
So, search how to tame...
理解、理解。理解、理解。はい、はい、はい。
I understand, I understand. Yes, yes, yes.
これ、確かにご飯がなくてキツイね。
This is indeed tough without food.
"Extremely rare." Okay.
One unicorn can exist on an active map simultaneously.
Okay, I don't think we're doing that in 15 minutes.
あ、無理。こうか。
Ah, impossible. Is it like this?
で、こう。あー。
And then like this. Ah...
体でけぇ。
Its body is huge.
届かねぇ。
I can't reach.
DPS届くか？お？
Can my DPS reach? Oh?
はい。
Okay.
We need a...
はい。
Yes.
...ghillie, and then feed it berries, right?
What if we get really lucky?
Eh? North side of the map?
Was it the purple berries, right? Mejoberries.
Which area? Should be like a map of the spawns.
In the plains.
Like where Patches is? Wait, that's...
...Ragnarok, okay. Oh, it's in the north...
...something corner, okay.
You know what? Row, row, fight the power.
Do the impossible.
Where's my hat?
I lost my hat.
All right.
Row, row, fight the power.
こっちかな？
Is it this way?
で、上に行って...
And go up...
こっちか。
This way, huh.
Does it glow in the dark?
Fly north until you hit water, then turn right.
Or I can just go straight diagonally.
10 minutes.
Oh, wyverns.
I should get stamina back.
Mejoberries, tasukaru.
Mejoberries help a lot.
Yeah, row, row, fight the power.
この辺かな？
Around here?
Oops.
ただいまー！
I'm back!
倒せました！
We defeated it!
お疲れ様です！
Good job, everyone!
お疲れ様です。
Good job.
アスレチックどこでやるの、これ？
Where do we do the obstacle course?
集会所だったかな？
Was it at the meeting place?
はい。
Yes.
集会所？
The meeting place?
うん。
Yeah.
どこだ？
Where is it?
出口ひとつ...出口、外。
There's only one exit... the exit outside.
これか。
Is it this?
はい。
Yes.
ジャンピングアスレチックができますよ、フブキ先輩。
You can do a jumping obstacle course, Fubuki-senpai.
めっちゃやりたい！めっちゃやりたい！
I really want to do it! I really want to do it!
どこどこどこどこ？
Where, where, where?
ありえないぐらい慣性付きの、ジャンピングアスレチックが楽しめますよ。
You can enjoy a jumping obstacle course with unbelievable inertia.
最高すぎる、最高すぎる、最高すぎる。
That's too awesome, too awesome!
ちなみにラプトル用意してます、そこで。
By the way, I have a raptor ready there.
ラプトル用意ときました。
I set up a raptor for it.
これ恐竜で入ったら怒られますか？
Will I get in trouble if I go in with a dinosaur?
怒られると思う。
I think you will.
ここ？ここ？どこ？
Here? Here? Where?
心が折れそうな人が３人ぐらいいる。
There are about three people who look like they're about to give up.
これか？
Is it this?
はい、ジャンプしろ！
Yes, jump!
ライトニングワイバーンで探しまくったけど、恐竜は...
I searched all over with my lightning wyvern, but the dinosaurs are...
水分やば。
My water level is so low.
これ？
This?
アスレチックやろう。
Let's do the obstacle course.
防具だけで...これだけで...
Just with this... just with this...
水分、水分なさすぎてやばい。
Water, my water level is so low it's bad.
確かに、低体温症。
True, hypothermia.
全然ないんですけど。
I don't have any at all.
これか？
Is it this?
無理。
No way.
まず、こっちから飛べ。
First, fly from here.
ふわぁってなるの、これ？
Does it go whoosh?
わかんない。
I don't know.
心ね。
Their hearts, right?
うわぁ。
Whoa.
これ、こっち？
Is it this way?
どうぞ。ユニコーンって光る？
Go ahead. Does the unicorn glow?
あ、間違えた。
Ah, I made a mistake.
見える？あそこ、助数必要？
Can you see it? Do we need a count there?
あれ、助数いいの、これ？
Wait, is a count okay?
誰々先輩とか得意そう、これ。
Some senpai would probably be good at this.
まじで？
Really?
挙動、よくわからないよね。
We don't really know how it behaves, right?
なんか、戻り入力入れると...
Like, if you input a reverse action...
これ、届かないかな？
Won't this reach?
あぁ、なるほど。
Ah, I see.
ラプトルみたいな、カチッていうタイプの戻りだったら、ストッピングできます。
If it's a click-type reverse like a raptor, you can stop it.
そういうことね。
I see.
そうなんですよね。
Yeah, exactly.
カチッ。
Click.
最悪や。
This is the worst.
こういうことか。
Oh, is that how it is?
え？
What?
そういうつもりじゃなかった。
I didn't mean to do that.
１人称視点の方がいいのかな？
Maybe first-person view is better?
１人称の方が、制御しやすい気はしてます。
I feel like first-person is easier to control.
誰かクリアした？
Did anyone clear it?
いや、なんかみんな心が折れてボロボロらしいですよ、そこ。
No, apparently everyone is broken-hearted and exhausted over there.
うわぁ、めっちゃ行きたいけど。
Wow, I really want to go, but...
ちょっとむずいな。時間的に間に合わないかな？
It's a bit hard. Maybe we won't make it in time?
うわぁ、ころね。
Whoa, Korone.
おいで。
Come here.
これ...
This...
え、すごい。早っ、ボタン先輩。
Whoa, amazing. So fast, Botan-senpai.
トントントン。
Hop, hop, hop.
ボタン先輩、行けました？
Botan-senpai, did you make it?
足が引っかかるとこと引っかかんないとこがある。
There are places where your feet get caught and places where they don't.
まじ？
Really?
すごい、あ、行けた、行けた！
Amazing! Ah, I made it, I made it!
ナイス。
Nice.
そもそもはしごをどうやって上がるんだっけ？
Wait, how do we climb the ladder in the first place?
なんか...
Like...
カーソル合わせると...
When you aim the cursor...
これ...
This...
出る。
It shows up.
え、これどうやって登るの？
Wait, how do you climb this?
Ｅボタン。
E button.
Ｅボタン？
E button?
Ｅボタンかな？
E button, maybe?
Ｅボタン。
E button.
これ、爪どうなの？
What about the claws?
逆に。
On the contrary.
あ、これで。
Ah, with this.
これ。
This.
１個ずつじゃねえ、騙されるな、これ。
It's not one by one, don't be fooled by this.
１個ずつじゃない？
Not one by one?
あ、いたいた。
Ah, there they are.
それでも...
Even so...
ボタン先輩、お疲れ様。
Botan-senpai, good job.
それでも...
Even so...
最悪。行けたのに。
The worst. I almost made it.
これ、１個あれ、どこなんだろう？
Wait, where is the other one?
１個か。
Just one?
みんなやってるな。
Everyone is working hard.
あぁ。
Ah.
めっちゃ煽られてるやん。
They're getting teased so much.
あれ、めっちゃ煽られてる、トワ様。
Oh, Towa-sama is getting teased so much.
何故かな？
I wonder why?
横かな？
Is it to the side?
うわぁ。
Whoa.
あれ、ここ何だっけ？
Wait, what was this place?
あ、死んだ。
Ah, I died.
なんでか。
Why?
いや、まあまあやったから、いっか。
Well, I did okay, so I guess it's fine.
あ、マップ入れちゃった。
Ah, I opened the map.
ドードー、ドードー。
Dodo! Dodo!
あ、これ、アスレチックいけるということ？
Ah, but does this mean we can do the parkour?
ユニコーン...
Unicorn...
末永く溶岩洞窟で一緒ってこと。
It means we'll be together in the lava cave forever.
これどこだ、アスレチック？えーっと...
Where is the parkour? Let's see...
うーん、アスレチック is どれだ？
Hmm, which one is the parkour?
これか！アスレチックあった！みんなやってる！
Is it this? There's the parkour! Everyone's doing it!
あれ？これ戻ってきてるやつじゃん。草。
Wait? We're going backwards on this one. Lol.
戻ってんじゃん。
We're going backwards.
ユニコーン...
Unicorn...
あ、引っかかっちゃう。
Ah, I'm getting caught.
あ、寒っ。
Ah, it's cold.
あ、もうちょっと勢いか。
Ah, do I need a bit more speed?
あっちもある？
Is there one over there too?
あ、で、真ん中か。
Ah, and then the middle?
あ、なんかジャンプ２回押しちゃった。
Ah, I pressed jump twice for some reason.
Yeah, it's not about taming it now, it's about seeing it.
It's real.
About...
あ、いいか。
Ah, is this fine?
Journey... あ。
Journey... Ah.
It's for myself, not the points.
三角。
Triangle.
三角...
Triangle...
三角...これ何だこれ？
Triangle... What is this?
これ、これどうすればいいんだ？
What, what should I do with this?
この三角どうすんだ？
What do I do with this triangle?
は？これどうすんだ？
Huh? What do I do with this?
ん？
Hmm?
これ、ど、ど...
What, ho, ho...
ユニコーン...
Unicorn...
あれか？
Is it that?
あれ？これ戻ってきちゃった。またここ戻ってきてる。
Wait? I came back. I'm back here again.
え？これどこだ？どこどここれ？
Eh? Where is this? Where, where is this?
は？あ、上か！
Huh? Ah, is it up?
上か！
It's up!
あ、誰か見つかったかな？ユニコーン。
Ah, did someone find it? The unicorn.
んで、あっちか？
And then, is it over there?
あっち、あっちか？
Over there, is it over there?
あ、落ちちゃった。
Ah, I fell.
あ、イベント終了だあ！
Ah, the event is over!
あー。
Ah...
あ、これアスレチック行けたな？
Ah, could we have cleared the parkour?
おつ。
Good work.
あ、ちょっと足りない？
Ah, is it a bit short?
まあまあ、a beautiful way to end
Well, a beautiful way to end
my first Ark... Ark? Ark ark.
Oh, so foggy.
I don't know where I'm going.
To the moon!
Yeah, there is no unicorn.
No, it's like, I don't remember where the teleporter was, I guess where Shishiron is.
Yeah, it's so peaceful.
Ooh, big white cave.
ござる、ごめん。白組ボイチャが使えなくて。
Gozaru, sorry. The Shirogumi voice chat isn't working.
あ、なるほど。
Ah, I see.
すまぬ。
Sorry.
あ、お腹空きすぎて気絶する！
Ah, I'm too hungry, I'm going to pass out!
ご飯...
Food...
やばい。
This is bad.
気絶したらその時や。
If you pass out, then so be it.
気絶したらその時！
If you pass out, so be it!
うわ、ベビ猫ちゃん。
Wow, baby kitty.
Ooh, what is this place?
ご飯、なんかベリーか何かで凌げそうっすか？
For food, do you think we can get by on berries or something?
何もない。全裸で来ちゃった。
I have nothing. I came here completely naked.
ベリー...
Berries...
ベリーならありますよ。ベリー要ります？
I have berries. Do you want some?
ベリー欲しいけど、ここまで来ちゃったから...
I want berries, but since we've already come this far...
じゃあ、帰ってきたら取れるベリー...
Then when we get back, the berries we can harvest...
あざす、あざす、あざす、あざす。もう気絶値やばい。
Thanks, thanks, thanks, thanks. My torpor level is already super high.
Ah, I'm over that too.
Basically where the last death is. I think that's where...
あ、ライトニングワイバーンだ、これ。
Ah, this is a Lightning Wyvern.
え、45分までどこまでいけるかな、これ。
How far can we go by 45 minutes?
さっきのやつや。
It's the one from earlier.
ビビが乗り捨てたやつワイバーン。
The wyvern that Bibi abandoned.
あ、ござるのです。
Ah, it's Gozaru's.
乗り捨てたやつ？
The abandoned one?
Yeah, and her bunny.
ござる先輩のやつ乗り捨てた。
I abandoned Gozaru-senpai's one.
悲しい。
How sad.
乗り捨てワイバーン。
The abandoned wyvern.
間違えた。
I made a mistake.
優しくして欲しい。
Please be gentle.
There you are.
よいしょ。
Heave-ho.
生体音。
Biological sound.
あれ、来ないな。
Huh, it's not coming.
あ、固まってしまったんだ。
Ah, it got stuck.
柱にぶつからず。
Without hitting the pillars.
わーい。なんかあそこの3番目でいつも引っかかっちゃうな。
Yay. I always get caught on the third one over there.
難しいですよね、この3番目のここ。
It's difficult, this third part here.
ね。
Yeah.
がんばって！
Good luck!
なんか、感性左入れたら行きやすくなってたけど、どうなんだろう。
I felt like putting inertia to the left made it easier, but I wonder.
demo, kansei hayame ni iresugiru to, nanka karada ga hajiku no ka shinnai kedo, norenai nazu desu yo ne.
But if you put inertia in too early, I don't know if the body bounces off, but you can't ride it, right?
ね。
Yeah.
へえ。
Oh.
あ、来た来た来た来た。
Ah, here it comes, here it comes!
起きた。うそ。
It woke up. No way.
起きた、起きた、起きた。
It's up, it's up, it's up.
あ、行けなかった、行けなかった、行けなかった。
Ah, I couldn't go, I couldn't go.
あ、行けた。
Ah, I made it.
うんこでもするか、久しぶりに。
Maybe I'll take a poop, for the first time in a while.
その、久しぶりに。
Yeah, for the first time in a while.
あ、トイレで。
Ah, in the toilet.
トイレで。
In the toilet.
久しぶりのトイレ。
A toilet visit after a long time.
なんかもう、最後、うんこする暇なかったからな。
Like, at the end, there was no time to poop.
垂れ流し、垂れ流し。
Just letting it out, letting it out.
トイレ寄る時間がなかったわ。
There was no time to drop by the toilet.
トイレ熱かったの、最初からや。
The toilet has been hot from the very beginning.
確かに、お前。
True, you...
ね。
Yeah.
なんか、ビビのワイバーン、追従してるよ。大丈夫？
Bibi's wyvern is following us. Is it okay?
え？嘘！来てる？あ、本当だ、来てる、来てる。
Eh? No way! It is? Ah, you're right, it's coming, it's coming.
すげえ、ワイバーンかっこいいな。
Wow, wyverns are so cool.
どうやって乗るの？こっちにおいで。
How do you ride it? Come here.
え、なんかバグって時計が、命の砂時計、あと10分か。命の砂時計、あと10分。
Wait, the clock is bugged, the hourglass of life has 10 minutes left. Hourglass of life, 10 minutes.
結構離れた方がいいかもね。
It might be better to stay quite far away.
45分から閉会式ですよね。
The closing ceremony is from 45 minutes, right?
うん、そう。そうそう。
Yes, that's right. Yes, yes.
じゃ、それまでここで...
Then until then, here...
来た、来た、来た、来た。
They're here, they're here!
あれ？何？何？
Huh? What is it? What?
ええ？何、何、今の？
Eh? What was that just now?
うん、うん。
Yeah, yeah.
よいしょ。
Heave-ho.
どこかな？
Where is it?
heikaishiki no suteeji, girigiri de ikou kana to omotteta gozaru. chotto ano, ippai hito ga atsumattara, mimi ga shinisou.
Gozaru was thinking of going to the closing ceremony stage at the last minute. Because if a lot of people gather, my ears might die.
確かに。
Indeed.
そうね。
Right.
なんか、めっちゃアスレチックに鍛えられた...
Somehow, I've been trained so much by the obstacle course...
この、この先なんだ。
It's beyond this, this part.
もう、ここの先に行ったらゴールだったのか。
Ah, if I had gone past here, it would have been the goal?
くそ、アスレチック。
Damn that obstacle course.
三角のとこね。
The triangle part, right?
アスレチック、ワンチャンあったな。
There was a chance for the obstacle course.
絶対行けるよ。
You can definitely do it.
はい、はい、はい、はい！
Yes, yes, yes, yes!
絶対行けるかな？
Can I definitely do it?
いや、全然、全然。
No, completely, completely.
じゃあ、もう交代して。
Then, let's swap now.
交代すればよかったね
We should've swapped, huh.
あそこジャンプでいい感じに...
Jumping nicely over there...
でももう1時間くらいはいたけど無理だったな
But even after staying for another hour, it was impossible.
あ、沼り散らかしてた？
Ah, were you totally struggling?
うん
Yeah.
あいよ
Here we go.
三角のところ何回か行ったけど
I went to the triangle area a few times, but...
なんか上にやっぱり板があってジャンプがシビアだから
there was a ceiling above, so the jump was really tight.
あ、ここなのか！なるほどね。この最後のとこね。
Ah, so it's here! I see. This last part, right?
うん
Yeah.
そこが結構シビアで。
That part is pretty tight.
お手洗い行ってきます。
I'm heading to the restroom.
お願いします。閉会式のゲーム内ボイス何も聞こえないんだよね、きっと。
Go ahead. I probably won't be able to hear any in-game voice during the closing ceremony.
あ、画面共有すればいいんじゃない？
Ah, why don't you screen share?
あ、いいね。
Ah, that works.
助かりんちょ。助かりんちょ。
That helps so much! That helps!
ナイス。
Nice.
あとちょっと頑張ろう。
Let's do our best just a bit longer.
タイミングが掴めれば...
If only we can get the timing down...
ワンチャンいけたのかな...
I wonder if we could've made it.
どうだった？ていうか、あのボス。
How was it? I mean, that boss.
いや、ボスはね... 大変だったな。
Well, the boss... was pretty tough.
大変だったよ。
It really was tough.
クリアはしてましたよね？
But you did clear it, right?
うん、クリアはできた、そう。
Yeah, we were able to clear it. Right.
何がダメだったの？
What went wrong then?
リポップが来なくてね。そう。
The respawn didn't happen. Right.
ああ、なるほど。
Ah, I see.
リポップ待ちだった。そう。
We were waiting for the respawn. Yeah.
「これ沸くかな？」みたいな感じで言って、上さんに行ったら沸かしてもらえたから。
We were like, "Will it spawn?" and when we asked the admin, they spawned it for us.
ああ！そうそうそう。
Ah, right, right, right!
よかったね。
That was great.
え、あれ上がれたんですか？下から。
Wait, were you able to get up there from below?
下からあれを上げてもらった。あとバグってたからね、今日ドアが。
We had them raise it from below. Also, the door was a bit bugged today.
前だったっけ？こっちだったっけ？
Was it in front? Was it this way?
よかったですね。でもなんか色々バグたまにあったけど...
I'm glad it worked out. Though there were some bugs here and there...
よかった、よかった。
I'm glad, I'm glad.
よいしょ。
Alright.
嬉しかったよ、あのアスレ。
I was so happy about that parkour.
アスレにいるときに「お片付けできるもん」が
While doing parkour, a notification popped up saying...
マル秘ミッションをクリアしましたって出てくれて。
...'Okataduke Dekirumon cleared the secret mission!'
よかった！ギリギリ間に合ってよかった！
Awesome! I'm so glad we made it just in time!
「ワンチャン間に合わないかも」みたいに言ってたからね。
Since you were saying, "We might not make it."
結構ギリギリだったんだ。
Ah, so it was really down to the wire.
そうそうそうそう。
Yeah, exactly.
でもマジでナイス！
But seriously, nice job!
すみません、私がアスレできなくて...！
I'm so sorry that I couldn't do the parkour...!
テイムはいけたんだっけ？結局。
Were you able to tame it in the end?
テイムはいけたんですけど...
We managed to tame it, but...
ティラノが全然見つからなくて。
we couldn't find a Rex at all.
ああ、みんなティラノ狩りしてたんだろ、多分。
Ah, everyone was probably hunting Rexes.
そう、もうティラノはいけませんでした、足りなくて。
Yeah, we couldn't get a Rex because we ran out.
あららら...
Oh dear...
でもナイスファイトだよ！ナイスファイト！
But nice fight! Good effort!
頑張りましたよ、みんな。
Everyone did their best.
ティラノ完売。もういません。
Rexes are sold out. There are none left.
よいしょ。
Up we go.
ユニコーンも見つからずでした。
We couldn't find the Unicorn either.
ユニコーン！
Unicorn!
人参持ってめっちゃ待機してたのに。
Even though I was waiting with carrots.
いつでも上げられるようにね。ユニコーンも人参食べたかっただろうな。
Ready to feed it anytime. The Unicorn probably wanted to eat carrots too.
このワールドのどこかで泣いてるよ。
It's crying somewhere in this world.
しくしく。見つけてもらえなくて悲しい、悲しい。
"I'm so sad no one found me."
どこにいるんだろうな、本当に。
I wonder where it actually is.
どっかには絶対にいる。
It's definitely out there somewhere.
伝説じゃないんだ。
It's not just a legend.
このワールドに1匹だけ存在する。
Only one exists in this world.
1匹だけっていうのがなかなかですよね。
Having only one makes it quite rare.
見てみたかったな、ユニコーン。
I wanted to see the Unicorn.
ロマン。この鯖で1匹。
It's romantic. Just one on this server.
デモ、見つけに行く時間なかった、余裕。
But we didn't have time to look for it.
そうね。
True.
ちょっと早いのかな？
Is it a bit early?
ヘイヘイヘイ。よいしょ。
Hey, hey, hey. Up we go.
ほい。あそこどうやって乗ろう？
There. How do we get on that?
なんか雪フクロウが...
Looks like a Snow Owl...
雪フクロウだ！いいな、雪フクロウ。
It's a Snow Owl! I'm jealous of the Snow Owl.
ええと、どうしよ。雪フクロウ。
Let's see, what should I do? Snow Owl...
あ、なんかここ行けなくなっちゃった。
Oh, looks like I can't go this way anymore.
空中機動変化。
Aerial maneuver shift.
あ、レアポップだけどないんだ。なんか1匹だけしか沸かないみたいな。
Ah, so it's a rare spawn, but none are here. Like, only one spawns at a time.
へえ。1匹ずつなのかな。
Oh. I wonder if they spawn one by one.
よいしょ。
Alright.
よいしょ。うんち魔だ。
Alright. Poop monsters.
あ、行けない。
Ah, I can't go through.
ここの三角1個目までは登れるんだけどな。
I can climb up to the first triangle here, though.
あ、変なキー入れちゃった今。
Ah, I pressed the wrong key just now.
もういっちょプレスするよ。
I'll press it one more time.
またご飯が足りなくなってるな。水もない。
I'm running low on food again. No water either.
頑張れ、頑張れ。
Hang in there! You can do it!
よ。
Okay.
あ、もう水なくね？もう水ねえや。
Ah, is there no water left? There's no water.
水分が... 水ないです。
Hydration is... I have no water.
よいしょ。
Alright.
俺のプテラが...
My Ptera...
えーっと。
Let's see.
あ、上れなくなっちゃった、もう。
Ah, I can't climb up anymore.
雪フクロウ可愛い！
Snow Owls are so cute!
雪フクロウいいよね、回復もできるし。
Snow Owls are great, right? They can also heal.
大好き、雪フクロウ。
I love Snow Owls.
優秀、優秀。
They're so useful, so useful.
これも回復して、一緒に固まって。頼む、あ。
Heal this too, please. Gather together. Please. Ah.
あれを、あれをしたいんだよ。
I want to do that, that.
よいしょ、ちょっと一旦出ちゃう。よいしょ。
Alright, let me get out for a bit. Alright.
えーっと、着替えもして。ふう。
Let's see, change clothes too. Whew.
上空にワイバーン君が。よいしょ。
Mr. Wyvern is up in the sky. Alright.
取る取る取る。
Taking, taking, taking...
1時間やってるからですよ。もう、ここはザラに。
Because we've been doing it for an hour. This is already common.
ズッタズッタズッタ。お、なんか。
Zutta, zutta, zutta. Oh, something...
よいしょ、りゅい。
Alright, whew.
今、集計中なんだろうな。
They must be tallying the results now.
うん、多分ね。
Yeah, probably.
集会所の恐竜。
The dinosaurs at the meeting place.
にょ、恐竜。
Nyo, dinosaurs.
え、ちょっと解き放ったワイバーン、ちょっと何で解き放ってきちゃったんですか？
Wait, you released the Wyvern? Why did you release it?
ワイバーン。
Wyvern...
ワイバーンどこいるんだ？
Where is the Wyvern?
そこにいるワイバーン。
The Wyvern over there.
あ、乗ってるのか。乗ってるならいいか。
Ah, is someone riding it? If they're riding it, then it's fine.
ほな、ほな、いいか。
Then, then, it's fine.
ほな。
Then.
ズッタズッタ。
Zutta, zutta.
demo, monbo ga nai na.
But we don't have Cryopods.
モンボール、集会所の中にあるよ。うん。
Cryopods are inside the meeting place. Yeah.
よいしょ。
Alright.
ワンワンしまった方がいいか？ワンワン来てるか？
Should we put away the dogs? Are they coming?
ツェッペリン。
Zeppelin.
ツェッペリンに乗っていくぜ、集会所に。
I'm going to the meeting place in the Zeppelin.
いいね。
Nice.
ツェッペリン持ってきて、スバルちゃん。
Bring the Zeppelin, Subaru-chan.
みんなでツェッペリンに乗って、集会所のど真ん中でツェッペリンで鎮座しよう。
Let's all get on the Zeppelin and settle down in the middle of the meeting place.
ツェッペリン取りに行くか。
Let's go get the Zeppelin.
今、取ってる取ってる、持って行ってる持って行ってる。
We're getting it now, we're bringing it.
水の耐久値ないから...
Since there's no water durability...
あ、ごめんごめん。水邪魔すぎる、これ。
Ah, sorry, sorry. This water is too much in the way.
水やばい、自分も。やばい、水分やばかった。
The water is bad for me too. Oh no, my hydration was really low.
水もねえや。
I don't have water either.
飲ませて。
Let me drink.
ちょっと待ってね。
Hold on a second.
はい。
Okay.
体痛。
My body hurts.
戻るど、戻るど。
Going back, going back.
お、お、お、ごめん。
Oh, oh, oh, sorry.
あ、ママ、水に吸い込まれる。
Ah, Mama is getting sucked into the water.
子犬...
Puppies...
ちょっと...ごめん。
Wait... Sorry.
いいかなって。
I wonder if it's fine.
ちょっと待って、オプションで...
Wait a minute. In the options...
ちゃうちゃうちゃうちゃう。
No, no, no, no.
はい、お待たせしました。すみません。
Yes, sorry for the wait. Excuse me.
ツェッペリンって、あれ、テレポーター乗れたんですか？
Wait, could you ride the teleporter with the Zeppelin?
乗れないから今移動しようとしている。
We can't ride it, so we're trying to move it now.
ああ、なるほどな。
Ah, I see.
よ。空赤！何だこれ。
Yo. The sky is red! What is this?
閉会式？
Closing ceremony?
よいしょ、ほり。
Alright, there.
今ここ。おーい。
We are here now. Oh.
閉会式中に絶対めちゃくちゃご飯とか足りなくなるやつじゃん。
We're definitely going to run out of food during the closing ceremony.
ワイバーンどこ行った？
Where did the Wyvern go?
どこだ？会場ってどこにあるんですか？
Where is it? Where is the venue?
あ、めっちゃデカイうんちしてる。
Ah, it's taking a huge poop.
緑ポイントに。持っちゃおう。
At the green point. Let's take it.
最初、一番最初のところなのかな？
Is it the very first place?
ツェッペリンって梯子降ろせたらしい。
Apparently, you can lower the ladder on the Zeppelin.
へぇ、そうそう、横に梯子ってのがあったんだよ。
Huh. Yeah, there was a ladder on the side.
へぇ、知らなかった。
Huh, I didn't know.
知らなかった。
I didn't know.
よいしょ。
Alright.
いっぱいあれだね。今回は新しい知らないことがいっぱいあったけど、みんな頑張れたね。
There was a lot of that. There were many new things we didn't know this time, but everyone did their best.
いや、本当だよ。うん。凄かった。
Yeah, really. Yeah. It was amazing.
よいしょ。いや...
Alright. Wow...
やったことないマップだったから、とうも全く分からなかったな。
It was a map we'd never played on, so I had no idea at all.
結構システム、ASAでしたっけ？それも含めて変わってましたからね。
The system changed a lot, including ASA, right?
恐竜とかもね、その、使い方がとか、新しい恐竜とかを調べたりしてね。
Even the dinosaurs, like how to use them, and researching new dinosaurs.
ね。
Right.
あ、ちょっと、雪山を越えなきゃね、雪山やば。
Ah, wait, we have to cross the snowy mountain. The snowy mountain is dangerous.
ここに行け。
Go here.
ここに行け？
Go here?
始まる？
Is it starting?
よいしょ、始まるらしいぞ。始まるか。
Alright, looks like it's starting. Is it starting?
よいしょ。ちょっと待とう。
Alright. Let's wait a bit.
やばい、人いっぱいやって。人いっぱいすぎてやばいかも。やばい待って。
Oh no, there are so many people. It might be bad because there are too many people. Wait.
ちょいちょい重くて。
It's a bit laggy.
ふう、よし。これどうですか？見えてます？
Phew, okay. How is this? Can you see?
お、いいと。
Oh, good.
ありがたい。
Thank you.
なんかあっという間だったな、ガチで。
It felt like it went by in a flash, seriously.
あっという間だけど、何で何でこんなに濃いんだろうな。
It went by in a flash, but why was it so packed?
あ、すごい！
Oh, amazing!
まぶしい
It's bright!
確かに これから...
Indeed, from now...
まぶしい
It's so bright!
眩しい... えっと
Bright... let's see...
うんと...
Hmm...
水、水が欲しい... そんなのなかったんだ
Water, I want water... We didn't have that.
お？ やばい、なんかめっちゃ...
Oh? Oh no, there's a lot of...
水、水が...
Water, water...
誰か殴ってる！
Someone is punching!
傷が、傷がつく！やめやめ！
We're taking damage! Stop it!
水が... 誰か水...
Water... Someone, water...
死んじゃう、死んじゃいますよ！
I'm gonna die, someone is gonna die!
How does it feel? It feels like...
傷がつくだろ！ 誰か殴り合ってる！
You're damaging it! Some people are fighting!
うわ、やべえ！大丈夫、大丈夫ですか？
Wow, crazy! Is everyone okay?
あ、やばい！ 大大丈夫か？
Ah, oh no! Are you alright?
水が... 解除...
Water... Deactivate...
水、水欲しい。1個だけあるけど...
Water, I want water. I have just one, though...
誰かが食べてる。
Someone is eating.
水？ ベリー食べた。
Water? I ate some berries.
会場にいないけど、会場の声はこれじゃなきゃ聞こえないから、声は大丈夫や。
I'm not at the venue, but since we can't hear the venue's voice without this, the voice is fine.
一回しまって... 聞こえてる、ありがとう。
Put it away once... I can hear, thank you.
犬しまいたいんだけどさ、エイムが全然合わなくて。
I want to put the dog away, but my aim is totally off...
ボール入んないよね。
The ball won't go in, right?
ナイス！ 集まり次第始めていきますので、
Nice! We will start as soon as everyone is gathered,
ご静粛にお願いいたします。
so please be quiet.
誰か入れてくれない？ 水、水、医者...
Can someone put me in? Water, water, doctor...
ここだと入んないのかな。
Maybe it won't go in here?
眩しい、ホントに眩しい！
Bright, really bright!
ペコラが落ちてる。厳しくない？
Pekora disconnected. Isn't it tough?
外に連れ出そうか？ それがいいかも。
Shall we take them outside? That might be good.
みんなボリボリ食ってる。
Everyone is munching away.
あ、なんか設定あった気がする。
Ah, I feel like there was a setting for that.
まだ集まれてないチームメンバーはいますか？
Are there any team members who haven't gathered yet?
大丈夫かな。ペコちゃん落ちたかも。
I wonder if it's okay. Peko-chan might have disconnected.
あ、今ね、再起動してる、あきちゃん。ちょっと待ちましょう。
Ah, right now Aki-chan is restarting. Let's wait a bit.
どうやってするの？
How do you do it?
フブキ先輩がVC聞こえなくなっちゃったみたいで、画面共有で見てるんで、一旦こっちは大丈夫です。
It seems Fubuki-senpai can't hear the VC anymore, so she's watching via screen share, we're fine for now.
了解しました。解除したよ。
Understood. I deactivated it.
お疲れ！ どうやってやるんですか、それ？
Thanks for your hard work! How do you do that?
ハロー。フラフラ...
Hello. Dizzy...
聞こえない。
Can't hear.
あ、戻った、戻った。はあはあ。
Ah, she's back, she's back. Huff puff...
ペコラ帰ってきた？ペコラいける？ペコラ大丈夫そうかな。
Pekora's back? Pekora, can you make it? Does Pekora seem okay?
眩しい... あ、ペコラ戻ってきた。
Bright... Ah, Pekora came back.
あの後も行ったんですよ。
We went after that as well.
はい、オッケー、ありがとう。
Yes, okay, thank you.
ネコは同伴オッケーですか？ネコも同伴オッケーです。
Is it okay to bring the cat along? Yes, the cat is allowed too.
あ、ネコやった！ いいな、ネコ燃えてる！
Ah, Neko did it! Nice, Neko is on fire!
ネコがオッケー。燃えてる？
Cat is okay. On fire?
それでは、えー、幹事のね、声が聞こえる範囲内に、えー、お集まりいただき、ご静粛にお願いします。
Now then, please gather within the range where you can hear the organizer's voice, and please be quiet.
はーい。
Okay~
可愛い。
Cute.
みんな揃ってるかな？ あれ？みこちは？
Is everyone gathered? Huh? Where is Mikochi?
各チームメンバーでいない人はいないかね？大丈夫かね？
Is there anyone missing from each team? Are we good?
あれ？ みこちがちょっとまだかもです。みこちがいないかも。
Huh? Mikochi might not be here yet. Mikochi might be missing.
みこちと、これポルカかな？そうだね、みこポルがいない。
Mikochi and... is this Polka? That's right, Miko-Pol are missing.
あ、始まるよ。
Ah, it's starting!
水飲むんだ。
Drink some water.
はい、大丈夫でしょうか。はい。
Yes, is everyone ready? Yes.
それでは、皆様、3日間のサバイバル生活、お疲れ様でした！
And now, everyone, thank you for your hard work during these three days of survival life!
お疲れ様でした！イェーイ！
Thank you for your hard work! Yay!
それでは、3日間のすべてを各チームが背負っての閉会式
Now, each team carrying all they've done over these three days, we will hold the closing ceremony,
および授賞式を開催させていただきます。
as well as the award ceremony.
はい、お願いします。それでは、まず...
Yes, please do. First off...
誰か死んだ音がしたか大丈夫？ 今、死亡の音が...
Did some one just hear a death sound, is everything okay? There was just a death sound...
すばちゃん落ちたかも。誰か死んだ？ すばちゃん落ちた？
Suba-chan might have died. Did someone die? Did Suba-chan die?
大丈夫か？ マジで？ ご飯？ご飯か水。
Is she okay? Seriously? Food? Food or water.
みんなボリボリ食べてる。こんな風にならないようにしなきゃって。
Everyone's munching away. We have to make sure we don't end up like this...
そう、自分たちも怖くて。お水が...
Yeah, we're scared ourselves. The water...
おそらくすぐ戻ってくると思うので、少し待ちましょう。
She'll probably be right back, so let's wait a bit.
はい。過労死だ、過労死。
Okay. Death from overwork.
頑張ってたから。やばい。もう1回。
She was working so hard. Oh dear. One more time.
かっこいいな、無軌道。
That's cool.
どうしても人が集まるとね、落ちやすいのでお気を...
When people gather, it's easy to disconnect, so please be careful...
あ、なるほど。
Ah, I see.
落とせる設定は低めにしておくと安心かもしれない。あ、戻ったっぽい。
Setting the display graphics low might make it safer so it doesn't crash. Oh, they look back.
Got my snack.
あれ？あれ？OKって。聞こえる？
Huh? Huh? It says OK. Can you hear me?
あ、OKって来てる。OK、OK。復帰しましたかね？復帰しましたね、はい。はい、はい。
Ah, they're saying OK. OK, OK. Are they back? Yes, they are back. Yes, yes.
じゃあ、もし見れてない、音声聞こえてないようでしたら、えーと、画面共有などでお願いいたします。はい。
So, if you can't see the screen or hear the audio, please let us know through screen share. Okay.
はい！それでは少しずつ発表させていただきます！えー、まずマル秘ミッションがどういった内容だったかを発表していきます！
Alright! Then, I will start announcing the results little by little! First, let's announce what the secret missions were!
おおー！これで違ってたら悲しい...
Ooh! It would be sad if we got this wrong...
まず、ミッション1は、ラヴァエレメンタルの討伐でした！
First, Mission 1 was to defeat the Lava Elemental!
おおー！合ってる、合ってる！
Whoa! We got it, we got it!
達成できたチームは、「お片付けできるもん」、「一蓮托生ディノパーティー」、そして「エリートファミリア」の3チームになります！
The successful teams are 'Okataduke Dekirumon', 'Dino Party', and 'Elite Familiar'!
いやったー！
Yay!
続いて、マル秘ミッション2の正解は、太鼓をクラフトする！こちらは全チームクリアいたしました！
Next, Secret Mission 2 was to craft a drum! Every single team cleared this one!
おおー！
Ooh!
マル秘ミッション3！2枚以上の記録（日誌）を書く！こちらは大体ほとんどのメンバーが達成いたしました！
Secret Mission 3: Write two or more explorer notes! Almost all members completed this one!
おおー！まあまあまあ。
Ooh! Well, that's fair.
マル秘ミッション4！正解は、開会式ステージでマンモスに2人で乗りながら太鼓を叩く！
Secret Mission 4! The correct answer is: Drumming while two people ride a mammoth on the opening ceremony stage!
こちらも全チームクリアとなります！おおー！きたー！
This is also cleared by all teams! Ooh! Yes!
続きましてですね、えー、今回発表していなかった、ムキロゼシークレット賞を発表...
And next... we will announce the Mukiroze Secret Award that wasn't previously mentioned!
ええ！？何それ！聞いてない！
What?! What is that?! We didn't hear about this!
はい、こちらはですね、公表しておらず、シークレットであらかじめ用意しておいた賞になります！シークレットあったんや！
Yes, this is an award we secretly prepared beforehand without announcing it! There was a secret award?!
それで、こちらのムキロゼシークレット賞は、賞品およびポイントの追加がございます！ええー！すごーい！
And for this Mukiroze Secret Award, there will be extra prizes and points! Whoa! Awesome!
それではまず1つ目のシークレット賞から発表いたします！1つ目？複数あるの？
So, let's start with the first secret award! The first one? There are multiple?
「最も死んだ回数が多いプレイヤー」！
"The player who died the most times"!
あははは！だれだれ？これポイントになるの？ワンチャンある！
Ahahaha! Who is it? Does this get points? I might have a chance!
別名「一番愛されたで賞」ということで、ノエルさんが受賞！ぎゃあああ！
Also known as the "Most Beloved Award"... Noel-san wins! *screams*
ノエルさん！28回！おめでとうー！
Noel-san! 28 times! Congratulations!
それでは授与を行いたいと思いますので、ノエルさん、こちらステージまでお願いいたします。最も死んだ回数が多い、別名「一番愛されたで賞」を受賞されたお気持ちを一言お願いいたします！
We'd like to present the award, so Noel-san, please come up to the stage. Please give us a word on winning the "Most Beloved Award" for dying the most!
はい！団長はARK結構経験者で、予習もしたんですけど、こういう結果になって複雑ですｗ
Yes! I'm actually quite experienced in ARK and even prepared, so I have mixed feelings about this lol
でも！チームに貢献できたんですよね、ポイントがもらえて！嬉しいです！おめでとう！
But! I was able to contribute to the team with these points, so I'm happy! Congratulations!
受賞されたノエルさんにはですね、リアルの景品をムキロゼのポケットマネーからお送りします！リアル！？嬉しい！
To the winner, Noel-san, we will send a real-life prize using Mukiroze's pocket money! A real prize?! Awesome!
さらにですね、エリートファミリアのチームに、プラス10ポイント進呈いたします！でか！ありがとうございます！
Furthermore, the Elite Familiar team will get an extra 10 points! That's huge! Thank you so much!
はい、それでは続いての賞を発表してまいります。ノエルさんありがとうございました。ありがとうございました。
Alright, now let's move on to the next award. Thank you, Noel-san. Thank you very much.
続きましての賞は、「最もプレイヤーにキルされた回数が多いプレイヤー」！ええ！？そんなのあるの！？
The next award is: "The player who was killed by other players the most times"! What?! There's one for that?!
こちらみんなに愛されすぎでしょうということで...
This award is for being "loved too much" by everyone...
今回は、3名いらっしゃいます。
And this time, we have three winners!
べーちゃん、そしてミオ、そしてスバル！
Bae-chan, Mio-sha, and Subaru!
はい、では代表、3名一言ずついただきたいので、一応前に出てきていただいてよろしいでしょうか？
So, representatives... I'd like to get a few words from the three of you, so could you please step forward?
...となっておりますので、よろしくお願いいたします。
Please come forward.
はい。それでは一人ずつ、ミオちゃんから順に、えー、お願いいたします。
Alright, let's hear from you one by one, starting with Mio-sha. Go ahead.
はい！なんか不意にポイントもらえてやったー！嬉しいです！
Yes! I got some sympathy points, yay! I'm so happy!
はい、おめでとうございます！それでは続いて、じゃ、スバル、お願いいたします。
Congratulations! Next up, Subaru, please.
なんか分からんけど死んでたらしい！殺してくれたみんなありがとう！
I don't really get it, but apparently I died! Thanks to everyone who killed me!
おめでとうございます。それでは、べーちゃんお願いいたします。
Congratulations. Next, Bae-chan, please.
いや、同じくよく分からんが、愛されてて良かったな！
Yeah, same here, I don't really get it, but I'm glad I was loved!
おめでとうございます。
Congratulations!
こちらはですね、えー、むきろぜから高級和菓子をリアルでお渡しします！
For this, Mukiroze will give you high-class Japanese sweets in real life!
おー！
Oh! Awesome!
はい、おめでとうございます。そして、所属しているチーム、ポンコツサウルス、一蓮託生、ディノパーティー、えー、こちらディノパーティーからは2名なんですが...
Congratulations. And for the teams they belong to: Ponkotsusaurus, Ichirentakushou, and Dino Party... From Dino Party, there are two members...
各チーム上限1回とさせていただきまして、それぞれ10ポイント進呈いたします！
But since we're limiting it to one award per team, each team will receive 10 points!
イェーイ！
Yay!
えー、最も、恐竜をテイムした数が多いチーム、恐竜スター賞を受賞したチームは...
Next, the team that tamed the most dinosaurs... The winner of the Dino Star Award is...
お片付けできるもん！
Okataduke Dekiru Mon!
では、代表してリーダーの、えー、いろはちゃん、こちら前で一言おねがいします。
So, representing the team, leader Iroha-chan, please step forward and say a few words.
これ入ってるかな？入ってますか？これ。
Is my mic working? Is it on?
イェーイ！なんかみんなが手分けしてミッションクリアしようとして、ダブったテイムとかもあったんですけど、結果的にいっぱいになったんで、良かったです！ありがとうございます！
Yay! Everyone divided tasks to clear missions, and though some tames overlapped, we ended up with a lot! I'm glad! Thank you!
イェーイ！
Yay!
はい、こちらですね、リアルのプレゼントとしまして、チーム一人一人ですね、プレゼントがあります。
For this, as a real-life prize, every member of the team will receive a present!
小さめなペットロボットをプレゼントいたします！
We will gift you a small pet robot!
えー！ペットロボット？！いや、頑張って良かった！
Wait, a pet robot?! I'm so glad we worked hard!
はい、ポケットマネーから出させていただきますので、そちらを...
Yes, this will be paid out of my own pocket, so enjoy!
そして、チームにはプラス10ポイントが贈呈されます。
Also, the team will receive an additional 10 points!
イェーイ！
Yay!
さあ、続きまして、最もテイムした恐竜の種類が多いチーム...
Now, next up, the team that tamed the highest variety of dinosaur species...
恐竜図鑑賞を受賞されたのは...
The winner of the Dino Encyclopedia Award is...
お片付けできるもん！
Okataduke Dekiru Mon!
やったー！
We did it!
こちらはですね、W受賞になっておりまして、どちらも20種類をテイムされておりました！
Actually, this is a tie! Both teams tamed 20 different species!
おー！すごーい！がんばった甲斐あった！
Wow! Amazing! It was worth the effort!
それでは、マイクを持って前にお願いいたします。
So please come to the front with your microphone.
みこちゃん？みこちゃん行ってきな！
Miko-chan? Miko-chan, go ahead!
いやいや、いいよいいよ...
No, no, go ahead...
うちの、うちの家族がすごいです！はい！
My family is amazing! Yes!
はい、じゃあ、先程も受賞されましたお片付けできるもんの、チームリーダーから一言お願いいたします。
Alright, first, let's hear a word from the team leader of Okataduke Dekiru Mon, who also won earlier.
これは本当にイナ先輩がめっちゃ頑張ってくれました！
This is really thanks to Ina-senpai, she worked so hard!
え、そうですか？うれしい！
Really? I'm so happy!
続いて、エリートファミリアのリーダー、みこち、お願いいたします。
Next, Elite Familia's leader, Mikochi, please.
はい！うちの家族のみんなが一生懸命テイムしてくれました！みんなありがとう！
Yes! Everyone in my family did their absolute best taming! Thank you, everyone!
はい、ありがとうございます。
Yes, thank you very much.
はい、こちらリアルの景品のプレゼントは、
Now, the physical prizes we are giving away are...
恐竜フィギュアをそれぞれ1つずつプレゼントします。
dinosaur figures, one for each of you!
おお！うれしい！すごい！
Oh! Nice! I'm so happy! / Amazing!
さらに、所属するチームそれぞれに
Furthermore, to each of your respective teams,
プラス10ポイント進呈いたします。
we will present an extra 10 points.
イェーイ！10ポイントでかい！
Yay! 10 points is huge!
えー、そして、最後の無罪放免シークレット賞を、
And now, for the final exemption secret award...
お？なんだなんだ？
Oh? What is it, what is it?
アイスワームクイーンのトロフィー納品を最初に達成したチーム、
The team that first completed the Iceworm Queen trophy delivery,
「道を切り開いたで賞」を受賞されたのは、
winning the "Paved the Way Award," is...
「一蓮托生DINO PARTY」です！
"Ichirentakushou DINO PARTY"!
おおー！すごい！いって！代表者いって！
Ohhh! Awesome! Go on! Representatives, go!
代表者の方はぜひ前にお越しください。
Representatives, please come forward.
はい、それでは受賞した一言お願い致します。
Okay, please give us a few words on winning.
パーティー仲間のおかげで、ぺこぺこらも自由に動かされたので、
Thanks to my party members, Pekopekora was able to move freely,
本当にパーティーのみんなには感謝します！ありがとうございました！
so I'm really grateful to everyone in the party! Thank you very much!
おー！おめでとう！
Ohh! Congratulations!
はい、こちらですね、なんと9月5日23時07分に達成したのが最速となっておりました。
Yes, this was actually achieved on September 5th at 23:07, making it the fastest.
はや！すごい！
So fast! Amazing!
こちらの報酬として、10ポイント進呈いたします。
As a reward for this, we present 10 points.
おおー！
Ohhh!
そして、景品はですね、あの、インスタントヌードルセットをプレゼントいたします。
And the prize is... an instant noodle set.
インスタントヌードル！早いからね！ありがたい！
Instant noodles! Because they're fast, right! Appreciated!
おめでとうございます。
Congratulations.
そうしまして、すべての賞が終了いたしました。
With that, all the awards have finished.
それでは、最終結果の発表をいたします。
Now, we will announce the final results.
おお！
Oh!
えー、どの順位から発表するか非常に迷うところではありますが、
Um, I'm really torn about which rank to announce first, but...
えー、3位から発表させていただきます。
I will start by announcing the 3rd place.
3位！
3rd place!
それでは、
Now then,
3位のチームは、合計得点193ポイント。
the team in 3rd place, with a total score of 193 points...
おお！すごい！
Oh! Amazing!
チーム名は、「お片付けできるもん」！
The team name is "Okataduke Dekirumon" (We Can Clean Up)!
おおー！すごいすごい！
Ohhh! Awesome, awesome!
続きまして、2位と行きたいところなんですが、
Next, we would go to 2nd place, but...
なんと、同率で1位のチームとなりました！
we actually have a tie for 1st place!
えええ！同率！？
Whaaat! A tie!?
得点ポイントがそれぞれ200ポイントとなりました！
Their scores were 200 points each!
すごい！ぴったり！
Amazing! Exact tie!
そちらのチームが、2チーム。一蓮托生DINO PARTY、そしてエリートファミリア！
Those two teams are "Ichirentakushou DINO PARTY" and "Elite Familiar"!
えええ！うおおー！
Whaaat! Whoa!
おめでとう！
Congratulations!
すごい！
Amazing!
そうしまして、えー、結果4位となりました、えー、ポンコツサウルスの獲得ポイントは171ポイントとなっております。
And so, ending up in 4th place, "Ponkotu Saurus" acquired a score of 171 points.
惜しい！おめでとう！
Close! Congratulations!
あー、めちゃくちゃ惜しかった！
Ah, that was so close!
総合順位に対しましても、無罪放免からの、えー、賞品がございます。
Regarding the overall rankings, we also have prizes along with the exemption.
え？まだあるの？すご！
Eh? There's more? Awesome!
え、奮発させていただきました。
Yes, we went all out.
ええ！なになに？気になる！
Eh! What is it? I'm curious!
ちょっと待ってください、報酬一覧がですね、ちょっとお待ちくださいね。
Please wait a moment, the reward list is... please wait a second.
めっちゃすごいやつじゃない？
Isn't it something super amazing?
え？なんか飛んでる！何これ！
Eh? Something's flying! What is this!
エンタープライズ来た！俺たちのエンタープライズが！
The Enterprise is here! Our Enterprise!
乗れる！乗れる！
We can ride it!
少々お待ちくださいね。
Please wait just a moment.
すご、上！
Wow, look up!
大変お待たせいたしました。
Thank you very much for waiting.
賞品はですね、えーと、まず、最下位になりましたポンコツサウルスには、
The prizes are, let's see... First, for the last-place Ponkotu Saurus,
「もっと強くなれ」という意味を込めまして、
with the meaning of "become stronger"...
1人1つ プロテインを
One protein shake per person...
...プロテインを
...protein!
プロテイン！
Protein!
プロテイン
Protein...
そして同率1位となりました皆様には それぞれに
And for those of you who tied for first place, each of you gets...
高級肉ギフトを贈ります！
...a high-grade meat gift!
お肉！
Meat!
高級肉、いいな、肉
High-grade meat... nice, meat.
いいんですか？
Is that okay?
はい、お肉、楽しんでください！
Yes, please enjoy the meat!
肉！
Meat!
肉
Meat.
ということで、改めて3日間、ホロ鯖ARKありがとうございました！
So, once again, thank you all for the three days of HoloArk!
お疲れ様でした！
Thank you for your hard work!
それでは最後に、記念撮影をぜひ撮らせていただきたいと思いますので
Now then, finally, we would like to take a commemorative photo...
こちらのステージに、ちょっといい感じに並んでいただけますでしょうか
So could you please line up nicely on this stage?
死にそうなんで水1本だけいいですか？
I'm about to die, can I have a bottle of water?
行ってらっしゃい
Go ahead.
わー！
Wow!
たーまやー！
Tamaya!
たまやー！
すげえ
Amazing!
たまやー
Tamaya!
ぷぷぷぷ
*snickers*
綺麗！こっちだ！
Beautiful! Over here!
Pen-Pen and Popoking.
記念撮影を撮らせていただいて、この辺り、もしくはもう一段上がれますか？
Let's take a commemorative photo. Can we stand here, or go up one step?
あ、これ。ゆっくりゆっくり
Ah, this. Slowly, slowly.
乗る乗る
Get on, get on.
落ち着いた？
Are we settled?
見えないか
Can you not see?
チームの真ん中に行きなよ、ボス
Go to the center of your team, boss.
いやいや、いいですよ
No, no, it's fine.
治った？
Are you healed?
いろは、どこですか？
Iroha, where are you?
いないですか？大丈夫ですか？
Is she not here? Is everyone okay?
いるよね？
You're here, right?
オッケー、全員いる
Okay, everyone's here.
チームメンバーで揃ってない人はいませんか？
Is there anyone whose team members aren't all here?
大丈夫です
We're fine.
フブちゃん
Fubu-chan!
お、ツェッペリンいる
Oh, there's a Zeppelin.
みっちゃん、大層な...
Mio-chan, what a grand...
はい、こちらで、えーっと、運営さんがね、今、写真を撮影してくれてますので
Yes, the staff is taking photos for us now.
おのおの、エモートなども楽しんでいただきつつ、もう撮られていると思いますので、お願いします
So please enjoy performing your emotes while they take them. Thank you.
エモート、どうぞ
Perform your emotes, please.
エモート？
Emotes?
ホイール長押しして、大体10時くらいのところに
Long-press the wheel, it's around 10 o'clock.
ほうほう。ワシの真似？
I see, I see. Imitating an eagle?
おー。ちょっと...
Oh... a bit...
エンタープライズが...
Enterprise is...
それでは、一応掛け声もさせていただきますので、よろしいでしょうか
Well then, I'll count us down, is that okay?
はーい
Yes!
ホロ鯖ARK、3日間お疲れ様でした。はい、チーズ！
HoloArk, thank you for these 3 days. Say cheese!
チーズ！
Cheese!
イェーイ！
Yay!
Oh, I forgot to turn off my snack.
イェーイ、お疲れ様でした！
Yay, thank you for your hard work!
ありがとうございました！
Thank you very much!
うぇーい、ありがとうございました！
Wei, thank you very much!
えー、もしですね、よろしければ、感想とかがありましたらね、余裕があれば、日誌の方に入れていただけましたら
And if you'd like, if you have any thoughts or impressions, you can write them in the journal if you have time.
後日の振り返りなどでも、読ませていただきますので
I'll read them during the later review stream.
ありがとうございます
Thank you.
お疲れ様でした！
Thank you for your hard work!
ポテトの前で、ちょっと肉食べようよ
Let's eat some meat in front of the potato.
肉、肉。お疲れ
Meat, meat. Good job.
お疲れ様でした
Thank you for your hard work.
我々、ツェッペリンに乗って...
Let's get on the Zeppelin...
ツェッペリン乗ろうぜ
Let's get on the Zeppelin.
ツェッペリン！
Zeppelin!
ぼたんちゃんが、なんか、写真、集まりたい、みたいな感じだったから
Botan-chan looked like she wanted to gather for a photo.
あ、ツェッペリン乗って...
Ah, get on the Zeppelin...
記念撮影だ
It's a commemorative photo.
よし、飛ばすか、ツェッペリン。動かしてくれて
Alright, let's fly the Zeppelin. Thanks for moving it.
みんな、乗った？ツェッペリン、だいぶ助かったけどな、今日
Is everyone on? The Zeppelin really helped a lot today, though.
言ってた、だいぶ助かった。準備は意味があった。
It really helped a lot. The preparation was worth it.
あったぞ！意味あった！
There was! It was worth it!
ちょっと飛んでやるからさ、この辺、この辺で。
I'll fly it a bit, around here, around here.
来た！来た！
It's here! It's here!
これ、Bibi落ちないでよ？
Bibi, don't fall off, okay?
落ちない、落ちない。
I won't fall, I won't fall.
でもさ、結構接戦だったよね、なんだかんだで。
But you know, it was a pretty close match in the end.
なんだかんだで残ってたよね。
Yeah, we managed to stay in it till the end.
あのユニコーンか、あのアスレチックやれてたら勝てた。
If we had gotten that unicorn, or if we did that athletic course, we could have won.
ティラノがね...うわー、しょうがない、しょうがないな。
The Rexes, though... Ah, well, can't be helped, can't be helped.
それはもうしょうがない。
That's just how it is.
いやー、みんな本当に頑張りました。頑張りました！
But really, everyone worked so hard. We worked hard!
撮るか、じゃあ。お疲れ様でした。並ぶか、これ。
Shall we take a picture, then? Good job, everyone. Should we line up?
これ、浮いてる状態でハンドル離したら落ちるかな？
If I let go of the wheel while we're floating, will it fall?
いや、止まるはず。あ、止まった！
No, it should stay. Oh, it stopped!
止まってる、止まってる！
It's staying, it's staying!
じゃあ、これで撮ってこようよ、写真。
Then let's take a picture like this.
あ、じゃあフォトモードできるよ、一応。
Oh, we can use photo mode, actually.
あ、本当？じゃあおねがいしようかな、ちょっと操作。
Really? Then could you handle the controls?
どうやってやってて？
How do we do it?
いいよ、送ってもらう。
Sure, I'll send it.
これ、前、前でこう向いとけばいいの？
Do we just face forward like this?
あ、前に向いてもらえれば。
Yeah, if you can face forward.
タマキの後ろ...後ろ側向いてるわ。
Behind Tamaki... I'm facing backwards.
やば、あとBibi、あとこれ、胸叩き、これしない？これ。
Oh, and Bibi, shouldn't we do the chest-beating emote? This one.
胸叩き、これ何で、何でしたっけ？
Chest-beating? How do we do that again?
エモートで、左下にね、胸叩きがある。ほら。
In the emotes, on the bottom left, there's chest-beating. See?
あ、やばいやばい...
Oh, wait, wait...
Bibiさんのデカいケツ目の前なんだが。
Bibi-san's huge butt is right in front of me, though.
やばいやばい...
Oh no, oh no...
これ、エモートどれでしたっけ？Tでしたっけ？
Which button was the emote? Was it T?
Bibiさん何か、さっき初期設定は...T？
For Bibi-san, earlier the default setting was... T?
うん、T。長押し。
Yeah, T. Hold it down.
エモート来た、来た、来た。せーの、胸叩き！
The emotes appeared! One, two, chest-beating!
なんかある？これ。
Is it working?
いい、いいじゃん！Monkey!
Nice, nice! Monkey!
おいおいよ。エモート...
Alright, alright. Emote...
おらおらおらおら！
Ora ora ora ora!
これでじゃあちょっと、アップ...え、すごい！撮れてるのすごい！
Let's take a close-up with this. Wow, it's amazing that you can take pictures!
すごい！撮れてる、撮れてる。
Amazing! It's capturing it.
おらおらおらおらおら！
Ora ora ora ora ora!
あ、いいよ、いい感じ、いい感じ。
Ah, nice, looking good, looking good.
何これ？なんか悲しい音楽が...
What is this? Some sad music is...
かな、悲しいやつ。
Yeah, a sad one.
よいしょ。これで...
Yoisho. With this...
うわ、すごい！首吹いちゃうわ。
Wow, cool! My neck is blowing away.
バックフリップできる。センキュー、センキュー。
I can do a backflip! Thank you, thank you.
よいしょ、これで何枚か撮れたはず。あ、
Okay, we should have gotten a few pictures with this.
ありがとうございます。ありがとうございました！
Thank you very much. Thank you so much!
いや、もう皆様、まず3日間、本当にお疲れ様でした。
Seriously, everyone, thank you so much for your hard work over these 3 days.
お疲れ様でした！いやもう、本当にみんながめっちゃ頑張ってくれて、
Thank you for your hard work! Everyone worked so hard,
3位にね、なれました！ありがとう。ありがとうございました。
and we managed to get 3rd place! Thank you. Thank you so much.
ちょっと本当、おしかった。1位との差が、正直10ポイントなくて、
It was really close. Honestly, we were less than 10 points away from 1st place.
びっくり！まさかこんなにいくと思ってなかったんで、個人的にはとってもびっくり&嬉しいです。
I'm shocked! I didn't think we'd get this far, so personally, I'm super surprised and happy.
あ、よかった、よかった。うれしかったよ。
Ah, that's great, that's great. I'm so glad.
ちょっとね、全然ARKのこと、正直最後の最後まで分かり、分かりきれなかったんですけど、まあ、またそれもARKということで。
To be honest, I couldn't fully grasp ARK until the very end, but I guess that's just how ARK is.
そうやね。ね。
True. Yeah.
でも、なんかいろいろ教えてくださって本当にありがとうございました。
But thank you so much for teaching me so many things.
助かった。本当に...いや、本当に良かった。
It really helped. Seriously... Yeah, it was really great.
いや本当に教えてもらったし、たくさん助けてもらいました。助かった。
I learned so much, and everyone helped me a lot. It really helped.
ね、助かった。ありがとう。
Yeah, it really helped. Thank you.
だいぶ、ARK全然やってなかったけど、楽しかった。
I hadn't played ARK in a while, but it was so fun.
ね、楽しんでいけました。
Yeah, we had a lot of fun.
本当に、お疲れ様でした。お疲れ様でした！
Really, thank you for your hard work. Thank you for your hard work!
お疲れ様でした。いろいろありましたが、ありがとうございました。
Good job, everyone. Many things happened, but thank you very much.
よかった、よかった。とわね、嬉しかったよ、その、やっぱりさ、こういう箱企画って、
I'm so glad. For me, Towa, I was really happy. After all, in these group events,
またフブちゃんとか、とわとか、やっぱりリーダーになりがちだけど、
people like Fubuki-chan or me tend to become leaders,
今回、いろはが頑張って、
but this time, Iroha worked really hard,
やってくれて、で、その、自分なりに表作ったりとかして、
took charge, made spreadsheets on her own,
みんなに分かりやすいように動いてくれたじゃん。
and took action to make things easy for everyone to understand.
それが本当に、なんか、嬉しかったわ、とわ。ね、ありがとう。
That honestly made me really happy. Yeah, thank you.
少しでも力になれてたら幸いです。
I'm glad if I could be of even a little help.
分かりやすかったよ、すごい。ありがとうございました！
It was super easy to understand. Thank you very much!
ナイスだよ。よく頑張りました。
Nice job. You worked so hard.
みんな本当によく頑張りました！
Everyone worked so hard!
後半って、今日1日の後半の追い上げ、めっちゃ凄くなかった？
And that late-stage push today was absolutely incredible, wasn't it?
めっちゃ凄かった！いや、本当にお疲れ様でした。
It was amazing! Seriously, great work, everyone.
お疲れ様！お疲れ様でした。
Good job! Thank you for your hard work.
いいチームだったんで、これもまた1つの思い出。
It was a great team, so this is another great memory.
写真、2期生も撮ってね。
Take a photo with the 2nd generation too.
2期生も...はい。じゃあみんなで解散にしましょう。お疲れ様でした！
For the 2nd generation... Alright, let's disband now. Good job, everyone!
お疲れ様でした！バイバイ！
Thank you for your hard work! Bye-bye!
あ、うまい。
Ah, smooth.
Yay, that wraps up ARK, ARK.
Yay, that wraps up ARK.
どこだ
Where is it?
Okay.
All right, one last journal and then we'll go.
Say bye to our friends we made along the way today.
あ、
Ah,
It is always...
...scary...
...heading into...
...the unknown.
But there's nothing to fear...
...with the perfect...
...team...
...mates.
We did great!
I won't forget the friends...
...we made along the way.
よし。
Okay.
いや、楽しかったな。
Man, that was fun.
なんか、すっごいゆっくりARKもやってみたいな。
I kind of want to play ARK at a really relaxed pace sometime...
I kind of want to play ARK like, casually sometime.
It seems like one of the games where you can just...
...spend a long time playing.
Maybe not like in the near future, but sometime in the future. That'll be fun.
Yeah, like solo.
I don't know if there will be enough people for EN ARK.
I think it's just harder to set up with more players.
I just want to play really, really casually, you know.
"You just want to tame all of the animals, do you?"
No, no.
All right, we tamed a lot today, huh.
All right, let's just...
I don't know what a good place would be.
I think, I think where we first tamed Argen,
I think that's a pretty iconic place.
It's where my, my ARK journey started.
Yeah, I think like at the start I was really stuck,
because I was like, I can't... because I was tired out of my mind.
Oh, I need water.
And then,
I couldn't Japanese because I was tired.
I couldn't speak Japanese because I was tired.
And then all these ARK lingo that I don't know, that's in Japanese.
I was like, my brain was so overwhelmed on the first day.
I was like, was it a mistake for me to join?
But, you know, I got the hang of it, and my teammates were very, very helpful.
And they like, explained a lot off-stream too.
So I was able to manage. I think...
I think I pulled one person's worth of weight, you know?
That's, that's all I wanted to do.
Yeah. Like when I saw my teammates I was like, "Eh? Really? All of them in one team?"
But, yeah, it was fun. It was fun.
All right. All right, TONDERU.
And, BEAUTY.
And, what else do I have? A doggo that I never took out.
And of course,
should I take out BIG MEOW?
Wait, no.
All right.
How do we do this?
Okay, the whole crew is here.
Anyways,
thank you...
...everyone,
for watching.
I hope you guys enjoyed
the journey
in ARK, the ARK arc.
Oh, I gotta take a break
cuz I've been running on so little sleep
that I feel like I'm going crazy.
So...
yeah.
Anniversary coming up.
Real fun stuff, let's go.
Some big things on the way.
Anyways, thank you guys.
Hope you guys have a wonderful...
...rest of the morning, afternoon, evening.
Until next time,
take care.
Bye-bye!
Wah!